[
    {
        "answer": "the Radiocommunication Act",
        "id": "B-001-001-001",
        "options": [
            "the Radiocommunication Act",
            "the Radiocommunication Regulations",
            "the Standards for the Operation of Radio Stations in the Amateur Radio Service",
            "the ITU Radio Regulations"
        ],
        "question": "Authority to make regulations governing radiocommunications is derived from:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "the Radiocommunication Act",
        "id": "B-001-001-002",
        "options": [
            "the Radiocommunication Act",
            "the Radiocommunication Regulations",
            "the Standards for the Operation of Radio Stations in the Amateur Radio Service",
            "the ITU Radio Regulations"
        ],
        "question": "Authority to make \"Standards for the Operation of Radio Stations in the Amateur Radio Service\" is derived from:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada",
        "id": "B-001-001-003",
        "options": [
            "Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada",
            "Transport Canada",
            "Communications Canada",
            "National Defence"
        ],
        "question": "The Department that is responsible for the administration of the Radiocommunication Act is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "the Radiocommunication Regulations",
        "id": "B-001-001-004",
        "options": [
            "the Radiocommunication Regulations",
            "the Radiocommunication Act",
            "the Standards for the Operation of Radio Stations in the Amateur Radio Service",
            "the FCC's Part 97 rules"
        ],
        "question": "The \"amateur radio service\" is defined in:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Contact Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada and provide details of your address change",
        "id": "B-001-002-001",
        "options": [
            "Contact Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada and provide details of your address change",
            "Telephone your local club, and give them your new address",
            "Contact an accredited examiner and provide details of your address change",
            "Write amateur organizations advising them of your new address, enclosing your certificate"
        ],
        "question": "What must you do to notify your mailing address changes ?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "life",
        "id": "B-001-002-002",
        "options": [
            "life",
            "five years",
            "three years",
            "one year"
        ],
        "question": "An Amateur Radio Operator Certificate is valid for:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada must be advised of any change in postal address",
        "id": "B-001-002-003",
        "options": [
            "Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada must be advised of any change in postal address",
            "Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada must be notified within 14 days of operation at the new address",
            "the station shall not be operated until a change of address card is forwarded to Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada",
            "within the same province, there is no need to notify Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada"
        ],
        "question": "Whenever a change of address is made:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "must be retained at the station",
        "id": "B-001-002-004",
        "options": [
            "must be retained at the station",
            "must be put on file",
            "must be kept in a safe place",
            "must be kept on the person to whom it is issued"
        ],
        "question": "The Amateur Radio Operator Certificate:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "48",
        "id": "B-001-002-005",
        "options": [
            "48",
            "12",
            "24",
            "72"
        ],
        "question": "The holder of an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate shall, at the request of a duly appointed radio inspector, produce the certificate, or a copy thereof, to the inspector, within ____ hours after the request:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "free",
        "id": "B-001-002-006",
        "options": [
            "free",
            "$32",
            "$10",
            "$24"
        ],
        "question": "The fee for an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "retained at the address provided to Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada",
        "id": "B-001-002-007",
        "options": [
            "retained at the address provided to Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada",
            "retained in a safety deposit box",
            "retained on the radio amateur's person",
            "retained in the radio amateur's vehicle"
        ],
        "question": "The Amateur Radio Operator Certificate should be:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "are prohibited - penalties could be assessed to the control operator",
        "id": "B-001-003-001",
        "options": [
            "are prohibited - penalties could be assessed to the control operator",
            "must be identified with your call sign",
            "are permitted",
            "are permitted for short tests only"
        ],
        "question": "Out of amateur band transmissions:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "False or deceptive signals",
        "id": "B-001-003-002",
        "options": [
            "False or deceptive signals",
            "A traditional greeting in May",
            "An emergency test transmission",
            "Nothing special: \"MAYDAY\" has no meaning in an emergency"
        ],
        "question": "If an amateur pretends there is an emergency and transmits the word \"MAYDAY,\" what is this called?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "a fine, not exceeding $5 000, or a prison term of one year, or both",
        "id": "B-001-003-003",
        "options": [
            "a fine, not exceeding $5 000, or a prison term of one year, or both",
            "a fine of $10 000",
            "a prison term of two years",
            "a fine of $1 000"
        ],
        "question": "A person found guilty of transmitting a false or fraudulent distress signal, or interfering with, or obstructing any radio communication, without lawful cause, may be liable, on summary conviction, to a penalty of:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The Radiocommunication Act",
        "id": "B-001-003-004",
        "options": [
            "The Radiocommunication Act",
            "The Official Radio Rules of Canada",
            "The Radiocommunications Regulations",
            "The Radiocommunications Law Reform Act of 2002"
        ],
        "question": "What government document states the offences and penalties for non compliance of the rules governing radiocommunications?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "With no notice, or opportunity to make representation thereto",
        "id": "B-001-003-005",
        "options": [
            "With no notice, or opportunity to make representation thereto",
            "Where the holder has contravened the Radiocommunication Act, its Regulations, or the terms and conditions of the certificate",
            "Where the certificate was obtained through misrepresentation",
            "Where the holder has failed to comply with a request to pay fees or interest due"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following is not correct? The Minister may suspend an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A radio inspector may enter a dwelling without the consent of the occupant and without a warrant",
        "id": "B-001-003-006",
        "options": [
            "A radio inspector may enter a dwelling without the consent of the occupant and without a warrant",
            "Where entry is refused, and is necessary to perform his duties under the Act, a radio inspector may obtain a warrant",
            "In executing a warrant, a radio inspector shall not use force, unless accompanied by a peace officer, and force is authorized",
            "The person in charge of a place entered by a radio inspector shall give the inspector information that the inspector requests"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following statements is not correct?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "There are no age limits",
        "id": "B-001-004-001",
        "options": [
            "There are no age limits",
            "70 years or younger",
            "18 years or older",
            "14 years or older"
        ],
        "question": "What age must you be to hold an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate with Basic Qualification?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Basic",
        "id": "B-001-004-002",
        "options": [
            "Basic",
            "Personality test",
            "Morse code",
            "Advanced"
        ],
        "question": "Which examination must be passed before an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate is issued?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Canadian Radiocommunication Operator General Certificate Maritime (RGMC)",
        "id": "B-001-004-003",
        "options": [
            "Canadian Radiocommunication Operator General Certificate Maritime (RGMC)",
            "Canadian Restricted Operator Certificate - Maritime (ROC-M)",
            "Canadian Restricted Operator's Certificate - Maritime Commercial (ROC-MC)",
            "Canadian Restricted Operator Certificate - Aeronautical (ROC-A)"
        ],
        "question": "Holders of which one of the following certificates may be issued an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "any order",
        "id": "B-001-004-004",
        "options": [
            "any order",
            "Morse code after passing the Advanced",
            "Morse code after passing the Basic with Honours",
            "Advanced after passing Morse code"
        ],
        "question": "After an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate with Basic qualifications is issued, the holder may be examined for additional qualifications in the following order:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "5 w.p.m.",
        "id": "B-001-004-005",
        "options": [
            "5 w.p.m.",
            "12 w.p.m.",
            "7 w.p.m.",
            "15 w.p.m."
        ],
        "question": "One Morse code qualification is available for the Amateur Radio Operator Certificate. It is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "a station authorized in the amateur service",
        "id": "B-001-004-006",
        "options": [
            "a station authorized in the amateur service",
            "a station authorized in the aeronautical service",
            "a station authorized in the maritime service",
            "any authorized station except stations authorized in the amateur, aeronautical or maritime services"
        ],
        "question": "The holder of an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate with the Basic Qualification is authorized to operate following stations:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Have a valid address in Canada",
        "id": "B-001-004-007",
        "options": [
            "Have a valid address in Canada",
            "Be a Canadian citizen",
            "Be a Canadian citizen or permanent resident",
            "Be at least 14 years of age and a Canadian citizen or permanent resident"
        ],
        "question": "What conditions must candidates to amateur radio certification meet?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "if the other person is the holder of an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate to operate in the amateur radio service",
        "id": "B-001-005-001",
        "options": [
            "if the other person is the holder of an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate to operate in the amateur radio service",
            "pending the granting of a radio authorization, if the apparatus covers the amateur and commercial frequency bands",
            "pending the granting of an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate if the apparatus covers the amateur frequency bands only",
            "if the transmitter of a station, for which a radio authorization is to be applied for, is type approved and crystal controlled"
        ],
        "question": "Radio apparatus may be installed, placed in operation, repaired or maintained by the holder of an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate with Advanced Qualification on behalf of another person:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Advanced qualification",
        "id": "B-001-005-002",
        "options": [
            "Advanced qualification",
            "Basic and Morse code qualification",
            "Morse code with Honours qualification",
            "Basic qualification"
        ],
        "question": "The holder of an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate may design and build from scratch transmitting equipment for use in the amateur radio service provided that person has the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "not install, place in operation, modify, repair, maintain, or permit the operation of the radio apparatus",
        "id": "B-001-005-003",
        "options": [
            "not install, place in operation, modify, repair, maintain, or permit the operation of the radio apparatus",
            "install an amateur station, but not operate or permit the operation of the apparatus",
            "install and operate the radio apparatus, using your own call sign",
            "modify and repair the radio apparatus but not install it"
        ],
        "question": "Where a friend is not the holder of any type of radio operator certificate, you, as a holder of an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate with Basic Qualification, may, on behalf of your friend:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "only if the other person is the holder of a valid Amateur Radio Operator Certificate",
        "id": "B-001-005-004",
        "options": [
            "only if the other person is the holder of a valid Amateur Radio Operator Certificate",
            "only if the final power input does not exceed 100 watts",
            "only if the station is for use on one of the VHF bands",
            "only if the DC power input to the final stage does not exceed 200 watts"
        ],
        "question": "A radio amateur with Basic and Morse code qualifications may install an amateur station for another person:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "must be operated by a person with an Amateur Certificate and call sign",
        "id": "B-001-006-001",
        "options": [
            "must be operated by a person with an Amateur Certificate and call sign",
            "must be licensed by Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada",
            "need not be licensed in isolated areas only",
            "is exempt from regulatory control by Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada"
        ],
        "question": "An amateur radio station with a maximum input power to the final stage of 2 watts:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "stations operated under similar authorizations",
        "id": "B-001-006-002",
        "options": [
            "stations operated under similar authorizations",
            "any stations which are identified for special contests",
            "armed forces stations during special contests and training exercises",
            "any station transmitting in the amateur bands"
        ],
        "question": "An amateur station may be used to communicate with:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A radio amateur may use a linear amplifier to amplify the output of a licence-exempt transmitter outside any amateur radio allocations",
        "id": "B-001-006-003",
        "options": [
            "A radio amateur may use a linear amplifier to amplify the output of a licence-exempt transmitter outside any amateur radio allocations",
            "A considerate operator does not transmit unnecessary signals",
            "A courteous operator refrains from using offensive language",
            "A radio amateur may not operate, or permit to be operated, a radio apparatus which he knows is not performing to the Radiocommunication Regulations"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following statements is not correct?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "An amateur radio operator transmitting unnecessary or offensive signals does not violate accepted practice",
        "id": "B-001-006-004",
        "options": [
            "An amateur radio operator transmitting unnecessary or offensive signals does not violate accepted practice",
            "Except for a certified radio amateur operating within authorized amateur radio allocations, no person shall possess or operate any device for the purpose of amplifying the output power of a licence-exempt radio apparatus",
            "A person may operate or permit the operation of radio apparatus only where the apparatus is maintained to the Radiocommunication Regulations tolerances",
            "A person may operate an amateur radio station when the person complies with the Standards for the Operation of Radio Stations in the Amateur Radio Service"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following statements is not correct?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "on aeronautical, marine or land mobile frequencies",
        "id": "B-001-006-005",
        "options": [
            "on aeronautical, marine or land mobile frequencies",
            "only where the person complies with the Standards for the Operation of Radio Stations in the Amateur Radio Service",
            "only where the apparatus is maintained within the performance standards set by Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada regulations and policies",
            "except for the amplification of the output power of licence-exempt radio apparatus operating outside authorized amateur radio service allocations"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following statements is not correct? A person may operate radio apparatus, authorized in the amateur service:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The radio is certified under the proper Radio Standard Specification for use in Canada and licensed by Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada on the specified frequencies",
        "id": "B-001-006-006",
        "options": [
            "The radio is certified under the proper Radio Standard Specification for use in Canada and licensed by Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada on the specified frequencies",
            "The radio operator has a Restricted Operator's Certificate",
            "The equipment has a RF power output of 2 watts or less",
            "The equipment is used in remote areas north of 60 degrees latitude"
        ],
        "question": "Some VHF and UHF FM radios purchased for use in the amateur service can also be programmed to communicate on frequencies used for the land mobile service. Under what conditions is this permissible?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Business planning",
        "id": "B-001-007-001",
        "options": [
            "Business planning",
            "Recreation planning",
            "Code practice planning",
            "Emergency planning"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following cannot be discussed on an amateur club net?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Never",
        "id": "B-001-007-002",
        "options": [
            "Never",
            "Only when the operator is being paid",
            "Only when broadcasts last less than 1 hour",
            "Only when broadcasts last longer than 15 minutes"
        ],
        "question": "When is a radio amateur allowed to broadcast information to the general public?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Never",
        "id": "B-001-007-003",
        "options": [
            "Never",
            "When operating a beacon transmitter in a \"fox hunt\" exercise",
            "When playing a harmless \"practical joke\"",
            "When you need to hide the meaning of a message for secrecy"
        ],
        "question": "When may false or deceptive amateur signals or communications be transmitted?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Broadcasts intended for the general public",
        "id": "B-001-007-004",
        "options": [
            "Broadcasts intended for the general public",
            "Radio control commands to model craft",
            "Brief transmissions to make adjustments to the station",
            "Morse code practice"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following one-way communications may not be transmitted in the amateur service?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "When the encoding technique is published in the public domain",
        "id": "B-001-007-005",
        "options": [
            "When the encoding technique is published in the public domain",
            "When it is used for music streaming content",
            "When it is used for commercial traffic",
            "When it includes sending the amateur station's call sign"
        ],
        "question": "You wish to develop and use a new digital encoding technique to transmit data over amateur radio spectrum. Under what conditions is this permissible?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Only when the encoding or cipher is not secret",
        "id": "B-001-007-006",
        "options": [
            "Only when the encoding or cipher is not secret",
            "During a declared communications emergency",
            "During contests",
            "When transmitting above 450 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "When may an amateur station in two-way communication transmit an encoded  message?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "They may be used if the signals or codes are not secret",
        "id": "B-001-007-007",
        "options": [
            "They may be used if the signals or codes are not secret",
            "There are no restrictions",
            "They are not permitted because they obscure the meaning of a message to government monitoring stations",
            "Only \"10 codes\" are permitted"
        ],
        "question": "What are the restrictions on the use of abbreviations or procedural signals in the amateur service?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Turn down the volume of background audio",
        "id": "B-001-007-008",
        "options": [
            "Turn down the volume of background audio",
            "Turn up the volume of your transmitter",
            "Speak closer to the microphone to increase your signal strength",
            "Adjust your transceiver noise blanker"
        ],
        "question": "What should you do to keep you station from retransmitting music or signals from a non-amateur station?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "is not permitted",
        "id": "B-001-007-009",
        "options": [
            "is not permitted",
            "is permitted for contests",
            "must be approved by Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada",
            "is permitted for third-party traffic"
        ],
        "question": "The transmission of a secret code by the operator of an amateur station:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Q signals",
        "id": "B-001-007-010",
        "options": [
            "Q signals",
            "programming that originates from a broadcasting undertaking",
            "radiocommunication in support of industrial, business, or professional activities",
            "commercially recorded material"
        ],
        "question": "A radio amateur may be engaged in communication which include the transmission of:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "are not permitted under any circumstance",
        "id": "B-001-007-011",
        "options": [
            "are not permitted under any circumstance",
            "are permitted on some bands",
            "are only permitted if they are for the safety of life or immediate protection of property",
            "are not prohibited by regulation"
        ],
        "question": "In the amateur radio service, business communications:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Anywhere in Canada",
        "id": "B-001-008-001",
        "options": [
            "Anywhere in Canada",
            "Anywhere in Canada during times of emergency",
            "Only at the address shown on Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada records",
            "Anywhere in your call sign prefix area"
        ],
        "question": "Where may the holder of an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate operate an amateur radio station in Canada?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Beacon station",
        "id": "B-001-008-002",
        "options": [
            "Beacon station",
            "Repeater station",
            "HF station",
            "VHF station"
        ],
        "question": "Which type of station may transmit one-way communications?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "at any location in Canada",
        "id": "B-001-008-003",
        "options": [
            "at any location in Canada",
            "only at the address which is on record at Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada",
            "at the address which is on record at Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada and at one other location",
            "at the address which is on record at Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada and in two mobiles"
        ],
        "question": "Amateur radio operators may install or operate radio apparatus:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Basic and Advanced qualifications",
        "id": "B-001-008-004",
        "options": [
            "Basic and Advanced qualifications",
            "Basic and Morse code qualifications",
            "Basic qualification",
            "Basic with Honours qualification"
        ],
        "question": "In order to install any radio apparatus, to be used specifically for receiving and automatically retransmitting radiotelephone communications within the same frequency band, a radio amateur must hold an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate, with a minimum of:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Basic and Advanced",
        "id": "B-001-008-005",
        "options": [
            "Basic and Advanced",
            "Basic, Advanced and Morse code",
            "Basic",
            "Basic with Honours"
        ],
        "question": "In order to install any radio apparatus, to be used specifically for an amateur radio club station, the radio amateur must hold an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate, with a minimum of the following qualifications:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Basic and Advanced",
        "id": "B-001-008-006",
        "options": [
            "Basic and Advanced",
            "Basic with Honours",
            "Basic and Morse code",
            "Basic, Advanced and Morse code"
        ],
        "question": "In order to install or operate a transmitter or RF amplifier that is neither professionally designed nor commercially manufactured for use in the amateur service, a radio amateur must hold an Amateur Operator's Certificate, with a minimum of which qualifications?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Both the control operator and the station owner",
        "id": "B-001-009-001",
        "options": [
            "Both the control operator and the station owner",
            "Only the station owner who is the holder of an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate",
            "The person who owns the station equipment",
            "Only the control operator"
        ],
        "question": "Who is responsible for the proper operation of an amateur station?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Both of you",
        "id": "B-001-009-002",
        "options": [
            "Both of you",
            "You",
            "The station owner, unless the station records show that you were the control operator at the time",
            "The station owner"
        ],
        "question": "If you transmit from another amateur's station, who is responsible for its proper operation?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "You are responsible for the proper operation of the station in accordance with the regulations",
        "id": "B-001-009-003",
        "options": [
            "You are responsible for the proper operation of the station in accordance with the regulations",
            "You must allow another amateur to operate your station upon request",
            "You must be present whenever the station is operated",
            "You must notify Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada if another amateur acts as the control operator"
        ],
        "question": "What is your responsibility as a station owner?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Any qualified amateur chosen by the station owner",
        "id": "B-001-009-004",
        "options": [
            "Any qualified amateur chosen by the station owner",
            "Any person over 21 years of age with a Basic Qualification",
            "Any person over 21 years of age with Basic and Morse code qualifications",
            "Any person over 21 years of age"
        ],
        "question": "Who may be the control operator of an amateur station?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Whenever the station is transmitting",
        "id": "B-001-009-005",
        "options": [
            "Whenever the station is transmitting",
            "A control operator is not needed",
            "Whenever the station receiver is operated",
            "Only when training another amateur"
        ],
        "question": "When must an amateur station have a control operator?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "At the station's control point",
        "id": "B-001-009-006",
        "options": [
            "At the station's control point",
            "Anywhere in the same building as the transmitter",
            "At the station's entrance, to control entry to the room",
            "Anywhere within 50 km of the station location"
        ],
        "question": "When an amateur station is transmitting, where must its control operator be?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "They must hold suitable amateur radio qualifications before they are allowed to be control operators",
        "id": "B-001-009-007",
        "options": [
            "They must hold suitable amateur radio qualifications before they are allowed to be control operators",
            "They must not use your equipment without your permission",
            "They must first know how to use the right abbreviations and Q signals",
            "They must first know the right frequencies and emission modes for transmitting"
        ],
        "question": "Why can't family members without qualifications transmit using your amateur station if they are alone with your equipment?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "permit any person to operate the station under the supervision and in the presence of the holder of the amateur operator certificate",
        "id": "B-001-009-008",
        "options": [
            "permit any person to operate the station under the supervision and in the presence of the holder of the amateur operator certificate",
            "permit anyone to take part in communications only if prior written permission is received from Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada",
            "permit anyone to use the station without restrictions",
            "permit anyone to use the station and take part in communications"
        ],
        "question": "The owner of an amateur station may:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Any person may operate an amateur station under supervision, and in the presence of, a person holding appropriate qualifications",
        "id": "B-001-009-009",
        "options": [
            "Any person may operate an amateur station under supervision, and in the presence of, a person holding appropriate qualifications",
            "A person, holding only Basic Qualification, may operate another station on 14.2 MHz",
            "Radio amateurs may permit any person to operate the station without supervision",
            "Any person may operate a station in the amateur radio service"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Harmful interference",
        "id": "B-001-010-001",
        "options": [
            "Harmful interference",
            "Interrupted CW",
            "Transponder signals",
            "Unidentified transmissions"
        ],
        "question": "What is a transmission called that disturbs other communications?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Never",
        "id": "B-001-010-002",
        "options": [
            "Never",
            "Only if the station is operating illegally",
            "Only if the station begins transmitting on a frequency you are using",
            "You may expect, and cause, deliberate interference because it can't be helped during crowded band conditions"
        ],
        "question": "When may you deliberately interfere with another station's communications?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Amateurs are allowed to use the frequency band only if they do not cause interference to primary users",
        "id": "B-001-010-003",
        "options": [
            "Amateurs are allowed to use the frequency band only if they do not cause interference to primary users",
            "Nothing special: all users of a frequency band have equal rights to operate",
            "Amateurs are only allowed to use the frequency band during emergencies",
            "Amateurs must increase transmitter power to overcome any interference caused by primary users"
        ],
        "question": "If the regulations say that the amateur service is a secondary user of a frequency band, and another service is a primary user, what does this mean?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Both station operators have an equal right to operate on the frequency",
        "id": "B-001-010-004",
        "options": [
            "Both station operators have an equal right to operate on the frequency",
            "The station operator with a lesser qualification must yield the frequency to an operator of higher qualification",
            "The station operator with a lower power output must yield the frequency to the station with a higher power output",
            "Station operators in ITU Regions 1 and 3 must yield the frequency to stations in ITU Region 2"
        ],
        "question": "What rule applies if two amateurs want to use the same frequency?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Harmful interference",
        "id": "B-001-010-005",
        "options": [
            "Harmful interference",
            "Intentional interference",
            "Adjacent interference",
            "Disruptive interference"
        ],
        "question": "What name is given to a form of interference that seriously degrades, obstructs or repeatedly interrupts a radiocommunication service?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "the Minister may require that the necessary steps for the prevention of the interference be taken by the radio amateur",
        "id": "B-001-010-006",
        "options": [
            "the Minister may require that the necessary steps for the prevention of the interference be taken by the radio amateur",
            "the amateur station operator is not obligated to take any action",
            "the amateur station operator may continue to operate without restrictions",
            "the amateur station operator may continue to operate and the necessary steps can be taken when the amateur operator can afford it"
        ],
        "question": "Where interference to the reception of radiocommunications is caused by the operation of an amateur station:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "430.0 to 450.0 MHz",
        "id": "B-001-010-007",
        "options": [
            "430.0 to 450.0 MHz",
            "7.0 to 7.1 MHz",
            "144.0 to 148.0 MHz",
            "14.0 to 14.2 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "Radio amateur operation must not cause interference to other radio services operating in which of the following bands?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "902 to 928 MHz",
        "id": "B-001-010-008",
        "options": [
            "902 to 928 MHz",
            "144 to 148 MHz",
            "222 to 225 MHz",
            "50 to 54 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "Radio amateur operations are not ARE NOT protected from interference caused by another service operating in which of the following frequency bands?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "may make trials or tests, even though there is a possibility of interfering with other stations",
        "id": "B-001-010-009",
        "options": [
            "may make trials or tests, even though there is a possibility of interfering with other stations",
            "shall not cause harmful interference to a station in another service which has primary use of that band",
            "may conduct technical experiments using the station apparatus",
            "may make trials or tests, except if there is a possibility of interference to other stations"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following is not correct? The operator of an amateur station:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "902 to 928 MHz",
        "id": "B-001-010-010",
        "options": [
            "902 to 928 MHz",
            "3.5 to 4.0 MHz",
            "430 to 450 MHz",
            "135.7 to 137.8 kHz"
        ],
        "question": "Which of these amateur bands may be heavily occupied by licence exempt devices?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "2300 to 2450 MHz",
        "id": "B-001-010-011",
        "options": [
            "2300 to 2450 MHz",
            "430 to 450 MHz",
            "144 to 148 MHz",
            "1240 to 1300 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "The amateur radio service is authorized to share a portion of what Industrial Scientific Medical (ISM) band that is heavily used by licence exempt devices?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "only with other amateur stations",
        "id": "B-001-011-001",
        "options": [
            "only with other amateur stations",
            "with anyone who uses international Morse code",
            "with non amateur stations",
            "with any station involved in a real or simulated emergency"
        ],
        "question": "Amateur radio stations may communicate:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Never",
        "id": "B-001-011-002",
        "options": [
            "Never",
            "When relaying messages on behalf of government agencies",
            "When messages are destined to agencies without amateur radio support",
            "When normal communication systems are overloaded, damaged or disrupted"
        ],
        "question": "During relief operations in the days following a disaster, when may an amateur use his equipment to communicate on frequencies outside amateur bands?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "you should offer assistance",
        "id": "B-001-011-003",
        "options": [
            "you should offer assistance",
            "you may offer assistance using international Morse code only",
            "you may offer assistance after contacting Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada for permission to do so",
            "you may not offer assistance"
        ],
        "question": "If you hear an unanswered distress signal on an amateur band where you do not have privileges to communicate:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "radio communications required for the immediate safety of life of individuals or the immediate protection of property",
        "id": "B-001-011-004",
        "options": [
            "radio communications required for the immediate safety of life of individuals or the immediate protection of property",
            "music",
            "commercially recorded material",
            "programming that originates from a broadcast undertaking"
        ],
        "question": "In the amateur radio service, it is permissible to broadcast:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "any means of radiocommunication",
        "id": "B-001-011-005",
        "options": [
            "any means of radiocommunication",
            "only use radiocommunication bands for which the operator is qualified to use",
            "use any means of radiocommunication, but only on internationally recognized emergency channels",
            "only Morse code communications on internationally recognized emergency channels"
        ],
        "question": "An amateur radio station in distress may:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "When normal communication systems are overloaded, damaged or disrupted",
        "id": "B-001-011-006",
        "options": [
            "When normal communication systems are overloaded, damaged or disrupted",
            "Never: only official emergency stations may transmit in a disaster",
            "When normal communication systems are working but are not convenient",
            "Only when the local emergency net is activated"
        ],
        "question": "During a disaster, when may an amateur station make transmissions necessary to meet essential communication needs and assist relief operations?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "There are no limitations for a station in distress",
        "id": "B-001-011-007",
        "options": [
            "There are no limitations for a station in distress",
            "1000 watts PEP during daylight hours, reduced to 200 watts PEP during the night",
            "1500 watts PEP",
            "200 watts PEP"
        ],
        "question": "During an emergency, what power output limitations must be observed by a station in distress?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "most communications are handled by nets using predetermined frequencies in amateur bands. Operators not directly involved with disaster communications are requested to avoid making unnecessary transmissions on or near frequencies being used for disaster communications",
        "id": "B-001-011-008",
        "options": [
            "most communications are handled by nets using predetermined frequencies in amateur bands. Operators not directly involved with disaster communications are requested to avoid making unnecessary transmissions on or near frequencies being used for disaster communications",
            "use only frequencies in the 80 metre band",
            "use only frequencies in the 40 metre band",
            "use any United Nations approved frequency"
        ],
        "question": "During a disaster:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "during peace time and civil emergencies and exercises",
        "id": "B-001-011-009",
        "options": [
            "during peace time and civil emergencies and exercises",
            "using Morse code only",
            "when Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada has issued a special authorization",
            "only on the 7 and 14 MHz bands"
        ],
        "question": "Messages from recognized public service agencies may be handled by amateur radio stations:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "your station is directly involved with a distress situation",
        "id": "B-001-011-010",
        "options": [
            "your station is directly involved with a distress situation",
            "the other station is not operating according to the Radiocommunication Regulations",
            "you both wish to contact the same station",
            "the other station is interfering with your transmission"
        ],
        "question": "It is permissible to interfere with the working of another station if:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "No payment of any kind is allowed",
        "id": "B-001-012-001",
        "options": [
            "No payment of any kind is allowed",
            "Donation of amateur equipment",
            "Donation of equipment repairs",
            "Any amount agreed upon in advance"
        ],
        "question": "What kind of payment is allowed for third-party messages sent by an amateur station?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "if it is transmitted by an amateur station",
        "id": "B-001-012-002",
        "options": [
            "if it is transmitted by an amateur station",
            "if transmitted by any station using the international Morse code",
            "if transmitted in English or French",
            "during peacetime civil emergencies"
        ],
        "question": "Radiocommunications transmitted by stations other than a broadcasting station may be divulged or used:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "shall not demand or accept remuneration in any form, in respect of a radiocommunication that the person transmits or receives",
        "id": "B-001-012-003",
        "options": [
            "shall not demand or accept remuneration in any form, in respect of a radiocommunication that the person transmits or receives",
            "shall charge no less than $10 for each message that the person transmits or receives",
            "shall charge no more than $10 for each message that the person transmits or receives",
            "may accept a gift or gratuity in lieu of remuneration for any message that the person transmits or receives"
        ],
        "question": "The operator of an amateur station:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Where it is to provide information for a journalist",
        "id": "B-001-012-004",
        "options": [
            "Where it is to provide information for a journalist",
            "Where it is for the purpose of preserving or protecting property, or for the prevention of harm to a person",
            "Where it is for the purpose of giving evidence in a criminal or civil proceeding in which persons are required to give evidence",
            "Where it is on behalf of Canada, for the purpose of international or national defence or security"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following is not an exception from the penalties under the Act, for divulging, intercepting or using information obtained through radiocommunication, other than broadcasting?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "VA3XYZ",
        "id": "B-001-013-001",
        "options": [
            "VA3XYZ",
            "SM2CAN",
            "BY7HY",
            "KA9OLS"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following call signs is a valid Canadian amateur radio call sign?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "At least every thirty minutes, and at the beginning and at the end of a contact",
        "id": "B-001-013-002",
        "options": [
            "At least every thirty minutes, and at the beginning and at the end of a contact",
            "At the beginning of a contact and at least every thirty minutes after that",
            "At least once during each transmission",
            "At the beginning and end of each transmission"
        ],
        "question": "How often must an amateur station be identified?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Your call sign",
        "id": "B-001-013-003",
        "options": [
            "Your call sign",
            "Your \"handle\"",
            "Your first name and your location",
            "Your full name"
        ],
        "question": "What do you transmit to identify your amateur station?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Each station must transmit its own call sign",
        "id": "B-001-013-004",
        "options": [
            "Each station must transmit its own call sign",
            "No identification is required",
            "Both stations must transmit both call signs",
            "One of the stations must give both stations' call signs"
        ],
        "question": "What identification, if any, is required when two amateur stations begin communications?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Each station must transmit its own call sign",
        "id": "B-001-013-005",
        "options": [
            "Each station must transmit its own call sign",
            "No identification is required",
            "One of the stations must transmit both stations' call signs",
            "Both stations must transmit both call signs"
        ],
        "question": "What identification, if any, is required when two amateur stations end communications?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "30 minutes",
        "id": "B-001-013-006",
        "options": [
            "30 minutes",
            "20 minutes",
            "15 minutes",
            "10 minutes"
        ],
        "question": "What is the longest period of time an amateur station can transmit, without identifying by call sign?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Never, except to control a model craft",
        "id": "B-001-013-007",
        "options": [
            "Never, except to control a model craft",
            "Only for brief tests not meant as messages",
            "Only if it does not interfere with others",
            "Only for two-way or third-party communications"
        ],
        "question": "When may an amateur transmit unidentified communications?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "English or French",
        "id": "B-001-013-008",
        "options": [
            "English or French",
            "Any language being used for a contact",
            "Any language being used for a contact, providing Canada has a third-party communications agreement with that country",
            "Any language of a country which is a member of the International Telecommunication Union"
        ],
        "question": "What language may you use when identifying your station?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "at the beginning and at the end of each exchange of communications and at intervals not greater than 30 minutes",
        "id": "B-001-013-009",
        "options": [
            "at the beginning and at the end of each exchange of communications and at intervals not greater than 30 minutes",
            "at intervals not greater than three minutes when using voice communications",
            "at intervals not greater than ten minutes when using Morse code",
            "when requested to do so by the station being called"
        ],
        "question": "The call sign of an amateur station must be transmitted:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "at the beginning and end of each exchange of communications, and at least every 30 minutes, while in communications",
        "id": "B-001-013-010",
        "options": [
            "at the beginning and end of each exchange of communications, and at least every 30 minutes, while in communications",
            "every minute",
            "every 15 minutes",
            "once after initial contact"
        ],
        "question": "The call sign of an amateur station must be sent:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "VA, VE, VO or VY",
        "id": "B-001-013-011",
        "options": [
            "VA, VE, VO or VY",
            "GA, GE, MO or VQ",
            "A, K, N or W",
            "EA, EI, RO or UY"
        ],
        "question": "The call sign of a Canadian amateur radio station would normally start with the letters:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Have your friend wait until you determine from the foreign station if their administration permits third-party traffic",
        "id": "B-001-014-001",
        "options": [
            "Have your friend wait until you determine from the foreign station if their administration permits third-party traffic",
            "Since you can talk to foreign amateurs, your friend may keep talking as long as you are the control operator",
            "Report the incident to the foreign amateur's government",
            "Stop all discussions and quickly sign off"
        ],
        "question": "If a non-amateur friend is using your station to talk to someone in Canada, and a foreign station breaks in to talk to your friend, what should you do?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "You must continuously monitor and supervise the third party's participation",
        "id": "B-001-014-002",
        "options": [
            "You must continuously monitor and supervise the third party's participation",
            "You must key the transmitter and make the station identification",
            "You must monitor and supervise the communication only if contacts are made on frequencies below 30 MHz",
            "You must monitor and supervise the communication only if contacts are made in countries which have no third party communications"
        ],
        "question": "If you let an unqualified third party use your amateur station, what must you do at your station's control point?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "such communications have been authorized by the other country concerned",
        "id": "B-001-014-003",
        "options": [
            "such communications have been authorized by the other country concerned",
            "the amateur station has received written authorization from Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada to pass third party traffic",
            "the communication is transmitted by secret code",
            "prior remuneration has been received"
        ],
        "question": "Radio amateurs may use their stations to transmit international communications on behalf of a third party only if:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "when that country has notified the International Telecommunication Union that it objects to such communications",
        "id": "B-001-014-004",
        "options": [
            "when that country has notified the International Telecommunication Union that it objects to such communications",
            "without written permission from Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada",
            "until he has properly identified his station",
            "unless he is passing third-party traffic"
        ],
        "question": "A person operating a Canadian amateur station is forbidden to communicate with amateur stations of another country:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "the countries concerned have authorized such communications",
        "id": "B-001-014-005",
        "options": [
            "the countries concerned have authorized such communications",
            "English or French is used to identify the station at the end of each transmission",
            "the countries for which the traffic is intended have registered their consent to such communications with the ITU",
            "radiotelegraphy is used"
        ],
        "question": "International communications on behalf of third parties may be transmitted by an amateur station only if:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "the transmission of non-commercial or personal messages to or on behalf of a third party",
        "id": "B-001-014-006",
        "options": [
            "the transmission of non-commercial or personal messages to or on behalf of a third party",
            "the transmission of commercial or secret messages",
            "a simultaneous communication between three operators",
            "none of these answers"
        ],
        "question": "Amateur third party communications is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "specifically prohibited by the foreign administration concerned",
        "id": "B-001-014-007",
        "options": [
            "specifically prohibited by the foreign administration concerned",
            "satellite communication can be originated in the disaster area",
            "the foreign administration is in a declared state of war",
            "internet service is working well in the foreign country involved"
        ],
        "question": "International third party amateur radio communication in case of emergencies or disaster relief is expressly permitted unless:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "messages originated from Canadian Forces Affiliate Radio Service (CFARS)",
        "id": "B-001-014-008",
        "options": [
            "messages originated from Canadian Forces Affiliate Radio Service (CFARS)",
            "messages that are handled within a local network",
            "messages addressed to points within Canada",
            "all messages received from Canadian stations"
        ],
        "question": "One of the following is not considered to be communications on behalf of a third party, even though the message is originated by, or addressed to, a non-amateur:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "messages that originate from the United States Military Auxiliary Radio System (MARS)",
        "id": "B-001-014-009",
        "options": [
            "messages that originate from the United States Military Auxiliary Radio System (MARS)",
            "all messages originated by Canadian amateur stations",
            "messages addressed to points within Canada from the United States",
            "messages that are handled within local networks during a simulated emergency exercise"
        ],
        "question": "One of the following is not considered to be communications on behalf of a third party, even though the message may be originated by, or addressed to, a non-amateur:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "obtain a Canadian amateur certificate before operating in Canada",
        "id": "B-001-014-010",
        "options": [
            "obtain a Canadian amateur certificate before operating in Canada",
            "add to his call sign the Canadian call sign prefix for the geographic location of the station",
            "qualify his identification when operating phone by adding to the call sign the word \"mobile\" or \"portable\" or when operating Morse code by adding a slash \"/\"",
            "identify with the call sign assigned by the FCC"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following is not correct? While operating in Canada a radio amateur licensed by the Government of the United States must:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "pass third-party traffic with all duly licensed amateur stations in any country which is a member of the ITU",
        "id": "B-001-014-011",
        "options": [
            "pass third-party traffic with all duly licensed amateur stations in any country which is a member of the ITU",
            "pass messages originating from or destined to the United States Military Auxiliary Radio System (MARS)",
            "pass messages originating from or destined to the Canadian Forces Affiliate Radio Service (CFARS)",
            "communicate with a similar station of a country which has not notified ITU that it objects to such communications"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following statements is not correct? A Canadian radio amateur may, on amateur frequencies,:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Only the privileges allowed by your qualifications",
        "id": "B-001-015-001",
        "options": [
            "Only the privileges allowed by your qualifications",
            "Any privileges allowed by the additional qualifications",
            "All the emission privileges of the additional qualifications, but only the frequency privileges of your qualifications",
            "All the frequency privileges of the additional qualifications, but only the emission privileges of your qualifications"
        ],
        "question": "If you let another amateur with additional qualifications than yours control your station, what operating privileges are allowed?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Only the privileges allowed by your qualifications",
        "id": "B-001-015-002",
        "options": [
            "Only the privileges allowed by your qualifications",
            "Any privileges allowed by the additional qualifications",
            "All the emission privileges of the additional qualifications, but only the frequency privileges of your qualifications",
            "All the frequency privileges of the additional qualifications, but only the emission privileges of your qualifications"
        ],
        "question": "If you are the control operator at the station of another amateur who has additional qualifications to yours, what operating privileges are you allowed?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "You must pass a Morse code or Advanced test or attain a mark of 80% on the Basic exam",
        "id": "B-001-015-003",
        "options": [
            "You must pass a Morse code or Advanced test or attain a mark of 80% on the Basic exam",
            "You must notify Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada that you intend to operate on the HF bands",
            "You must pass a Morse code test",
            "You must attend a class to learn about HF communications"
        ],
        "question": "In addition to passing the Basic written examination, what must you do before you are allowed to use amateur frequencies below 30 MHz?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "on all frequencies above 30 MHz",
        "id": "B-001-015-004",
        "options": [
            "on all frequencies above 30 MHz",
            "if the control transmitter does not exceed 15 kHz of occupied bandwidth",
            "if the frequency used is below 30 MHz",
            "if only pulse modulation is used"
        ],
        "question": "The holder of an amateur radio certificate may operate radio controlled models:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "3.5 to 4.0 MHz",
        "id": "B-001-015-005",
        "options": [
            "3.5 to 4.0 MHz",
            "3.0 to 3.5 MHz",
            "4.0 to 4.5 MHz",
            "4.5 to 5.0 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "In Canada, the 75/80 metre amateur band corresponds in frequency to:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "1.8 to 2.0 MHz",
        "id": "B-001-015-006",
        "options": [
            "1.8 to 2.0 MHz",
            "1.5 to 2.0 MHz",
            "2.0 to 2.25 MHz",
            "2.25 to 2.5 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "In Canada, the 160 metre amateur band corresponds in frequency to:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "7.0 to 7.3 MHz",
        "id": "B-001-015-007",
        "options": [
            "7.0 to 7.3 MHz",
            "6.5 to 6.8 MHz",
            "6.0 to 6.3 MHz",
            "7.7 to 8.0 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "In Canada, the 40 metre amateur band corresponds in frequency to:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "14.000 to 14.350 MHz",
        "id": "B-001-015-008",
        "options": [
            "14.000 to 14.350 MHz",
            "13.500 to 14.000 MHz",
            "15.000 to 15.750 MHz",
            "16.350 to 16.830 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "In Canada, the 20 meter amateur band corresponds in frequency to:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "21.000 to 21.450 MHz",
        "id": "B-001-015-009",
        "options": [
            "21.000 to 21.450 MHz",
            "18.068 to 18.168 MHz",
            "14.000 to 14.350 MHz",
            "28.000 to 29.700 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "In Canada, the 15 metre amateur band corresponds in frequency to:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "28.000 to 29.700 MHz",
        "id": "B-001-015-010",
        "options": [
            "28.000 to 29.700 MHz",
            "24.890 to 24.990 MHz",
            "21.000 to 21.450 MHz",
            "50.000 to 54.000 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "In Canada, the 10 metre amateur band corresponds in frequency to:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "all amateur frequency bands above 30 MHz",
        "id": "B-001-015-011",
        "options": [
            "all amateur frequency bands above 30 MHz",
            "50 to 54 MHz only",
            "all amateur frequency bands",
            "50 to 54, 144 to 148, and 222 to 225 MHz only"
        ],
        "question": "In Canada, radio amateurs may use which of the following for radio control of models:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "30 kHz",
        "id": "B-001-016-001",
        "options": [
            "30 kHz",
            "20 kHz",
            "The total bandwidth shall not exceed that of a single-sideband phone emission",
            "The total bandwidth shall not exceed 10 times that of a CW emission"
        ],
        "question": "What is the maximum authorized bandwidth within the frequency range of 50 to 148 MHz?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "20 kHz",
        "id": "B-001-016-002",
        "options": [
            "20 kHz",
            "6 kHz",
            "30 kHz",
            "15 kHz"
        ],
        "question": "The maximum bandwidth of an amateur station's transmission allowed in the band 28 to 29.7 MHz is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "6 kHz",
        "id": "B-001-016-003",
        "options": [
            "6 kHz",
            "15 kHz",
            "20 kHz",
            "30 kHz"
        ],
        "question": "Except for one band, the maximum bandwidth of an amateur station's transmission allowed between 7 and 28 MHz is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "30 kHz",
        "id": "B-001-016-004",
        "options": [
            "30 kHz",
            "6 kHz",
            "20 kHz",
            "15 kHz"
        ],
        "question": "The maximum bandwidth of an amateur station's transmission allowed in the band 144 to 148 MHz is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "30 kHz",
        "id": "B-001-016-005",
        "options": [
            "30 kHz",
            "20 kHz",
            "6 kHz",
            "15 kHz"
        ],
        "question": "The maximum bandwidth of an amateur station's transmission allowed in the band 50 to 54 MHz is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "10.1 to 10.15 MHz",
        "id": "B-001-016-006",
        "options": [
            "10.1 to 10.15 MHz",
            "18.068 to 18.168 MHz",
            "24.89 to 24.99 MHz",
            "1.8 to 2.0 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following bands of amateur frequencies has a maximum allowed bandwidth of less than 6 kHz. That band is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "10.1 to 10.15 MHz",
        "id": "B-001-016-007",
        "options": [
            "10.1 to 10.15 MHz",
            "18.068 to 18.168 MHz",
            "24.89 to 24.99 MHz",
            "7.0 to 7.3 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "Single sideband is not permitted in the band:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Ensure that the bandwidth required on either side of the carrier frequency does not fall out of band",
        "id": "B-001-016-008",
        "options": [
            "Ensure that the bandwidth required on either side of the carrier frequency does not fall out of band",
            "Restrict operation to telegraphy",
            "Make sure that the emission mode is compatible with agreed band plans",
            "Watch the standing wave ratio so as not to damage the transmitter"
        ],
        "question": "What precaution must an amateur radio operator take when transmitting near band edges?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "fast-scan television (ATV) on 145 MHz",
        "id": "B-001-016-009",
        "options": [
            "fast-scan television (ATV) on 145 MHz",
            "AMTOR on 14.08 MHz",
            "300 bps packet on 10.145 MHz",
            "fast-scan television (ATV) on 440 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following answers is not correct? Based on the bandwidth required, the following modes may be transmitted on these frequencies:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "fast-scan television (ATV) on 14.23 MHz",
        "id": "B-001-016-010",
        "options": [
            "fast-scan television (ATV) on 14.23 MHz",
            "slow-scan television (SSTV) on 14.23 MHz",
            "frequency modulation (FM) on 29.6 MHz",
            "single-sideband (SSB) on 3.76 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following answers is not correct? Based on the bandwidth required, the following modes may be transmitted on these frequencies:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "single-sideband (SSB) on 10.12 MHz",
        "id": "B-001-016-011",
        "options": [
            "single-sideband (SSB) on 10.12 MHz",
            "frequency modulation (FM) on 29.6 MHz",
            "Morse radiotelegraphy (CW) on 10.11 MHz",
            "300 bps packet on 10.148 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following answers is not correct? Based on the bandwidth required, the following modes may be transmitted on these frequencies:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The minimum legal power necessary to communicate",
        "id": "B-001-017-001",
        "options": [
            "The minimum legal power necessary to communicate",
            "25 watts PEP output",
            "250 watts PEP output",
            "2000 watts PEP output"
        ],
        "question": "What amount of transmitter power should radio amateurs use at all times?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "250 W DC input",
        "id": "B-001-017-002",
        "options": [
            "250 W DC input",
            "1000 watts DC input",
            "200 watts PEP output",
            "25 watts PEP output"
        ],
        "question": "What is the most FM transmitter power a holder of only Basic Qualification may use on 147 MHz?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "At the antenna connector of the transmitter or amplifier",
        "id": "B-001-017-003",
        "options": [
            "At the antenna connector of the transmitter or amplifier",
            "At the power amplifier RF input terminals inside the transmitter or amplifier",
            "On the antenna itself, after the transmission line",
            "At the power supply terminals inside the transmitter or amplifier"
        ],
        "question": "Where in your station can you verify that legal power limits are respected?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "560 watts PEP output for SSB operation",
        "id": "B-001-017-004",
        "options": [
            "560 watts PEP output for SSB operation",
            "1000 watts PEP output for SSB operation",
            "1500 watts PEP output for SSB operation",
            "2000 watts PEP output for SSB operation"
        ],
        "question": "What is the maximum transmitting output power an amateur station may use on 3750 kHz, if the operator has Basic and Morse code qualifications?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "560 watts PEP output",
        "id": "B-001-017-005",
        "options": [
            "560 watts PEP output",
            "1000 watts PEP output",
            "2000 watts PEP output",
            "200 watts PEP output"
        ],
        "question": "What is the maximum transmitting power an amateur station may use for SSB operation on 7055 kHz, if the operator has Basic with Honours qualifications?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "1000 watts",
        "id": "B-001-017-006",
        "options": [
            "1000 watts",
            "250 watts",
            "500 watts",
            "750 watts"
        ],
        "question": "The DC power input to the anode or collector circuit of the final RF stage of a transmitter, used by a holder of an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate with Advanced Qualification, shall not exceed:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "1000 watts",
        "id": "B-001-017-007",
        "options": [
            "1000 watts",
            "250 watts",
            "1500 watts",
            "500 watts"
        ],
        "question": "The maximum DC input to the final stage of an amateur transmitter, when the operator is the holder of both the Basic and Advanced qualifications, is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "560 watts peak-envelope power, for transmitters producing any type of single sideband emission",
        "id": "B-001-017-008",
        "options": [
            "560 watts peak-envelope power, for transmitters producing any type of single sideband emission",
            "2500 watts peak power",
            "1000 watts carrier power for transmitters producing other emissions",
            "150 watts peak power"
        ],
        "question": "The operator of an amateur station, who is the holder of a Basic Qualification, shall ensure that the station power, when expressed as RF output power measured across an impedance matched load, does not exceed:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "250",
        "id": "B-001-017-009",
        "options": [
            "250",
            "1000",
            "750",
            "100"
        ],
        "question": "The holder of an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate with Basic Qualification is limited to a maximum of _______ watts when expressed as direct current input power to the anode or collector circuit of the transmitter stage supplying radio frequency energy to the antenna:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "160 watts carrier power VHF amplifier",
        "id": "B-001-017-010",
        "options": [
            "160 watts carrier power VHF amplifier",
            "100 watts carrier power HF transmitter",
            "200 watts carrier power HF transceiver",
            "600 watts PEP HF linear amplifier"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following is the most powerful equipment the holder of a Basic with Honours certificate can legally operate at full power?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Repeater station",
        "id": "B-001-018-001",
        "options": [
            "Repeater station",
            "Space station control and telemetry link",
            "Remote-control station",
            "Beacon station"
        ],
        "question": "What kind of amateur station automatically retransmits the signals of other stations?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "for brief tests on frequencies below 30 MHz",
        "id": "B-001-018-002",
        "options": [
            "for brief tests on frequencies below 30 MHz",
            "if the output to the final RF amplifier is kept under 5W",
            "when transmitting SSB",
            "in frequency bands below 30 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "An unmodulated carrier may be transmitted only:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "29.5 MHz",
        "id": "B-001-018-003",
        "options": [
            "29.5 MHz",
            "29.7 MHz",
            "50 MHz",
            "144 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "Radiotelephone signals in a frequency band below ____ MHz cannot be automatically retransmitted, unless these signals are received from a station operated by a person qualified to transmit on frequencies below the above frequency:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "in the 21 MHz band, when received in a VHF band, from a station operated by a person with only Basic Qualification",
        "id": "B-001-018-004",
        "options": [
            "in the 21 MHz band, when received in a VHF band, from a station operated by a person with only Basic Qualification",
            "in the 29.5-29.7 MHz band, when received in a VHF band, from a station operated by a person with only Basic Qualification",
            "in the 50-54 MHz frequency band, when received from a station operated by a person with only Basic Qualification",
            "in the 144-148 MHz frequency band, when received from a station operated by a person with only Basic Qualification"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following statements is not correct? Radiotelephone signals may be retransmitted:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "the frequency stability must be comparable to crystal control",
        "id": "B-001-019-001",
        "options": [
            "the frequency stability must be comparable to crystal control",
            "the bandwidth for any emission must not exceed 3 kHz",
            "the frequency stability of the transmitter must be at least two parts per million over a period of one hour",
            "an overmodulation indicator must be used"
        ],
        "question": "When operating on frequencies below 148 MHz:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "radiotelephony is used",
        "id": "B-001-019-002",
        "options": [
            "radiotelephony is used",
            "DC input power to the anode or collector circuit of the final RF stage is in excess of 250 watts",
            "radiotelegraphy is used",
            "persons other than the holder of the authorization use the station"
        ],
        "question": "A reliable means to prevent or indicate overmodulation must be employed at an amateur station if:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "overmodulation",
        "id": "B-001-019-003",
        "options": [
            "overmodulation",
            "resonance",
            "antenna power",
            "plate voltage"
        ],
        "question": "An amateur station using radiotelephony must install a device for indicating or preventing:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "100 percent",
        "id": "B-001-019-004",
        "options": [
            "100 percent",
            "75 percent",
            "50 percent",
            "90 percent"
        ],
        "question": "The maximum percentage of modulation permitted in the use of radiotelephony by an amateur station is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "a reliable means of determining the operating radio frequency",
        "id": "B-001-019-005",
        "options": [
            "a reliable means of determining the operating radio frequency",
            "a DC power meter",
            "an overmodulation indicating device",
            "a dummy antenna"
        ],
        "question": "All amateur stations, regardless of the mode of transmission used, must be equipped with:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "100 percent",
        "id": "B-001-019-006",
        "options": [
            "100 percent",
            "90 percent",
            "75 percent",
            "50 percent"
        ],
        "question": "The maximum percentage of modulation permitted in the use of radiotelephony by an amateur station is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Messages of a technical nature or personal remarks of relative unimportance",
        "id": "B-001-020-001",
        "options": [
            "Messages of a technical nature or personal remarks of relative unimportance",
            "Messages of any type, if the foreign country allows third-party communications with Canada",
            "Messages that are not religious, political, or patriotic in nature",
            "Messages of any type"
        ],
        "question": "What type of messages may be transmitted to an amateur station in a foreign country?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "communications are limited to messages of a technical or personal nature",
        "id": "B-001-020-002",
        "options": [
            "communications are limited to messages of a technical or personal nature",
            "communications are exchanged only with commercial stations",
            "all communications are conducted in secret code",
            "charges are properly applied to all third-party communications"
        ],
        "question": "The operator of an amateur station shall ensure that:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Transmissions between countries shall not include any messages of a technical nature, or remarks of a personal character",
        "id": "B-001-020-003",
        "options": [
            "Transmissions between countries shall not include any messages of a technical nature, or remarks of a personal character",
            "It is forbidden to transmit international messages on behalf of third parties, unless those countries make special arrangements",
            "Radiocommunications between countries shall be forbidden, if the administration of one of the countries objects",
            "Administrations shall take such measures as they judge necessary to verify the operational and technical qualifications of amateurs"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following is not a provision of the ITU Radio Regulations which apply to Canadian radio amateurs?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "none of the other answers",
        "id": "B-001-020-004",
        "options": [
            "none of the other answers",
            "1.8 MHz",
            "3.5MHz",
            "28 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "The ITU Radio Regulations limit those radio amateurs, who have not demonstrated proficiency in Morse code, to frequencies above:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "International Telecommunication Union",
        "id": "B-001-020-005",
        "options": [
            "International Telecommunication Union",
            "American Radio Relay League",
            "Radio Amateurs of Canada Inc.",
            "International Amateur Radio Union"
        ],
        "question": "In addition to complying with the Radiocommunication Act and Regulations, Canadian radio amateurs must also comply with the regulations of the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Region 2",
        "id": "B-001-021-001",
        "options": [
            "Region 2",
            "Region 4",
            "Region 3",
            "Region 1"
        ],
        "question": "In which International Telecommunication Union Region is Canada?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Those applicable to US radio amateurs",
        "id": "B-001-021-002",
        "options": [
            "Those applicable to US radio amateurs",
            "ITU Region 2",
            "ITU Region 3",
            "ITU Region 1"
        ],
        "question": "A Canadian radio amateur, operating his station in the state of Florida, is subject to which frequency band limits?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Those applicable to US radio amateurs",
        "id": "B-001-021-003",
        "options": [
            "Those applicable to US radio amateurs",
            "Those applicable to Canadian radio amateurs",
            "ITU Region 1",
            "ITU Region 2"
        ],
        "question": "A Canadian radio amateur, operating his station 7 kilometres (4 miles) offshore from the coast of Florida, is subject to which frequency band limits?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Region 3",
        "id": "B-001-021-004",
        "options": [
            "Region 3",
            "Region 1",
            "Region 2",
            "Region 4"
        ],
        "question": "Australia, Japan, and Southeast Asia are in which ITU Region?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Region 2",
        "id": "B-001-021-005",
        "options": [
            "Region 2",
            "Region 1",
            "Region 3",
            "Region 4"
        ],
        "question": "Canada is located in ITU Region:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The fee for taking an examination for an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate at an Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada office is $5 per qualification",
        "id": "B-001-022-001",
        "options": [
            "The fee for taking an examination for an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate at an Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada office is $5 per qualification",
            "An accredited examiner  may recover the cost of administering an examination",
            "An accredited volunteer examiner must hold an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate with Basic, Advanced, and Morse code qualifications",
            "There are no fees for taking an examination for an Amateur Radio Operator Certificate at an Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada office."
        ],
        "question": "Which of these statements is not correct?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A disabled candidate must pass a normal amateur radio certificate examination before being granted any qualification",
        "id": "B-001-022-002",
        "options": [
            "A disabled candidate must pass a normal amateur radio certificate examination before being granted any qualification",
            "A disabled candidate, taking a Morse code sending test, may be allowed to recite the examination text in Morse code sounds",
            "Examinations for disabled candidates may be given orally, or tailored to the candidate's ability to complete the examination",
            "An accredited examiner may recover the cost of administering an examination."
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following statements is not correct?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "to be negotiated between examiner and candidate",
        "id": "B-001-022-003",
        "options": [
            "to be negotiated between examiner and candidate",
            "always $20 per qualification",
            "always free of charge",
            "always $20 per visit regardless of the number of examinations"
        ],
        "question": "The fee for taking examinations for amateur radio operator certificates by an accredited volunteer examiner is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "no charge for qualification examinations",
        "id": "B-001-022-004",
        "options": [
            "no charge for qualification examinations",
            "$20 per visit, regardless of the number of qualification examinations",
            "$20 per qualification",
            "$5 per qualification examination"
        ],
        "question": "The fee for taking amateur radio certificate examinations at an Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada office is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A candidate with insufficient knowledge of English or French may be accompanied by an interpreter",
        "id": "B-001-022-005",
        "options": [
            "A candidate with insufficient knowledge of English or French may be accompanied by an interpreter",
            "A candidate who fails a written examination for lack of reading skills may be given an oral examination",
            "A candidate who fails a written examination due to not usually speaking English or French may be given an oral examination",
            "An examiner may request medical evidence from a practicing medical physician before accommodating testing"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following statements is false?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A radio amateur may erect any size antenna structure without consulting neighbours or the local land-use authority",
        "id": "B-001-023-001",
        "options": [
            "A radio amateur may erect any size antenna structure without consulting neighbours or the local land-use authority",
            "A radio amateur must follow Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada's antenna siting procedures.",
            "Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada expects radio amateurs to address community concerns in a responsible manner",
            "Prior to an installation, for which community concerns could be raised, radio amateurs may be required to consult with their land-use authority"
        ],
        "question": "Which of these statements about the installation or modification  of an antenna structure is not correct?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The Minister of Innovation, Science and Economic Development",
        "id": "B-001-023-002",
        "options": [
            "The Minister of Innovation, Science and Economic Development",
            "The person planning to use the tower or their spouse",
            "The local municipal government",
            "The majority of neighbours residing within a distance of three times the proposed antenna structure height"
        ],
        "question": "Who has authority over antenna installations including antenna masts and towers?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "When an exclusion criterion defined by Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada applies",
        "id": "B-001-023-003",
        "options": [
            "When an exclusion criterion defined by Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada applies",
            "In a rural area",
            "When the structure is part of an amateur radio antenna",
            "When transmitting will only be done at low power"
        ],
        "question": "If you are planning to install or modify an antenna system under what conditions may you not be required to contact land use authorities to determine public consultation requirements?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "must fulfill the public consultation requirements set out in Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada's Default Public Consultation Process unless the land use authority excludes their type of proposal from consultation or it is excluded by Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada's process",
        "id": "B-001-023-004",
        "options": [
            "must fulfill the public consultation requirements set out in Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada's Default Public Consultation Process unless the land use authority excludes their type of proposal from consultation or it is excluded by Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada's process",
            "can proceed with their project without public consultation",
            "must implement a public consultation process of their own design",
            "must wait for the land use authority to develop a public consultation process"
        ],
        "question": "The land use authority has not established a process for public consultation for antenna systems. The radio amateur planning to install or modify an antenna system:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Participating in public meetings on the project",
        "id": "B-001-023-005",
        "options": [
            "Participating in public meetings on the project",
            "Providing written notice",
            "Addressing relevant questions comments and concerns",
            "Providing an opportunity for the public to respond regarding measures to address reasonable and relevant concerns"
        ],
        "question": "Which is not an element of the Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada Public Consultation Process for antenna systems?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "reasonable and relevant concerns provided in writing within the 30 day public comment period",
        "id": "B-001-023-006",
        "options": [
            "reasonable and relevant concerns provided in writing within the 30 day public comment period",
            "all questions, comments and concerns raised",
            "comments reported in media reporting on the proposal",
            "opposition to the project"
        ],
        "question": "The Default Public Consultation Process for antenna systems requires proponents to address:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Exclusions listed in either CPC-2-0-03 or the Local land use authority process",
        "id": "B-001-023-007",
        "options": [
            "Exclusions listed in either CPC-2-0-03 or the Local land use authority process",
            "Exclusions listed in the Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada Client Procedures Circular on Radiocommunications and Broadcasting Antenna Systems CPC-2-0-03",
            "Exclusions defined in the Local land use authority process",
            "Exclusions listed in both CPC-2-0-03 and the Local land use authority process"
        ],
        "question": "Where a municipality has developed a public consultation process which of the following options best describes all circumstances when public consultation may not be required?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "be made by Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada",
        "id": "B-001-023-008",
        "options": [
            "be made by Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada",
            "be postponed until those in dispute reach an agreement",
            "be made by the municipality in which the antenna is to be built",
            "be made by a majority vote of those residing within a radius of three times the antenna structure height"
        ],
        "question": "Where the proponent and a stakeholder other than the general public reach an impasse over a proposed antenna system the final decision will:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "the taller of the height exclusion in the land use authority public consultation process and Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada's antenna siting procedures",
        "id": "B-001-023-009",
        "options": [
            "the taller of the height exclusion in the land use authority public consultation process and Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada's antenna siting procedures",
            "10m",
            "15m",
            "21m"
        ],
        "question": "In general, what is the tallest amateur radio antenna system excluded from the requirement to consult with the land use authority and the public where there is a land use authority defined public consultation process?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The municipality or local land use authority",
        "id": "B-001-023-010",
        "options": [
            "The municipality or local land use authority",
            "Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada",
            "The person planning to erect an antenna structure",
            "The provincial government"
        ],
        "question": "Where a land use authority or municipality has established a public consultation process for antenna systems, who determines how public consultation should take place?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Health Canada",
        "id": "B-001-024-001",
        "options": [
            "Health Canada",
            "Canadian Standards Association",
            "Environment Canada",
            "Transport Canada"
        ],
        "question": "What organization has published safety guidelines for the maximum limits of RF energy near the human body?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It gives RF exposure limits for the human body",
        "id": "B-001-024-002",
        "options": [
            "It gives RF exposure limits for the human body",
            "It lists all RF frequency allocations for interference protection",
            "It sets transmitter power limits for interference protection",
            "It sets antenna height limits for aircraft protection"
        ],
        "question": "What is the purpose of the Safety Code 6?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "30 to 300 MHz",
        "id": "B-001-024-003",
        "options": [
            "30 to 300 MHz",
            "300 to 3000 MHz",
            "Above 1500 MHz",
            "3 to 30 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "According to Safety Code 6, what frequencies cause us the greatest risk from RF energy?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The human body absorbs RF energy the most in this range",
        "id": "B-001-024-004",
        "options": [
            "The human body absorbs RF energy the most in this range",
            "There are more transmitters operating in this range",
            "There are fewer transmitters operating in this range",
            "Most transmissions in this range are for a longer time"
        ],
        "question": "Why is the limit of exposure to RF the lowest in the frequency range of 30 MHz to 300 MHz, according to Safety Code 6?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Not specified",
        "id": "B-001-024-005",
        "options": [
            "Not specified",
            "10 watts",
            "25 watts",
            "125 milliwatts"
        ],
        "question": "According to Safety Code 6, what is the maximum safe power output to the antenna of a hand-held VHF or UHF radio?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Permissible exposure levels of RF fields decreases as frequency is decreased below 10 MHz",
        "id": "B-001-024-006",
        "options": [
            "Permissible exposure levels of RF fields decreases as frequency is decreased below 10 MHz",
            "Maximum exposure levels of RF fields to the general population, in the frequency range 10 to 300 MHz, is 28 V/m RMS (E-field)",
            "Permissible exposure levels of RF fields increases as frequency is increased from 300 MHz to 1.5 GHz",
            "Permissible exposure levels of RF fields increases as frequency is decreased from 10 MHz to 1 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following statements is not correct?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "increases, as frequency is increased from 300 MHz to 1.5 GHz",
        "id": "B-001-024-007",
        "options": [
            "increases, as frequency is increased from 300 MHz to 1.5 GHz",
            "decreases, as frequency is decreased below 10 MHz",
            "increases, as frequency is increased from 10 MHz to 300 MHz",
            "decreases, as frequency is increased above 300 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "The permissible exposure levels of RF fields:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "hand held transmitters are excluded from Safety Code 6 requirements",
        "id": "B-001-024-008",
        "options": [
            "hand held transmitters are excluded from Safety Code 6 requirements",
            "Antenna gain, distance, transmitter power and frequency are all factors which influence the electric field strength and a person's exposure to radio energy.",
            "Safety Code 6 uses different units for the magnetic field strength and the electric field strength when stating limits",
            "Safety Code 6 specifies lower exposure limits for the general public in uncontrolled areas than it does for people in controlled areas"
        ],
        "question": "Which statement is not correct?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Safety Code 6 sets limits for RF exposure from all radio transmitters regardless of power output",
        "id": "B-001-024-009",
        "options": [
            "Safety Code 6 sets limits for RF exposure from all radio transmitters regardless of power output",
            "Safety Code 6 regulates the operation of receivers only",
            "The operation of portable transmitting equipment is of no concern in Safety Code 6",
            "Portable transmitters, operating below 1 GHz, with an output power equal to, or less than 7 watts, are exempt from the requirements of Safety Code 6"
        ],
        "question": "Which statement is correct?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Safety Code 6 sets limits in terms of power levels fed into antennas",
        "id": "B-001-024-010",
        "options": [
            "Safety Code 6 sets limits in terms of power levels fed into antennas",
            "Safety Code 6 sets limits for contact currents that could be drawn from ungrounded or poorly grounded objects",
            "Safety Code 6 sets limits for induced currents, electrical field strength and magnetic field strength from electromagnetic radiation",
            "Safety Code 6 sets limits for allowable rates at which RF energy is absorbed in the body (Specific Absorption Rate)"
        ],
        "question": "Which of these statements about Safety Code 6 is false?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "on the premises of the affected equipment is below Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada's specified immunity criteria",
        "id": "B-001-025-001",
        "options": [
            "on the premises of the affected equipment is below Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada's specified immunity criteria",
            "at the transmitting location is below the radio amateur's maximum allowable transmitter power",
            "at the transmitting location is above 100 watts",
            "near the affected equipment is above Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada's specified immunity criteria"
        ],
        "question": "In the event of the malfunctioning of a neighbour's broadcast FM receiver and stereo system, it will be deemed that the affected equipment's lack of immunity is the cause if the field strength:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "on the neighbour's premises is above Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada's specified immunity criteria",
        "id": "B-001-025-002",
        "options": [
            "on the neighbour's premises is above Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada's specified immunity criteria",
            "near the TV is below  Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada's specified immunity criteria",
            "at the transmitting location is below the radio amateur's maximum allowable transmitter power",
            "at the transmitting location is above the radio amateur's maximum allowable transmitter power"
        ],
        "question": "In the event of interference to a neighbour's television receiver, according to EMCAB-2 it will be deemed that a radio amateur's transmission is the cause of the problem if the field strength:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Radio-sensitive equipment",
        "id": "B-001-025-003",
        "options": [
            "Radio-sensitive equipment",
            "Cable television converters",
            "Audio and video recorders",
            "Broadcast receivers"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following is defined in EMCAB-2 as \"any device, machinery or equipment, other than radio apparatus, the use or functioning of which is, or can be, adversely affected by radiocommunication emissions\"?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Broadcast transmitters",
        "id": "B-001-025-004",
        "options": [
            "Broadcast transmitters",
            "Broadcast receivers",
            "Associated equipment",
            "Radio-sensitive equipment"
        ],
        "question": "According to EMCAB-2 which of the following types of equipment is not included in the list of field strength criteria for resolution of immunity complaints?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Say the call sign of the station you want to contact, then your call sign",
        "id": "B-002-001-001",
        "options": [
            "Say the call sign of the station you want to contact, then your call sign",
            "Say the other operator's name, then your call sign three times",
            "Say, \"Breaker, breaker,\"",
            "Say the call sign of the station you want to contact three times"
        ],
        "question": "What is a good way to make contact on a repeater?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "To increase the range of portable and mobile stations",
        "id": "B-002-001-002",
        "options": [
            "To increase the range of portable and mobile stations",
            "To link amateur stations with the telephone system",
            "To retransmit weather information during severe storm warnings",
            "To make local information available 24 hours a day"
        ],
        "question": "What is the main purpose of a repeater?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A process which seeks to carefully assign frequencies so as to minimize interference with neighbouring repeaters",
        "id": "B-002-001-003",
        "options": [
            "A process which seeks to carefully assign frequencies so as to minimize interference with neighbouring repeaters",
            "A band plan detailing modes and frequency segments within a band",
            "The selection of simplex frequencies by individual operators",
            "A part of the planning prior to a contest"
        ],
        "question": "What is frequency coordination on VHF and UHF bands?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It interrupts lengthy transmissions without pauses",
        "id": "B-002-001-004",
        "options": [
            "It interrupts lengthy transmissions without pauses",
            "It lets a repeater have a rest period after heavy use",
            "It logs repeater transmit time to predict when a repeater will fail",
            "It tells how long someone has been using a repeater"
        ],
        "question": "What is the purpose of a repeater time-out timer?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A sub-audible tone that activates a receiver audio output when present",
        "id": "B-002-001-005",
        "options": [
            "A sub-audible tone that activates a receiver audio output when present",
            "A tone used by repeaters to mark the end of a transmission",
            "A special signal used for telemetry between amateur space stations and Earth stations",
            "A special signal used for radio control of model craft"
        ],
        "question": "What is a CTCSS tone?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Say the station's call sign, then identify your own station",
        "id": "B-002-001-006",
        "options": [
            "Say the station's call sign, then identify your own station",
            "Say \"break, break 79,\" then say the station's call sign",
            "Say \"CQ\" three times, then say the station's call sign",
            "Wait for the station to call \"CQ\", then answer it"
        ],
        "question": "How do you call another station on a repeater if you know the station's call sign?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "To listen for anyone else wanting to use the repeater",
        "id": "B-002-001-007",
        "options": [
            "To listen for anyone else wanting to use the repeater",
            "To check the SWR of the repeater",
            "To reach for pencil and paper for third-party communications",
            "To dial up the repeater's autopatch"
        ],
        "question": "Why should you pause briefly between transmissions when using a repeater?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A long transmission may prevent someone with an emergency from using the repeater",
        "id": "B-002-001-008",
        "options": [
            "A long transmission may prevent someone with an emergency from using the repeater",
            "To keep long-distance charges down",
            "To give any listening non-hams a chance to respond",
            "To see if the receiving station operator is still awake"
        ],
        "question": "Why should you keep transmissions short when using a repeater?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Say your call sign during a break between transmissions",
        "id": "B-002-001-009",
        "options": [
            "Say your call sign during a break between transmissions",
            "Wait for the end of a transmission and start calling the desired party",
            "Shout, \"break, break!\" to show that you're eager to join the conversation",
            "Turn on an amplifier and override whoever is talking"
        ],
        "question": "What is the proper way to join into a conversation on a repeater?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Where are you?",
        "id": "B-002-001-010",
        "options": [
            "Where are you?",
            "What is your 20?",
            "Locations are not normally told by radio",
            "What is your 12?"
        ],
        "question": "What is the accepted way to ask someone their location when using a repeater?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "600 kHz",
        "id": "B-002-001-011",
        "options": [
            "600 kHz",
            "800 kHz",
            "1 000 kHz",
            "400 kHz"
        ],
        "question": "FM repeater operation on the 2 metre band uses one frequency for transmission and one for reception. The difference in frequency between the transmit and receive frequency is normally:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Use Standard International Phonetics for each letter of your call sign",
        "id": "B-002-002-001",
        "options": [
            "Use Standard International Phonetics for each letter of your call sign",
            "Use any words which start with the same letters as your call sign for each letter of your call",
            "Talk louder",
            "Turn up your microphone gain"
        ],
        "question": "To make your call sign better understood when using voice transmissions, what should you do?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The Standard International Phonetic Alphabet",
        "id": "B-002-002-002",
        "options": [
            "The Standard International Phonetic Alphabet",
            "Q signals",
            "Unique words of your choice",
            "A speech compressor"
        ],
        "question": "What can you use as an aid for correct station identification when using phone?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Alfa",
        "id": "B-002-002-003",
        "options": [
            "Alfa",
            "Able",
            "Adam",
            "America"
        ],
        "question": "What is the Standard International Phonetic for the letter A?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Bravo",
        "id": "B-002-002-004",
        "options": [
            "Bravo",
            "Brazil",
            "Borneo",
            "Baker"
        ],
        "question": "What is the Standard International Phonetic for the letter B?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Delta",
        "id": "B-002-002-005",
        "options": [
            "Delta",
            "Dog",
            "Denmark",
            "David"
        ],
        "question": "What is the Standard International Phonetic for the letter D?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Echo",
        "id": "B-002-002-006",
        "options": [
            "Echo",
            "Easy",
            "Edward",
            "England"
        ],
        "question": "What is the Standard International Phonetic for the letter E?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Golf",
        "id": "B-002-002-007",
        "options": [
            "Golf",
            "George",
            "Germany",
            "Gibraltar"
        ],
        "question": "What is the Standard International Phonetic for the letter G?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "India",
        "id": "B-002-002-008",
        "options": [
            "India",
            "Iran",
            "Italy",
            "Item"
        ],
        "question": "What is the Standard International Phonetic for the letter I?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lima",
        "id": "B-002-002-009",
        "options": [
            "Lima",
            "Love",
            "London",
            "Luxembourg"
        ],
        "question": "What is the Standard International Phonetic for the letter L?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Papa",
        "id": "B-002-002-010",
        "options": [
            "Papa",
            "Portugal",
            "Paris",
            "Peter"
        ],
        "question": "What is the Standard International Phonetic for the letter P?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Romeo",
        "id": "B-002-002-011",
        "options": [
            "Romeo",
            "Roger",
            "Radio",
            "Romania"
        ],
        "question": "What is the Standard International Phonetic for the letter R?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Say \"CQ\" three times, followed by \"this is,\" followed by your call sign spoken three times",
        "id": "B-002-003-001",
        "options": [
            "Say \"CQ\" three times, followed by \"this is,\" followed by your call sign spoken three times",
            "Say \"CQ\" once, followed by \"this is,\" followed by your call sign spoken three times",
            "Say \"CQ\" at least five times, followed by \"this is,\" followed by your call sign spoken once",
            "Say \"CQ\" at least ten times, followed by \"this is,\" followed by your call sign spoken once"
        ],
        "question": "What is the correct way to call \"CQ\" when using voice ?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Say the other station's call sign once, followed by \"this is,\" then your call sign given phonetically",
        "id": "B-002-003-002",
        "options": [
            "Say the other station's call sign once, followed by \"this is,\" then your call sign given phonetically",
            "Say the other station's call sign at least five times phonetically, followed by \"this is,\" then your call sign twice",
            "Say the other station's call sign at least three times, followed by \"this is,\" and your call sign at least five times phonetically",
            "Say the other station's call sign at least ten times, followed by \"this is,\" then your call sign at least twice"
        ],
        "question": "How should you answer a voice CQ call?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Transmitting and receiving on the same frequency",
        "id": "B-002-003-003",
        "options": [
            "Transmitting and receiving on the same frequency",
            "Transmitting and receiving over a wide area",
            "Transmitting on one frequency and receiving on another",
            "Transmitting one-way communications"
        ],
        "question": "What is simplex operation?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "When signals are reliable between communicating parties without using a repeater",
        "id": "B-002-003-004",
        "options": [
            "When signals are reliable between communicating parties without using a repeater",
            "When the most reliable communications are needed",
            "When an emergency telephone call is needed",
            "When you are traveling and need some local information"
        ],
        "question": "When should you consider using simplex operation instead of a repeater?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "To minimize interference on HF bands capable of long-distance communication",
        "id": "B-002-003-005",
        "options": [
            "To minimize interference on HF bands capable of long-distance communication",
            "Because greater output power is permitted on VHF and UHF",
            "Because HF transmissions are not propagated locally",
            "Because signals are stronger on VHF and UHF frequencies"
        ],
        "question": "Why should local amateur communications use VHF and UHF frequencies instead of HF frequencies?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "You may inadvertently choose a channel that is the input to a local repeater",
        "id": "B-002-003-006",
        "options": [
            "You may inadvertently choose a channel that is the input to a local repeater",
            "Interference may be caused to unlicensed devices operating in the same band",
            "Implanted medical devices share the same spectrum",
            "Some frequencies are designated for narrow band FM and others for wideband FM"
        ],
        "question": "Why should we be careful in choosing a simplex frequency when operating VHF or UHF FM?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "See if you can clearly receive the station on the repeater's input frequency",
        "id": "B-002-003-007",
        "options": [
            "See if you can clearly receive the station on the repeater's input frequency",
            "See if a third station can clearly receive both of you",
            "See if you can clearly receive a more distant repeater",
            "See if you can clearly receive the station on a lower frequency band"
        ],
        "question": "If you are talking to a station using a repeater, how would you find out if you could communicate using simplex instead?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Changing the repeater's frequency is not practical",
        "id": "B-002-003-008",
        "options": [
            "Changing the repeater's frequency is not practical",
            "The repeater's output power may ruin your station's receiver",
            "There are more repeater operators than simplex operators",
            "Changing the repeater's frequency requires the authorization of Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada"
        ],
        "question": "If you are operating simplex on a repeater frequency, why would it be good amateur practice to change to another frequency?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Upper",
        "id": "B-002-003-009",
        "options": [
            "Upper",
            "Lower",
            "FM",
            "Double"
        ],
        "question": "Which sideband is commonly used for 20-metre phone operation?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lower",
        "id": "B-002-003-010",
        "options": [
            "Lower",
            "FM",
            "Double",
            "Upper"
        ],
        "question": "Which sideband is commonly used on 3755 kHz for phone operation?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Listen for signals from that area from an amateur beacon station or a foreign broadcast or television station on a nearby frequency",
        "id": "B-002-003-011",
        "options": [
            "Listen for signals from that area from an amateur beacon station or a foreign broadcast or television station on a nearby frequency",
            "Ask others on your local 2 metre FM repeater",
            "Telephone an experienced local amateur",
            "Look at the propagation forecasts in an amateur radio magazine"
        ],
        "question": "What is the best method to tell if a band is \"open\" for communication with a particular distant location?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Listen to make sure others are not using the frequency",
        "id": "B-002-004-001",
        "options": [
            "Listen to make sure others are not using the frequency",
            "Check your antenna for resonance at the selected frequency",
            "Make sure the SWR on your antenna transmission line is high enough",
            "Listen to make sure that someone will be able to hear you"
        ],
        "question": "What should you do before you transmit on any frequency?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Turn down your power output to the minimum necessary",
        "id": "B-002-004-002",
        "options": [
            "Turn down your power output to the minimum necessary",
            "Turn on your speech processor",
            "Reduce your SWR",
            "Continue with your contact, making no changes"
        ],
        "question": "If you contact another station and your signal is extremely strong and perfectly readable, what adjustment should you make to your transmitter?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Tune the transmitter into a dummy load",
        "id": "B-002-004-003",
        "options": [
            "Tune the transmitter into a dummy load",
            "Use a long wire antenna",
            "Tune up on 40 metres first, then switch to the desired band",
            "Use twin lead instead of coaxial cable transmission lines"
        ],
        "question": "What is one way to shorten transmitter tune-up time on the air to cut down on interference?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Use a dummy load",
        "id": "B-002-004-004",
        "options": [
            "Use a dummy load",
            "Choose an unoccupied frequency",
            "Use a non-resonant antenna",
            "Use a resonant antenna that requires no loading-up procedure"
        ],
        "question": "How can on-the-air interference be minimized during a lengthy transmitter testing or tuning procedure?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "To test or adjust your transceiver without causing interference",
        "id": "B-002-004-005",
        "options": [
            "To test or adjust your transceiver without causing interference",
            "To give comparative signal reports",
            "It is faster to tune",
            "To reduce output power"
        ],
        "question": "Why would you use a dummy load?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Call and ask occupants to relinquish the frequency for the scheduled net operations, but if they are not agreeable, conduct the net on a frequency 3 to 5 kHz away from the regular net frequency",
        "id": "B-002-004-006",
        "options": [
            "Call and ask occupants to relinquish the frequency for the scheduled net operations, but if they are not agreeable, conduct the net on a frequency 3 to 5 kHz away from the regular net frequency",
            "Reduce your output power and start the net as usual",
            "Increase your power output so that net participants will be able to hear you over the existing activity",
            "Cancel the net for that day"
        ],
        "question": "If you are the net control station of a daily HF net, what should you do if the frequency on which you normally meet is in use just before the net begins?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "As a courtesy to the net, move to a different frequency",
        "id": "B-002-004-007",
        "options": [
            "As a courtesy to the net, move to a different frequency",
            "Increase your power output to ensure that all net participants can hear you",
            "Transmit as long as possible on the frequency so that no other stations may use it",
            "Turn off your radio"
        ],
        "question": "If a net is about to begin on a frequency which you and another station are using, what should you do?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Move your contact to another frequency",
        "id": "B-002-004-008",
        "options": [
            "Move your contact to another frequency",
            "Tell the interfering stations to change frequency, since you were there first",
            "Report the interference to your local Amateur Auxiliary Coordinator",
            "Increase the output power of your transmitter to overcome the interference"
        ],
        "question": "If propagation changes during your contact and you notice increasing interference from other activity on the same frequency, what should you do?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Approximately 3 kHz",
        "id": "B-002-004-009",
        "options": [
            "Approximately 3 kHz",
            "150 to 500 Hz",
            "Approximately 6 kHz",
            "Approximately 10 kHz"
        ],
        "question": "When selecting a single-sideband phone transmitting frequency, what minimum frequency separation from a contact in progress should you allow (between suppressed carriers) to minimize interference?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A guideline for using different operating modes within an amateur band",
        "id": "B-002-004-010",
        "options": [
            "A guideline for using different operating modes within an amateur band",
            "A plan of operating schedules within an amateur band published by Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada",
            "A plan devised by a club to best use a frequency band during a contest",
            "A guideline for deviating from amateur frequency band allocations"
        ],
        "question": "What is a band plan?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "listen carefully so as not to interrupt communications already in progress",
        "id": "B-002-004-011",
        "options": [
            "listen carefully so as not to interrupt communications already in progress",
            "ask if the frequency is occupied",
            "make an announcement on the frequency indicating that you intend to make a call",
            "decrease your receiver's volume"
        ],
        "question": "Before transmitting, the first thing you should do is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Send the letters \"CQ\" three times, followed by \"DE\", followed by your call sign sent three times",
        "id": "B-002-005-001",
        "options": [
            "Send the letters \"CQ\" three times, followed by \"DE\", followed by your call sign sent three times",
            "Send the letters \"CQ\" three times, followed by \"DE\", followed by your call sign sent once",
            "Send the letters \"CQ\" ten times, followed by \"DE\", followed by your call sign sent once",
            "Send the letters \"CQ\" over and over"
        ],
        "question": "What is the correct way to call \"CQ\" when using Morse code?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Send the other station's call sign twice, followed by \"DE\", followed by your call sign twice",
        "id": "B-002-005-002",
        "options": [
            "Send the other station's call sign twice, followed by \"DE\", followed by your call sign twice",
            "Send your call sign four times",
            "Send the other station's call sign once, followed by \"DE\", followed by your call sign four times",
            "Send your call sign followed by your name, station location and a signal report"
        ],
        "question": "How should you answer a routine Morse code \"CQ\" call?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "At any speed which you can reliably receive",
        "id": "B-002-005-003",
        "options": [
            "At any speed which you can reliably receive",
            "At any speed below 5 w.p.m.",
            "At the highest speed your keyer will operate",
            "At the highest speed at which you can control the keyer"
        ],
        "question": "At what speed should a Morse code \"CQ\" call be transmitted?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Calling any station",
        "id": "B-002-005-004",
        "options": [
            "Calling any station",
            "Call on the quarter hour",
            "An antenna is being tested",
            "Only the station \"CQ\" should answer"
        ],
        "question": "What is the meaning of the procedural signal \"CQ\"?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "From",
        "id": "B-002-005-005",
        "options": [
            "From",
            "Received all correctly",
            "Calling any station",
            "Directional Emissions"
        ],
        "question": "What is the meaning of the procedural signal \"DE\"?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Any station please reply",
        "id": "B-002-005-006",
        "options": [
            "Any station please reply",
            "End of message",
            "Called station only transmit",
            "All received correctly"
        ],
        "question": "What is the meaning of the procedural signal \"K\"?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Distant station",
        "id": "B-002-005-007",
        "options": [
            "Distant station",
            "Calling any station",
            "Go ahead",
            "Best regards"
        ],
        "question": "What is meant by the term \"DX\"?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Best regards",
        "id": "B-002-005-008",
        "options": [
            "Best regards",
            "Long distance",
            "Love and kisses",
            "Go ahead"
        ],
        "question": "What is the meaning of the term \"73\"?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Incoming signals are received between transmitted Morse code dots and dashes",
        "id": "B-002-005-009",
        "options": [
            "Incoming signals are received between transmitted Morse code dots and dashes",
            "Automatic keyers are used to send Morse code instead of hand keys",
            "An operator must activate a manual send/receive switch before and after every transmission",
            "Breaking stations send the Morse code prosign \"BK\""
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following describes full break-in telegraphy (QSK)?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "150 to 500 Hz",
        "id": "B-002-005-010",
        "options": [
            "150 to 500 Hz",
            "5 to 50 Hz",
            "1 to 3 kHz",
            "3 to 6 kHz"
        ],
        "question": "When selecting a CW transmitting frequency, what minimum frequency separation from a contact in progress should you allow to minimize interference?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "listen to the frequency to make sure that it is not in use before transmitting",
        "id": "B-002-005-011",
        "options": [
            "listen to the frequency to make sure that it is not in use before transmitting",
            "always give stations a good readability report",
            "save time by leaving out spaces between words",
            "tune the transmitter using the operating antenna"
        ],
        "question": "Good Morse telegraphy operators:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A short way to describe signal reception",
        "id": "B-002-006-001",
        "options": [
            "A short way to describe signal reception",
            "A short way to describe transmitter power",
            "A short way to describe sunspot activity",
            "A short way to describe ionospheric conditions"
        ],
        "question": "What are \"RST\" signal reports?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Readability, signal strength, tone",
        "id": "B-002-006-002",
        "options": [
            "Readability, signal strength, tone",
            "Recovery, signal strength, tempo",
            "Recovery, signal speed, tone",
            "Readability, signal speed, tempo"
        ],
        "question": "What does \"RST\" mean in a signal report?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Your signal is perfectly readable and moderately strong",
        "id": "B-002-006-003",
        "options": [
            "Your signal is perfectly readable and moderately strong",
            "Your signal is readable with considerable difficulty",
            "Your signal is perfectly readable with near pure tone",
            "Your signal is perfectly readable, but weak"
        ],
        "question": "What is the meaning of: \"Your signal report is 5 7\"?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Your signal is readable with considerable difficulty and weak in strength",
        "id": "B-002-006-004",
        "options": [
            "Your signal is readable with considerable difficulty and weak in strength",
            "Your signal is unreadable, very weak in strength",
            "The station is located at latitude 33 degrees",
            "The contact is serial number 33"
        ],
        "question": "What is the meaning of: \"Your signal report is 3 3 \"?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "You are perfectly readable with a signal strength 20 decibels greater than S 9",
        "id": "B-002-006-005",
        "options": [
            "You are perfectly readable with a signal strength 20 decibels greater than S 9",
            "The bandwidth of your signal is 20 decibels above linearity",
            "Repeat your transmission on a frequency 20 kHz higher",
            "Your signal strength has increased by a factor of 100"
        ],
        "question": "What is the meaning of: \"You are 5 9 plus 20 dB\"?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The other operator needs to know how well he is received at the repeater, not how well you receive the repeater",
        "id": "B-002-006-006",
        "options": [
            "The other operator needs to know how well he is received at the repeater, not how well you receive the repeater",
            "The repeater gain affects your S-meter reading",
            "You need to listen to the repeater input frequency for an accurate signal report",
            "Signal reports are only useful on simplex communications"
        ],
        "question": "A distant station asks for a signal report on a local repeater you monitor. Which fact affects your assessment?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Increase by approximately one S unit",
        "id": "B-002-006-007",
        "options": [
            "Increase by approximately one S unit",
            "Increase by approximately four S units",
            "Decrease by approximately four S units",
            "Decrease by approximately one S unit"
        ],
        "question": "If the power output of a transmitter is increased by four times, how might a nearby receiver's S-meter reading change?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Approximately 4 times",
        "id": "B-002-006-008",
        "options": [
            "Approximately 4 times",
            "Approximately 5 times",
            "Approximately 3 times",
            "Approximately 2 times"
        ],
        "question": "By how many times must the power output of a transmitter be increased to raise the S-meter reading on a nearby receiver from S8 to S9?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Your signal is perfectly readable, moderately strong, and with perfect tone",
        "id": "B-002-006-009",
        "options": [
            "Your signal is perfectly readable, moderately strong, and with perfect tone",
            "Your signal is perfectly readable, weak strength, and with perfect tone",
            "Your signal is fairly readable, fair strength, and with perfect tone",
            "Your signal is barely readable, moderately strong, and with faint ripple"
        ],
        "question": "What does \"RST 579\" mean in a Morse code contact?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Your signal is quite readable, fair strength, and with perfect tone",
        "id": "B-002-006-010",
        "options": [
            "Your signal is quite readable, fair strength, and with perfect tone",
            "Your signal is very readable, very strong, and with perfect tone",
            "Your signal is barely readable, very weak, and with perfect tone",
            "Your signal is moderately readable, very weak, and with hum on the tone"
        ],
        "question": "What does \"RST 459\" mean in a Morse code contact?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Your signal is unreadable, and barely perceptible",
        "id": "B-002-006-011",
        "options": [
            "Your signal is unreadable, and barely perceptible",
            "Your signal is 11 dB over S9",
            "Your signal is first class in readability and first class in strength",
            "Your signal is very readable and very strong"
        ],
        "question": "What is the meaning of \"Your signal report is 1 1\"?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Send more slowly",
        "id": "B-002-007-001",
        "options": [
            "Send more slowly",
            "Interference from static",
            "Send \"RST\" report",
            "Radio station location is:"
        ],
        "question": "What is the meaning of the Q signal \"QRS\"?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "My location is",
        "id": "B-002-007-002",
        "options": [
            "My location is",
            "Stop sending",
            "My name is",
            "Time here is"
        ],
        "question": "What is one meaning of the Q signal \"QTH\"?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "QRL?",
        "id": "B-002-007-003",
        "options": [
            "QRL?",
            "QRV?",
            "QRU?",
            "QRZ?"
        ],
        "question": "What is the proper Q signal to use to see if a frequency is in use before transmitting on CW?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Change frequency",
        "id": "B-002-007-004",
        "options": [
            "Change frequency",
            "Use more power",
            "Send faster",
            "Send more slowly"
        ],
        "question": "What is one meaning of the Q signal \"QSY\"?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Your signal is fading",
        "id": "B-002-007-005",
        "options": [
            "Your signal is fading",
            "I am busy",
            "I have no message",
            "A contact is confirmed"
        ],
        "question": "What is the meaning of the Q signal \"QSB\"?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "QRZ?",
        "id": "B-002-007-006",
        "options": [
            "QRZ?",
            "QSL?",
            "QRL?",
            "QRT?"
        ],
        "question": "What is the proper Q signal to ask who is calling you on CW?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "I am being interfered with",
        "id": "B-002-007-007",
        "options": [
            "I am being interfered with",
            "I am troubled by static",
            "your signals are fading",
            "is my transmission being interfered with"
        ],
        "question": "The signal \"QRM\" signifies:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "are you troubled by static",
        "id": "B-002-007-008",
        "options": [
            "are you troubled by static",
            "I am busy",
            "Is my transmission being interfered with",
            "I am being interfered with"
        ],
        "question": "The signal \"QRN\" means:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "QRS",
        "id": "B-002-007-009",
        "options": [
            "QRS",
            "QRM",
            "QRL",
            "QRN"
        ],
        "question": "The \"Q signal\" indicating that you want the other station to send slower is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "QRZ?",
        "id": "B-002-007-010",
        "options": [
            "QRZ?",
            "QRK?",
            "QRP?",
            "QRM?"
        ],
        "question": "Who is calling me is denoted by the \"Q signal\":"
    },
    {
        "answer": "QRX",
        "id": "B-002-007-011",
        "options": [
            "QRX",
            "QRZ",
            "QRS",
            "QRT"
        ],
        "question": "The \"Q signal\" which signifies \"I will call you again\" is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "In a life-threatening distress situation",
        "id": "B-002-008-001",
        "options": [
            "In a life-threatening distress situation",
            "Never",
            "Only at specific times (at 15 and 30 minutes after the hour)",
            "Only in case of a severe weather watch"
        ],
        "question": "When may you use your amateur station to transmit an \"SOS\" or \"MAYDAY\"?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Immediately stop your contact and acknowledge the emergency call",
        "id": "B-002-008-002",
        "options": [
            "Immediately stop your contact and acknowledge the emergency call",
            "Tell the calling station that the frequency is in use",
            "Direct the calling station to the nearest emergency net frequency",
            "Call your local police station and inform them of the emergency call"
        ],
        "question": "If you are in contact with another station and you hear an emergency call for help on your frequency, what should you do?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Say \"MAYDAY\" several times",
        "id": "B-002-008-003",
        "options": [
            "Say \"MAYDAY\" several times",
            "Say \"SOS\" several times",
            "Say \"EMERGENCY\" several times",
            "Say \"HELP\" several times"
        ],
        "question": "What is the proper distress call to use when operating phone?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "SOS",
        "id": "B-002-008-004",
        "options": [
            "SOS",
            "CQD",
            "QRRR",
            "MAYDAY"
        ],
        "question": "What is the proper distress call to use when operating CW?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Break-in immediately following the transmission of the active party and state your situation and call sign",
        "id": "B-002-008-005",
        "options": [
            "Break-in immediately following the transmission of the active party and state your situation and call sign",
            "Say \"EMERGENCY\" three times",
            "Say \"SOS,\" then your call sign",
            "Say \"HELP\" as many times as it takes to get someone to answer"
        ],
        "question": "What is the proper way to interrupt a repeater conversation to signal a distress call?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "So you may provide communications in an emergency",
        "id": "B-002-008-006",
        "options": [
            "So you may provide communications in an emergency",
            "So you will comply with rules",
            "So you may operate in contests where AC power is not allowed",
            "So you may use your station while mobile"
        ],
        "question": "Why is it a good idea to have a way to operate your amateur station without using commercial AC power lines?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Several sets of charged batteries",
        "id": "B-002-008-007",
        "options": [
            "Several sets of charged batteries",
            "An extra antenna",
            "A portable amplifier",
            "A microphone headset for hands-free operation"
        ],
        "question": "What is the most important accessory to have for a hand-held radio in an emergency?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A dipole",
        "id": "B-002-008-008",
        "options": [
            "A dipole",
            "A parabolic dish",
            "A three-element Yagi",
            "A three-element quad"
        ],
        "question": "Which type of antenna would be a good choice as part of a portable HF amateur station that could be set up in case of an emergency?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Acknowledge the station in distress and determine its location and what assistance may be needed",
        "id": "B-002-008-009",
        "options": [
            "Acknowledge the station in distress and determine its location and what assistance may be needed",
            "Continue your communication because you were on frequency first",
            "Change to a different frequency so the station in distress may have a clear channel to call for assistance",
            "Immediately cease all transmissions because stations in distress have emergency rights to the frequency"
        ],
        "question": "If you are communicating with another amateur station and hear a station in distress break in, what should you do?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "an emergency message",
        "id": "B-002-008-010",
        "options": [
            "an emergency message",
            "no other messages",
            "a government priority message",
            "a safety message"
        ],
        "question": "In order of priority, a distress message comes before:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "contact authorities and then maintain watch until you are certain that assistance will be forthcoming",
        "id": "B-002-008-011",
        "options": [
            "contact authorities and then maintain watch until you are certain that assistance will be forthcoming",
            "enter the details in the log book and take no further action",
            "take no action",
            "tell all other stations to cease transmitting"
        ],
        "question": "If you hear distress traffic and are unable to render direct assistance you should:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A written proof of communication between two amateurs",
        "id": "B-002-009-001",
        "options": [
            "A written proof of communication between two amateurs",
            "A Notice of Violation from Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada",
            "A postcard reminding you when your certificate will expire",
            "A letter or postcard from an amateur pen pal"
        ],
        "question": "What is a \"QSL card\"?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A map projection centered on a particular location, used to determine the shortest path between points on the Earth's surface",
        "id": "B-002-009-002",
        "options": [
            "A map projection centered on a particular location, used to determine the shortest path between points on the Earth's surface",
            "A map projection centered on the North Pole",
            "A map that shows the angle at which an amateur satellite crosses the equator",
            "A map that shows the number of degrees longitude that an amateur satellite appears to move westward at the equator"
        ],
        "question": "What is an azimuthal map?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Azimuthal",
        "id": "B-002-009-003",
        "options": [
            "Azimuthal",
            "Mercator",
            "Polar projection",
            "Topographical"
        ],
        "question": "What is the most useful type of map to use when orienting a directional HF antenna toward a distant station?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "180 degrees",
        "id": "B-002-009-004",
        "options": [
            "180 degrees",
            "45 degrees",
            "90 degrees",
            "270 degrees"
        ],
        "question": "A directional antenna pointed in the long-path direction to another station is generally oriented how many degrees from its short-path heading?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A signed post card listing contact date, time, frequency, mode and power, called a \"QSL card\"",
        "id": "B-002-009-005",
        "options": [
            "A signed post card listing contact date, time, frequency, mode and power, called a \"QSL card\"",
            "A two-page letter containing a photograph of the operator",
            "A radiogram sent over the CW traffic net",
            "A packet message"
        ],
        "question": "What method is used by radio amateurs to provide written proof of communication between two amateur stations?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Point your beam 180 degrees away from that bearing and listen for the stations arriving on the \"long-path\"",
        "id": "B-002-009-006",
        "options": [
            "Point your beam 180 degrees away from that bearing and listen for the stations arriving on the \"long-path\"",
            "Point your antenna toward Newington, Connecticut",
            "Point your antenna to the north",
            "Point your antenna to the south"
        ],
        "question": "You hear other local stations talking to radio amateurs in New Zealand but you don't hear those stations with your beam aimed on the normal compass bearing to New Zealand. What should you try?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A logbook is required by Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada",
        "id": "B-002-009-007",
        "options": [
            "A logbook is required by Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada",
            "A log is important for recording contacts for operating awards",
            "A well-kept log preserves your fondest amateur radio memories for years",
            "A log is important for handling neighbour interference complaints"
        ],
        "question": "Which statement about recording all contacts and unanswered \"CQ calls\" in a station logbook or computer log is not correct?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Because it shows the compass bearing from your station to any place on Earth, for antenna planning and pointing",
        "id": "B-002-009-008",
        "options": [
            "Because it shows the compass bearing from your station to any place on Earth, for antenna planning and pointing",
            "Because it looks impressive",
            "Because it shows the angle at which an amateur satellite crosses the equator",
            "Because it shows the number of degrees longitude that an amateur satellite moves west"
        ],
        "question": "Why would it be useful to have an azimuthal world map centred on the location of your station?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Greenwich, England",
        "id": "B-002-009-009",
        "options": [
            "Greenwich, England",
            "Geneva, Switzerland",
            "Ottawa, Canada",
            "Newington, Connecticut"
        ],
        "question": "Station logs and confirmation (QSL) cards are always kept in UTC (Universal Time Coordinated). Where is that time based?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Universal Time Coordinated (formerly Greenwich Mean Time - GMT)",
        "id": "B-002-009-010",
        "options": [
            "Universal Time Coordinated (formerly Greenwich Mean Time - GMT)",
            "Universal Time Constant",
            "Unlisted Telephone Call",
            "Unlimited Time Capsule"
        ],
        "question": "When referring to contacts in the station log, what do the letters UTC mean?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "CHU, WWV or WWVH",
        "id": "B-002-009-011",
        "options": [
            "CHU, WWV or WWVH",
            "A non-directional beacon station",
            "Your local television station",
            "Your local radio station"
        ],
        "question": "To set your station clock accurately to UTC, you could receive the most accurate time off the air from _______?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "as close as possible to the transceiver output",
        "id": "B-003-001-001",
        "options": [
            "as close as possible to the transceiver output",
            "as close as possible to the antenna tuner output",
            "as close as possible to the antenna",
            "midway between the transceiver and antenna"
        ],
        "question": "A low pass filter in an HF station is most effective when connected:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "as close as possible to the linear amplifier output",
        "id": "B-003-001-002",
        "options": [
            "as close as possible to the linear amplifier output",
            "as close as possible to the antenna",
            "as close as possible to the antenna tuner output",
            "as close as possible to the linear amplifier input"
        ],
        "question": "A low pass filter in an HF station is most effective when connected:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Low pass filter",
        "id": "B-003-001-003",
        "options": [
            "Low pass filter",
            "Dummy load",
            "Antenna switch",
            "SWR bridge"
        ],
        "question": "In designing an HF station, which component would you use to reduce the effects of harmonic radiation?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "SWR bridge",
        "id": "B-003-001-004",
        "options": [
            "SWR bridge",
            "Antenna switch",
            "Linear amplifier",
            "Dummy load"
        ],
        "question": "Which component in an HF station is the most useful for determining the effectiveness of the antenna system?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Antenna switch",
        "id": "B-003-001-005",
        "options": [
            "Antenna switch",
            "Transceiver",
            "Low pass filter",
            "SWR bridge"
        ],
        "question": "Of the components in an HF station, which component would normally be connected closest to the antenna, antenna tuner and dummy load?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Antenna tuner",
        "id": "B-003-001-006",
        "options": [
            "Antenna tuner",
            "Antenna switch",
            "Dummy load",
            "SWR bridge"
        ],
        "question": "Of the components in an HF station, which component would be used to match impedances between the transceiver and antenna?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Dummy load",
        "id": "B-003-001-007",
        "options": [
            "Dummy load",
            "SWR bridge",
            "Low pass filter",
            "Antenna tuner"
        ],
        "question": "In an HF station, which component is temporarily connected in the tuning process or for adjustments to the transmitter?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "most antennas when operating below 14 MHz",
        "id": "B-003-001-008",
        "options": [
            "most antennas when operating below 14 MHz",
            "most antennas when operating above 14 MHz",
            "mono-band Yagi type antennas",
            "tri-band Yagi antennas"
        ],
        "question": "In an HF station, the antenna tuner is usually used for matching the transceiver with:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "with most antennas when operating below 14 MHz",
        "id": "B-003-001-009",
        "options": [
            "with most antennas when operating below 14 MHz",
            "with most antennas when operating above 14 MHz",
            "to tune into dummy loads",
            "to tune low pass filters"
        ],
        "question": "In an HF Station, the antenna tuner is commonly used:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "microphone",
        "id": "B-003-002-001",
        "options": [
            "microphone",
            "modulator",
            "power amplifier",
            "frequency multiplier"
        ],
        "question": "In a frequency modulation transmitter, the input to the speech amplifier is connected to the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "speech amplifier",
        "id": "B-003-002-002",
        "options": [
            "speech amplifier",
            "modulator",
            "power amplifier",
            "oscillator"
        ],
        "question": "In a frequency modulation transmitter, the microphone is connected to the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "modulator",
        "id": "B-003-002-003",
        "options": [
            "modulator",
            "power amplifier",
            "microphone",
            "frequency multiplier"
        ],
        "question": "In a frequency modulation transmitter, the ____________is in between the speech amplifier and the oscillator."
    },
    {
        "answer": "oscillator",
        "id": "B-003-002-004",
        "options": [
            "oscillator",
            "speech amplifier",
            "power amplifier",
            "microphone"
        ],
        "question": "In a frequency modulation transmitter, the __________is located between the modulator and the frequency multiplier."
    },
    {
        "answer": "frequency multiplier",
        "id": "B-003-002-005",
        "options": [
            "frequency multiplier",
            "microphone",
            "speech amplifier",
            "modulator"
        ],
        "question": "In a frequency modulation transmitter, the ___________is located between the oscillator and the power amplifier."
    },
    {
        "answer": "power amplifier",
        "id": "B-003-002-006",
        "options": [
            "power amplifier",
            "modulator",
            "speech amplifier",
            "oscillator"
        ],
        "question": "In a frequency modulation transmitter, the _________ is located between the frequency multiplier and the antenna."
    },
    {
        "answer": "antenna",
        "id": "B-003-002-007",
        "options": [
            "antenna",
            "frequency multiplier",
            "microphone",
            "modulator"
        ],
        "question": "In a frequency modulation transmitter, the power amplifier output is connected to the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "antenna",
        "id": "B-003-003-001",
        "options": [
            "antenna",
            "mixer",
            "frequency discriminator",
            "limiter"
        ],
        "question": "In a frequency modulation receiver, the ________is connected to the input of the radio frequency amplifier."
    },
    {
        "answer": "radio frequency amplifier",
        "id": "B-003-003-002",
        "options": [
            "radio frequency amplifier",
            "audio frequency amplifier",
            "local oscillator",
            "intermediate frequency amplifier"
        ],
        "question": "In a frequency modulation receiver, the __________ is in between the antenna and the mixer."
    },
    {
        "answer": "mixer",
        "id": "B-003-003-003",
        "options": [
            "mixer",
            "radio frequency amplifier",
            "limiter",
            "antenna"
        ],
        "question": "In a frequency modulation receiver, the output of the local oscillator is fed to the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "local oscillator",
        "id": "B-003-003-004",
        "options": [
            "local oscillator",
            "frequency discriminator",
            "intermediate frequency amplifier",
            "speaker or headphones"
        ],
        "question": "In a frequency modulation receiver, the output of the ________is connected to the mixer."
    },
    {
        "answer": "filter",
        "id": "B-003-003-005",
        "options": [
            "filter",
            "limiter",
            "frequency discriminator",
            "radio frequency amplifier"
        ],
        "question": "In a frequency modulation receiver, the_________ is in between the mixer and the intermediate frequency amplifier."
    },
    {
        "answer": "intermediate frequency amplifier",
        "id": "B-003-003-006",
        "options": [
            "intermediate frequency amplifier",
            "local oscillator",
            "mixer",
            "radio frequency amplifier"
        ],
        "question": "In a frequency modulation receiver, the ________ is located between the filter and the limiter."
    },
    {
        "answer": "limiter",
        "id": "B-003-003-007",
        "options": [
            "limiter",
            "filter",
            "local oscillator",
            "radio frequency amplifier"
        ],
        "question": "In a frequency modulation receiver, the__________ is in between the intermediate frequency amplifier and the frequency discriminator."
    },
    {
        "answer": "frequency discriminator",
        "id": "B-003-003-008",
        "options": [
            "frequency discriminator",
            "intermediate frequency amplifier",
            "speaker or headphones",
            "local oscillator"
        ],
        "question": "In a frequency modulation receiver, the __________ is located between the limiter and the audio frequency amplifier."
    },
    {
        "answer": "audio frequency amplifier",
        "id": "B-003-003-009",
        "options": [
            "audio frequency amplifier",
            "limiter",
            "intermediate frequency amplifier",
            "radio frequency amplifier"
        ],
        "question": "In a frequency modulation receiver, the _________ is located between the speaker or headphones and the frequency discriminator."
    },
    {
        "answer": "speaker or headphones",
        "id": "B-003-003-010",
        "options": [
            "speaker or headphones",
            "intermediate frequency amplifier",
            "frequency discriminator",
            "limiter"
        ],
        "question": "In a frequency modulation receiver, the __________ connects to the audio frequency amplifier output."
    },
    {
        "answer": "master oscillator",
        "id": "B-003-004-001",
        "options": [
            "master oscillator",
            "power amplifier",
            "telegraph key",
            "power supply"
        ],
        "question": "In a CW transmitter, the output from the __________ is connected to the driver/buffer."
    },
    {
        "answer": "power supply",
        "id": "B-003-004-002",
        "options": [
            "power supply",
            "driver/buffer",
            "power amplifier",
            "master oscillator"
        ],
        "question": "In a typical CW transmitter, the ___________ is the primary source of direct current."
    },
    {
        "answer": "driver/buffer",
        "id": "B-003-004-003",
        "options": [
            "driver/buffer",
            "audio amplifier",
            "power supply",
            "telegraph key"
        ],
        "question": "In a CW transmitter, the_________ is between the master oscillator and the power amplifier."
    },
    {
        "answer": "telegraph key",
        "id": "B-003-004-004",
        "options": [
            "telegraph key",
            "master oscillator",
            "driver/buffer",
            "power amplifier"
        ],
        "question": "In a CW transmitter, the_____________ controls when RF energy is applied to the antenna."
    },
    {
        "answer": "power amplifier",
        "id": "B-003-004-005",
        "options": [
            "power amplifier",
            "power supply",
            "telegraph key",
            "master oscillator"
        ],
        "question": "In a CW transmitter, the ______________ is in between the driver/buffer stage and the antenna."
    },
    {
        "answer": "power amplifier",
        "id": "B-003-004-006",
        "options": [
            "power amplifier",
            "driver/buffer",
            "power supply",
            "master oscillator"
        ],
        "question": "In a CW transmitter, the output of the _____________ is transferred to the antenna."
    },
    {
        "answer": "radio frequency amplifier",
        "id": "B-003-005-001",
        "options": [
            "radio frequency amplifier",
            "product detector",
            "local oscillator",
            "intermediate frequency amplifier"
        ],
        "question": "In a single sideband and CW receiver, the antenna is connected to the ____________ ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "radio frequency amplifier",
        "id": "B-003-005-002",
        "options": [
            "radio frequency amplifier",
            "filter",
            "intermediate frequency amplifier",
            "audio frequency amplifier"
        ],
        "question": "In a single sideband and CW receiver, the output of the _____________ is connected to the mixer."
    },
    {
        "answer": "mixer",
        "id": "B-003-005-003",
        "options": [
            "mixer",
            "beat frequency oscillator",
            "product detector",
            "filter"
        ],
        "question": "In a single sideband and CW receiver, the __________ is connected to the radio frequency amplifier and the local oscillator."
    },
    {
        "answer": "local oscillator",
        "id": "B-003-005-004",
        "options": [
            "local oscillator",
            "intermediate frequency amplifier",
            "beat frequency oscillator",
            "product detector"
        ],
        "question": "In a single sideband and CW receiver, the output of the ___________ is connected to the mixer."
    },
    {
        "answer": "filter",
        "id": "B-003-005-005",
        "options": [
            "filter",
            "radio frequency amplifier",
            "beat frequency oscillator",
            "product detector"
        ],
        "question": "In a single sideband and CW receiver, the _____________ is in between the mixer and intermediate frequency amplifier."
    },
    {
        "answer": "intermediate frequency amplifier",
        "id": "B-003-005-006",
        "options": [
            "intermediate frequency amplifier",
            "audio frequency amplifier",
            "beat frequency oscillator",
            "radio frequency amplifier"
        ],
        "question": "In a single sideband and CW receiver, the __________ is in between the filter and product detector."
    },
    {
        "answer": "product detector",
        "id": "B-003-005-007",
        "options": [
            "product detector",
            "local oscillator",
            "beat frequency oscillator",
            "intermediate frequency amplifier"
        ],
        "question": "In a single sideband and CW receiver, the __________ output is connected to the audio frequency amplifier."
    },
    {
        "answer": "beat frequency oscillator",
        "id": "B-003-005-008",
        "options": [
            "beat frequency oscillator",
            "mixer",
            "radio frequency amplifier",
            "audio frequency amplifier"
        ],
        "question": "In a single sideband and CW receiver, the output of the ___________ is connected to the product detector."
    },
    {
        "answer": "audio frequency amplifier",
        "id": "B-003-005-009",
        "options": [
            "audio frequency amplifier",
            "intermediate frequency amplifier",
            "local oscillator",
            "radio frequency amplifier"
        ],
        "question": "In a single sideband and CW receiver, the __________ is connected to the output of the product detector."
    },
    {
        "answer": "speaker or headphones",
        "id": "B-003-005-010",
        "options": [
            "speaker or headphones",
            "mixer",
            "radio frequency amplifier",
            "beat frequency oscillator"
        ],
        "question": "In a single sideband and CW receiver, the __________ is connected to the output of the audio frequency amplifier."
    },
    {
        "answer": "radio frequency oscillator",
        "id": "B-003-006-001",
        "options": [
            "radio frequency oscillator",
            "variable frequency oscillator",
            "linear amplifier",
            "mixer"
        ],
        "question": "In a single sideband transmitter, the output of the ________ is connected to the balanced modulator."
    },
    {
        "answer": "balanced modulator",
        "id": "B-003-006-002",
        "options": [
            "balanced modulator",
            "microphone",
            "mixer",
            "radio frequency oscillator"
        ],
        "question": "In a single sideband transmitter, the output of the ____________ is connected to the filter."
    },
    {
        "answer": "filter",
        "id": "B-003-006-003",
        "options": [
            "filter",
            "radio frequency oscillator",
            "speech amplifier",
            "microphone"
        ],
        "question": "In a single sideband transmitter, the _____________ is in between the balanced modulator and the mixer."
    },
    {
        "answer": "microphone",
        "id": "B-003-006-004",
        "options": [
            "microphone",
            "radio frequency oscillator",
            "filter",
            "mixer"
        ],
        "question": "In a single sideband transmitter, the ______________ is connected to the speech amplifier."
    },
    {
        "answer": "speech amplifier",
        "id": "B-003-006-005",
        "options": [
            "speech amplifier",
            "filter",
            "variable frequency oscillator",
            "linear amplifier"
        ],
        "question": "In a single sideband transmitter, the output of the ___________ is connected to the balanced modulator."
    },
    {
        "answer": "mixer",
        "id": "B-003-006-006",
        "options": [
            "mixer",
            "antenna",
            "balanced modulator",
            "linear amplifier"
        ],
        "question": "In a single sideband transmitter, the output of the variable frequency oscillator is connected to the __________."
    },
    {
        "answer": "variable frequency oscillator",
        "id": "B-003-006-007",
        "options": [
            "variable frequency oscillator",
            "radio frequency oscillator",
            "linear amplifier",
            "antenna"
        ],
        "question": "In a single sideband transmitter, the output of the _________ is connected to the mixer."
    },
    {
        "answer": "linear amplifier",
        "id": "B-003-006-008",
        "options": [
            "linear amplifier",
            "variable frequency oscillator",
            "balanced modulator",
            "radio frequency oscillator"
        ],
        "question": "In an single sideband transmitter, the ____________ is in between the mixer and the antenna."
    },
    {
        "answer": "antenna",
        "id": "B-003-006-009",
        "options": [
            "antenna",
            "filter",
            "variable frequency oscillator",
            "speech amplifier"
        ],
        "question": "In a single sideband transmitter, the output of the linear amplifier is connected to the ______________."
    },
    {
        "answer": "input/output",
        "id": "B-003-007-001",
        "options": [
            "input/output",
            "antenna",
            "power supply",
            "transceiver"
        ],
        "question": "In an amateur digital radio system, the __________________interfaces with the computer."
    },
    {
        "answer": "computer",
        "id": "B-003-007-002",
        "options": [
            "computer",
            "amplifier",
            "antenna",
            "input/output"
        ],
        "question": "In an amateur digital radio system, the modem is connected to the ________."
    },
    {
        "answer": "modem",
        "id": "B-003-007-003",
        "options": [
            "modem",
            "computer",
            "scanner",
            "input/output"
        ],
        "question": "In an amateur digital radio system, the transceiver is connected to the ___________."
    },
    {
        "answer": "transceiver",
        "id": "B-003-007-004",
        "options": [
            "transceiver",
            "input/output",
            "scanner",
            "antenna"
        ],
        "question": "In an amateur digital radio system, the audio connections of the modem/sound card are connected to the ___________."
    },
    {
        "answer": "sound card",
        "id": "B-003-007-005",
        "options": [
            "sound card",
            "keyboard",
            "scanner",
            "serial port"
        ],
        "question": "In an amateur digital radio system, the modem function is often performed by the computer____________ ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "input",
        "id": "B-003-008-001",
        "options": [
            "input",
            "regulator",
            "filter",
            "rectifier"
        ],
        "question": "In a regulated power supply, the transformer connects to an external source which is referred to as______________."
    },
    {
        "answer": "transformer",
        "id": "B-003-008-002",
        "options": [
            "transformer",
            "output",
            "regulator",
            "filter"
        ],
        "question": "In a regulated power supply, the _______________ is between the input and the rectifier."
    },
    {
        "answer": "rectifier",
        "id": "B-003-008-003",
        "options": [
            "rectifier",
            "input",
            "output",
            "regulator"
        ],
        "question": "In a regulated power supply, the _______________ is between the transformer and the filter."
    },
    {
        "answer": "filter",
        "id": "B-003-008-004",
        "options": [
            "filter",
            "output",
            "transformer",
            "regulator"
        ],
        "question": "In a regulated power supply, the output of the rectifier is connected to the ______________."
    },
    {
        "answer": "regulator",
        "id": "B-003-008-005",
        "options": [
            "regulator",
            "transformer",
            "rectifier",
            "output"
        ],
        "question": "In a regulated power supply, the output of the filter connects to the ____________________."
    },
    {
        "answer": "output",
        "id": "B-003-008-006",
        "options": [
            "output",
            "rectifier",
            "input",
            "transformer"
        ],
        "question": "In a regulated power supply, the _______________is connected to the regulator."
    },
    {
        "answer": "boom",
        "id": "B-003-009-001",
        "options": [
            "boom",
            "reflector",
            "driven element",
            "director"
        ],
        "question": "In a Yagi 3 element directional antenna, the ____________ is primarily for mechanical support purposes."
    },
    {
        "answer": "reflector",
        "id": "B-003-009-002",
        "options": [
            "reflector",
            "director",
            "driven element",
            "boom"
        ],
        "question": "In a Yagi 3 element directional antenna, the ________ is the longest radiating element."
    },
    {
        "answer": "director",
        "id": "B-003-009-003",
        "options": [
            "director",
            "boom",
            "reflector",
            "driven element"
        ],
        "question": "In a Yagi 3 element directional antenna, the ______________ is the shortest radiating element."
    },
    {
        "answer": "driven element",
        "id": "B-003-009-004",
        "options": [
            "driven element",
            "boom",
            "director",
            "reflector"
        ],
        "question": "In a Yagi 3 element directional antenna, the ______________is not the longest nor the shortest radiating element."
    },
    {
        "answer": "CW, RTTY, SSB voice, FM voice",
        "id": "B-003-010-001",
        "options": [
            "CW, RTTY, SSB voice, FM voice",
            "CW, SSB voice, RTTY, FM voice",
            "CW, FM voice, RTTY, SSB voice",
            "RTTY, CW, SSB voice, FM voice"
        ],
        "question": "Which list of emission types is in order from the narrowest bandwidth to the widest bandwidth?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "RF input signal needed to achieve a given signal plus noise to noise ratio",
        "id": "B-003-010-002",
        "options": [
            "RF input signal needed to achieve a given signal plus noise to noise ratio",
            "audio output in watts",
            "bandwidth of the IF in kilohertz",
            "number of RF amplifiers"
        ],
        "question": "The figure in a receiver's specifications which indicates its sensitivity is the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "less signal or more noise",
        "id": "B-003-010-003",
        "options": [
            "less signal or more noise",
            "a steady oscillator drift",
            "more than one signal",
            "more signal or less noise"
        ],
        "question": "If two receivers of different sensitivity are compared, the less sensitive receiver will produce:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Single sideband suppressed carrier",
        "id": "B-003-010-004",
        "options": [
            "Single sideband suppressed carrier",
            "Double sideband full carrier",
            "Frequency modulation",
            "Pulse modulation"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following modes of transmission is usually detected with a product detector?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "the suppressed carrier must be replaced for detection",
        "id": "B-003-010-005",
        "options": [
            "the suppressed carrier must be replaced for detection",
            "it beats with the received carrier to produce the other sideband",
            "it reduces the passband of the IF stages",
            "it phases out the unwanted sideband signal"
        ],
        "question": "A receiver designed for SSB reception must have a BFO (beat frequency oscillator) because:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "455 kHz",
        "id": "B-003-010-006",
        "options": [
            "455 kHz",
            "7.435 MHz",
            "3.995 MHz",
            "3.54 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "A receiver receives an incoming signal of 3.54 MHz, and the local oscillator produces a signal of 3.995 MHz. To which frequency should the IF be tuned?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A notch filter",
        "id": "B-003-010-007",
        "options": [
            "A notch filter",
            "A band pass filter",
            "An all pass filter",
            "A pi-network filter"
        ],
        "question": "What kind of filter would you use to attenuate an interfering carrier signal while receiving an SSB transmission?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "sensitivity, selectivity and stability",
        "id": "B-003-010-008",
        "options": [
            "sensitivity, selectivity and stability",
            "selectivity, stability and frequency range",
            "sensitivity, stability and cross-modulation",
            "sensitivity, selectivity and image rejection"
        ],
        "question": "The three main parameters against which the quality of a receiver is measured are:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "2.4 kHz",
        "id": "B-003-010-009",
        "options": [
            "2.4 kHz",
            "250 Hz",
            "6 kHz",
            "500 Hz"
        ],
        "question": "A communications receiver has four filters installed in it, respectively designated as 250 Hz, 500 Hz, 2.4 kHz, and 6 kHz. If you were listening to single sideband, which filter would you utilize?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "250 Hz",
        "id": "B-003-010-010",
        "options": [
            "250 Hz",
            "500 Hz",
            "2.4 kHz",
            "6 kHz"
        ],
        "question": "A communications receiver has four filters installed in it, respectively designated as 250 Hz, 500 Hz, 2.4 kHz and 6 kHz. You are copying a CW transmission and there is a great deal of interference. Which one of the filters would you choose?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "750 - 850 Hz",
        "id": "B-003-010-011",
        "options": [
            "750 - 850 Hz",
            "2100 - 2300 Hz",
            "300 - 2700 Hz",
            "100 - 1100 Hz"
        ],
        "question": "Selectivity can be placed in the audio stages of a receiver by the utilization of RC active or passive audio filters. If you were to copy CW, which of the following bandpasses would you choose?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A small change in a transmitter's frequency each time it is keyed",
        "id": "B-003-011-001",
        "options": [
            "A small change in a transmitter's frequency each time it is keyed",
            "A high-pitched tone which is received along with a CW signal",
            "A slow change in transmitter frequency as the circuit warms up",
            "An overload in a receiver's audio circuit whenever CW is received"
        ],
        "question": "What does chirp mean?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Keep the power supply voltages very steady under transmit load",
        "id": "B-003-011-002",
        "options": [
            "Keep the power supply voltages very steady under transmit load",
            "Add a key-click filter",
            "Keep the power supply current very steady under transmit load",
            "Add a low pass filter"
        ],
        "question": "What can be done to keep a CW transmitter from chirping?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A VFO-controlled CW transmitter",
        "id": "B-003-011-003",
        "options": [
            "A VFO-controlled CW transmitter",
            "A crystal-controlled AM transmitter",
            "A single-sideband transmitter",
            "A digital radio transmitter"
        ],
        "question": "What circuit has a variable-frequency oscillator connected to a buffer/driver and a power amplifier?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Amplitude modulation",
        "id": "B-003-011-004",
        "options": [
            "Amplitude modulation",
            "Phase modulation",
            "Amplitude-rectification modulation",
            "Frequency modulation"
        ],
        "question": "What type of modulation system changes the amplitude of an RF wave for the purpose of conveying information?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Amplitude modulation",
        "id": "B-003-011-005",
        "options": [
            "Amplitude modulation",
            "Frequency modulation",
            "Pulse modulation",
            "Frequency shift keying"
        ],
        "question": "In what emission type does the instantaneous amplitude (envelope) of the RF signal vary in accordance with the modulating audio?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "an interrupted carrier",
        "id": "B-003-011-006",
        "options": [
            "an interrupted carrier",
            "a series of key-clicks",
            "a continuous carrier",
            "a voice-modulated carrier"
        ],
        "question": "Morse code is usually transmitted by radio as:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "full power will not be transferred to the antenna",
        "id": "B-003-011-007",
        "options": [
            "full power will not be transferred to the antenna",
            "loss of modulation in the transmitted signal",
            "the driver stage will not deliver power to the final",
            "the output tank circuit breaks down"
        ],
        "question": "A mismatched antenna or transmission line may present an incorrect load to the transmitter. The result may be:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "reduced antenna radiation",
        "id": "B-003-011-008",
        "options": [
            "reduced antenna radiation",
            "smaller DC current drain",
            "lower modulation percentage",
            "radiated key-clicks"
        ],
        "question": "One result of a slight mismatch between the power amplifier of a transmitter and the antenna would be:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "drift in frequency",
        "id": "B-003-011-009",
        "options": [
            "drift in frequency",
            "become over modulated",
            "generate key-clicks",
            "cause undue distortion"
        ],
        "question": "An RF oscillator should be electrically and mechanically stable. This is to ensure that the oscillator does not:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It has been dissipated as heat loss",
        "id": "B-003-011-010",
        "options": [
            "It has been dissipated as heat loss",
            "It has been used to provide greater efficiency",
            "It has been used to provide negative feedback",
            "It has been used to provide positive feedback"
        ],
        "question": "The input power to the final stage of your transmitter is 200 watts and the output is 125 watts. What has happened to the remaining power?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "appears as heat dissipation",
        "id": "B-003-011-011",
        "options": [
            "appears as heat dissipation",
            "is lost in the transmission line",
            "is due to oscillating",
            "radiates from the antenna"
        ],
        "question": "The difference between DC input power and RF output power of a transmitter RF amplifier:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It may cause splatter interference to other stations operating near its frequency",
        "id": "B-003-012-001",
        "options": [
            "It may cause splatter interference to other stations operating near its frequency",
            "It may cause interference to other stations operating on a higher frequency band",
            "It may cause atmospheric interference in the air around the antenna",
            "It may cause digital interference to computer equipment"
        ],
        "question": "What may happen if an SSB transmitter is operated with the microphone gain set too high?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It may cause audio distortion or splatter interference to other stations operating near its frequency",
        "id": "B-003-012-002",
        "options": [
            "It may cause audio distortion or splatter interference to other stations operating near its frequency",
            "It may cause digital interference to computer equipment",
            "It may cause atmospheric interference in the air around the antenna",
            "It may cause interference to other stations operating on a higher frequency band"
        ],
        "question": "What may happen if an SSB transmitter is operated with too much speech processing?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Peak envelope power",
        "id": "B-003-012-003",
        "options": [
            "Peak envelope power",
            "Peak output power",
            "Average radio-frequency power",
            "Peak transmitter power"
        ],
        "question": "What is the term for the average power supplied to an antenna transmission line during one RF cycle, at the crest of the modulation envelope?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Between 2 and 3 kHz",
        "id": "B-003-012-004",
        "options": [
            "Between 2 and 3 kHz",
            "1 kHz",
            "2 kHz",
            "Between 3 and 6 kHz"
        ],
        "question": "What is the usual bandwidth of a single-sideband amateur signal?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Filter",
        "id": "B-003-012-005",
        "options": [
            "Filter",
            "IF amplifier",
            "RF amplifier",
            "Carrier oscillator"
        ],
        "question": "In a typical single-sideband phone transmitter, what circuit processes signals from the balanced modulator and sends signals to the mixer?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "More power can be put into the sidebands for a given power amplifier capacity",
        "id": "B-003-012-006",
        "options": [
            "More power can be put into the sidebands for a given power amplifier capacity",
            "Only half the bandwidth is required for the same information content",
            "Greater modulation percentage is obtainable with lower distortion",
            "Simpler equipment can be used to receive a double-sideband suppressed-carrier signal"
        ],
        "question": "What is one advantage of carrier suppression in a double-sideband phone transmission?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It becomes distorted and occupies more bandwidth",
        "id": "B-003-012-007",
        "options": [
            "It becomes distorted and occupies more bandwidth",
            "It becomes stronger with no other effects",
            "It occupies less bandwidth with poor high-frequency response",
            "It has higher fidelity and improved signal-to-noise ratio"
        ],
        "question": "What happens to the signal of an overmodulated single-sideband or double-sideband phone transmitter?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "For slight movement of the ALC meter on modulation peaks",
        "id": "B-003-012-008",
        "options": [
            "For slight movement of the ALC meter on modulation peaks",
            "For full deflection of the ALC meter on modulation peaks",
            "For 100% frequency deviation on modulation peaks",
            "For a dip in plate current"
        ],
        "question": "How should the microphone gain control be adjusted on a single-sideband phone transmitter?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "suppress the carrier and pass on the two sidebands",
        "id": "B-003-012-009",
        "options": [
            "suppress the carrier and pass on the two sidebands",
            "make sure that the carrier and both sidebands are 180 degrees out of phase",
            "ensure that the percentage of modulation is kept constant",
            "make sure that the carrier and both sidebands are in phase"
        ],
        "question": "The purpose of a balanced modulator in an SSB transmitter is to:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "reinserted at the receiver",
        "id": "B-003-012-010",
        "options": [
            "reinserted at the receiver",
            "transmitted with one sideband",
            "inserted at the transmitter",
            "of no use at the receiver"
        ],
        "question": "In a SSB transmission, the carrier is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "controls the peak audio input so that the power amplifier is not overdriven",
        "id": "B-003-012-011",
        "options": [
            "controls the peak audio input so that the power amplifier is not overdriven",
            "reduces transmitter audio feedback",
            "increases the occupied bandwidth",
            "reduces the system noise"
        ],
        "question": "The automatic level control (ALC) in a SSB transmitter:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It may cause interference to other stations operating near its frequency",
        "id": "B-003-013-001",
        "options": [
            "It may cause interference to other stations operating near its frequency",
            "It may cause digital interference to computer equipment",
            "It may cause atmospheric interference in the air around the antenna",
            "It may cause interference to other stations operating on a higher frequency band"
        ],
        "question": "What may happen if an FM transmitter is operated with the microphone gain or deviation control set too high?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It may cause interference to other stations operating near its frequency",
        "id": "B-003-013-002",
        "options": [
            "It may cause interference to other stations operating near its frequency",
            "It may cause digital interference to computer equipment",
            "It may cause atmospheric interference in the air around the antenna",
            "It may cause interference to other stations operating on a higher frequency band"
        ],
        "question": "What may your FM hand-held or mobile transceiver do if you shout into its microphone and the deviation adjustment is set too high?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Talk farther away from the microphone",
        "id": "B-003-013-003",
        "options": [
            "Talk farther away from the microphone",
            "Talk louder into the microphone",
            "Let the transceiver cool off",
            "Change to a higher power level"
        ],
        "question": "What can you do if you are told your FM hand-held or mobile transceiver is overdeviating?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "An unmodulated carrier",
        "id": "B-003-013-004",
        "options": [
            "An unmodulated carrier",
            "A frequency-modulated carrier",
            "An amplitude-modulated carrier",
            "A phase-modulated carrier"
        ],
        "question": "What kind of emission would your FM transmitter produce if its microphone failed to work?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It provides good signal plus noise to noise ratio at low RF signal levels",
        "id": "B-003-013-005",
        "options": [
            "It provides good signal plus noise to noise ratio at low RF signal levels",
            "The carrier is not detectable",
            "It is more resistant to distortion caused by reflected signals",
            "Its RF carrier stays on frequency better than the AM modes"
        ],
        "question": "Why is FM voice best for local VHF/UHF radio communications?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Between 10 and 20 kHz",
        "id": "B-003-013-006",
        "options": [
            "Between 10 and 20 kHz",
            "Less than 5 kHz",
            "Between 5 and 10 kHz",
            "Greater than 20 kHz"
        ],
        "question": "What is the usual bandwidth of a frequency-modulated amateur signal for +/- 5kHz deviation?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Out-of-channel emissions",
        "id": "B-003-013-007",
        "options": [
            "Out-of-channel emissions",
            "Increased transmitter power",
            "Increased transmitter range",
            "Poor carrier suppression"
        ],
        "question": "What is the result of overdeviation in an FM transmitter?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Phase modulation",
        "id": "B-003-013-008",
        "options": [
            "Phase modulation",
            "Multiplex modulation",
            "Amplitude modulation",
            "Pulse modulation"
        ],
        "question": "What emission is produced by a reactance modulator connected to an RF power amplifier?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The bandwidth would exceed limits in the Regulations",
        "id": "B-003-013-009",
        "options": [
            "The bandwidth would exceed limits in the Regulations",
            "The transmitter efficiency for this mode is low",
            "Harmonics could not be attenuated to practical levels",
            "The frequency stability would not be adequate"
        ],
        "question": "Why isn't frequency modulated (FM) phone used below 28.0 MHz?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The frequency deviation of your transmitter is set too high",
        "id": "B-003-013-010",
        "options": [
            "The frequency deviation of your transmitter is set too high",
            "The power supply output voltage is low",
            "The repeater is reversing your sidebands",
            "The frequency counter is giving an incorrect reading and you are indeed off frequency"
        ],
        "question": "You are transmitting FM on the 2 metre band. Several stations advise you that your transmission is loud and distorted. A quick check with a frequency counter tells you that the transmitter is on the proper frequency. Which of the following is the most probable cause of the distortion?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "capture effect",
        "id": "B-003-013-011",
        "options": [
            "capture effect",
            "attach effect",
            "interference effect",
            "surrender effect"
        ],
        "question": "FM receivers perform in an unusual manner when two or more stations are present. The strongest signal, even though it is only two or three times stronger than the other signals, will be the only transmission demodulated. This is called:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "An electronic keyer",
        "id": "B-003-014-001",
        "options": [
            "An electronic keyer",
            "A key-operated on/off switch",
            "A notch filter",
            "A DTMF keypad"
        ],
        "question": "What do many amateurs use to help form good Morse code characters?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "To a transceiver",
        "id": "B-003-014-002",
        "options": [
            "To a transceiver",
            "To a power supply",
            "To an antenna switch",
            "To an antenna"
        ],
        "question": "Where would you connect a microphone for voice operation?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A microphone",
        "id": "B-003-014-003",
        "options": [
            "A microphone",
            "A receiver audio filter",
            "A terminal-voice controller",
            "A splatter filter"
        ],
        "question": "What would you connect to a transceiver for voice operation?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Because it changes RF energy into heat",
        "id": "B-003-014-004",
        "options": [
            "Because it changes RF energy into heat",
            "Because it absorbs static electricity",
            "Because it stores radio waves",
            "Because it stores electric current"
        ],
        "question": "Why might a dummy antenna get warm when in use?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "VOX",
        "id": "B-003-014-005",
        "options": [
            "VOX",
            "VXO",
            "VCO",
            "VFO"
        ],
        "question": "What is the circuit called which causes a transmitter to automatically transmit when an operator speaks into its microphone?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It improves signal intelligibility at the receiver",
        "id": "B-003-014-006",
        "options": [
            "It improves signal intelligibility at the receiver",
            "It reduces average transmitter power requirements",
            "It reduces unwanted noise pickup from the microphone",
            "It improves voice frequency fidelity"
        ],
        "question": "What is the reason for using a properly adjusted speech processor with a single-sideband phone transmitter?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It will add nothing to the output Peak Envelope Power (PEP)",
        "id": "B-003-014-007",
        "options": [
            "It will add nothing to the output Peak Envelope Power (PEP)",
            "It will increase the output PEP",
            "It will decrease the peak power output",
            "It will decrease the average power output"
        ],
        "question": "If a single-sideband phone transmitter is 100% modulated, what will a speech processor do to the transmitter's power?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "the receiver should be muted",
        "id": "B-003-014-008",
        "options": [
            "the receiver should be muted",
            "the transmit oscillator should be turned off",
            "the receiving antenna should be connected",
            "the power supply should be off"
        ],
        "question": "When switching from receive to transmit:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "disable the unit not being used",
        "id": "B-003-014-009",
        "options": [
            "disable the unit not being used",
            "ground the antenna on receive",
            "switch between meters",
            "disconnect the antenna tuner"
        ],
        "question": "A switching system to enable the use of one antenna for a transmitter and receiver should also:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "so that one antenna can be used for transmitter and receiver",
        "id": "B-003-014-010",
        "options": [
            "so that one antenna can be used for transmitter and receiver",
            "to change antennas for operation on other frequencies",
            "to prevent RF currents entering the receiver circuits",
            "to allow more than one transmitter to be used"
        ],
        "question": "An antenna changeover switch in a transmitter-receiver combination is necessary:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Loudspeaker",
        "id": "B-003-014-011",
        "options": [
            "Loudspeaker",
            "Crystal earpiece",
            "Resistor",
            "Capacitor"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following components could be used as a dynamic microphone?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A transmitting station is sending data to only one receiving station, it replies that the data is being received correctly",
        "id": "B-003-015-001",
        "options": [
            "A transmitting station is sending data to only one receiving station, it replies that the data is being received correctly",
            "A telephone link is working between two stations",
            "A message has reached an amateur station for local delivery",
            "A transmitting and receiving station are using a digipeater, so no other contacts can take place until they are finished"
        ],
        "question": "What does \"connected\" mean in an AX.25 packet-radio link?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A receiving station is displaying messages that may not be sent to it, and is not replying to any message",
        "id": "B-003-015-002",
        "options": [
            "A receiving station is displaying messages that may not be sent to it, and is not replying to any message",
            "A member of the Amateur Auxiliary is copying all messages",
            "A receiving station is displaying all messages sent to it, and replying that the messages are being received correctly",
            "Innovation, Science and Economic Development Canada is monitoring all messages"
        ],
        "question": "What does \"monitoring\" mean on a packet-radio frequency?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A station that retransmits only data that is marked to be retransmitted",
        "id": "B-003-015-003",
        "options": [
            "A station that retransmits only data that is marked to be retransmitted",
            "A repeater built using only digital electronics parts",
            "A repeater that changes audio signals to digital data",
            "A station that retransmits any data that it receives"
        ],
        "question": "What is a digipeater?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A way of connecting packet-radio stations so data can be sent over long distances",
        "id": "B-003-015-004",
        "options": [
            "A way of connecting packet-radio stations so data can be sent over long distances",
            "A way of connecting terminal-node controllers by telephone so data can be sent over long distances",
            "The connections on terminal-node controllers",
            "The programming in a terminal-node controller that rejects other callers if a station is already connected"
        ],
        "question": "What does \"network\" mean in packet radio?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A transceiver, a computer and possibly a GPS receiver",
        "id": "B-003-015-005",
        "options": [
            "A transceiver, a computer and possibly a GPS receiver",
            "A transceiver and a modem",
            "A DTMF keypad, a monitor and a transceiver",
            "A DTMF microphone, a monitor and a transceiver"
        ],
        "question": "In AX.25 packet-radio operation, what equipment connects to a terminal-node controller?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Connect a terminal-node controller to the transceiver's microphone input",
        "id": "B-003-015-006",
        "options": [
            "Connect a terminal-node controller to the transceiver's microphone input",
            "Connect a terminal-node controller to interrupt the transceiver's carrier wave",
            "Connect a keyboard to the transceiver's microphone input",
            "Connect a DTMF key pad to the transceiver's microphone input"
        ],
        "question": "How would you modulate a 2 meter FM transceiver to produce packet-radio emissions?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "250 to 500 Hz",
        "id": "B-003-015-007",
        "options": [
            "250 to 500 Hz",
            "Approximately 6 kHz",
            "Approximately 3 kHz",
            "60 Hz"
        ],
        "question": "When selecting a RTTY transmitting frequency, what minimum frequency separation from a contact in progress should you allow (center to center) to minimize interference?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "mark and space",
        "id": "B-003-015-008",
        "options": [
            "mark and space",
            "packet and AMTOR",
            "Baudot and ASCII",
            "dot and dash"
        ],
        "question": "Digital transmissions use signals called __________ to transmit the states 1 and 0:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Baudot",
        "id": "B-003-015-009",
        "options": [
            "Baudot",
            "ASCII",
            "Automatic Packet Reporting System (APRS)",
            "AX.25"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following terms does not apply to packet radio?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "for communications after contact has been established",
        "id": "B-003-015-010",
        "options": [
            "for communications after contact has been established",
            "at all times. Mode B is for test purposes only",
            "only when communications have been completed",
            "when making a general call"
        ],
        "question": "When using AMTOR transmissions, there are two modes that may be utilized. Mode A uses Automatic Repeat Request (ARQ) protocol and is normally used:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Splatter or out-of-channel emissions",
        "id": "B-003-015-011",
        "options": [
            "Splatter or out-of-channel emissions",
            "Higher signal-to-noise ratio",
            "Lower error rate",
            "Power amplifier overheating"
        ],
        "question": "With a digital communication mode based on a computer sound card, what is the result of feeding too much audio in the transceiver?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "About 12 volts",
        "id": "B-003-016-001",
        "options": [
            "About 12 volts",
            "About 240 volts",
            "About 120 volts",
            "About 9 volts"
        ],
        "question": "How much voltage does a standard automobile battery usually supply?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A battery",
        "id": "B-003-016-002",
        "options": [
            "A battery",
            "A potentiometer",
            "A fuse",
            "A resistor"
        ],
        "question": "Which component has a positive and a negative side?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "storage cell",
        "id": "B-003-016-003",
        "options": [
            "storage cell",
            "low leakage cell",
            "memory cell",
            "primary cell"
        ],
        "question": "A cell, that can be repeatedly recharged by supplying it with electrical energy, is known as a:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "lithium-ion battery",
        "id": "B-003-016-004",
        "options": [
            "lithium-ion battery",
            "germanium diode",
            "P channel FET",
            "carbon resistor"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following is a source of electromotive force (EMF)?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "can be repeatedly recharged",
        "id": "B-003-016-005",
        "options": [
            "can be repeatedly recharged",
            "has two terminals",
            "can be completely discharged",
            "contains an electrolyte"
        ],
        "question": "An important difference between a conventional flashlight battery and a lead acid battery is that only the lead acid battery:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "internal resistance",
        "id": "B-003-016-006",
        "options": [
            "internal resistance",
            "electrolyte becoming dry",
            "current capacity",
            "voltage capacity"
        ],
        "question": "An alkaline cell has a nominal voltage of 1.5 volts. When supplying a great deal of current, the voltage may drop to 1.2 volts. This is caused by the cell's:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "never",
        "id": "B-003-016-007",
        "options": [
            "never",
            "twice",
            "many times",
            "once"
        ],
        "question": "An inexpensive primary cell in use today is the carbon-zinc or flashlight cell. This type of cell can be recharged:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A battery charge will not last as long",
        "id": "B-003-016-008",
        "options": [
            "A battery charge will not last as long",
            "The internal resistance of the cell is short-circuited",
            "The battery will accept the subsequent charge in shorter time",
            "The voltage delivered will be higher"
        ],
        "question": "Battery capacity is commonly stated as a value of current delivered over a specified period of time. What is the effect of exceeding that specified current?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "parallel",
        "id": "B-003-016-009",
        "options": [
            "parallel",
            "series",
            "parallel resonant",
            "series resonant"
        ],
        "question": "To increase the current capacity of a cell, several cells should be connected in:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "series",
        "id": "B-003-016-010",
        "options": [
            "series",
            "parallel",
            "series-parallel",
            "resonance"
        ],
        "question": "To increase the voltage output, several cells are connected in:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "short-circuited",
        "id": "B-003-016-011",
        "options": [
            "short-circuited",
            "recharged",
            "left disconnected",
            "left overnight at room temperature"
        ],
        "question": "A lithium-ion battery should never be:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The power supply",
        "id": "B-003-017-001",
        "options": [
            "The power supply",
            "The speaker",
            "The microphone",
            "The SWR meter"
        ],
        "question": "If your mobile transceiver works in your car but not in your home, what should you check first?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A power supply",
        "id": "B-003-017-002",
        "options": [
            "A power supply",
            "A low pass filter",
            "An RS-232 interface",
            "A catalytic converter"
        ],
        "question": "What device converts household current to 12 volts DC?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A transceiver",
        "id": "B-003-017-003",
        "options": [
            "A transceiver",
            "An antenna switch",
            "A receiver",
            "An SWR meter"
        ],
        "question": "Which of these usually needs a high current capacity power supply?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A bad filter capacitor in the transmitter's power supply",
        "id": "B-003-017-004",
        "options": [
            "A bad filter capacitor in the transmitter's power supply",
            "Using an antenna which is the wrong length",
            "Energy from another transmitter",
            "Bad design of the transmitter's RF power output circuit"
        ],
        "question": "What may cause a buzzing or hum in the signal of an AC-powered transmitter?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "60 watts",
        "id": "B-003-017-005",
        "options": [
            "60 watts",
            "17 watts",
            "2.4 watts",
            "6 watts"
        ],
        "question": "A power supply is to supply DC at 12 volts at 5 amperes. The power transformer should be rated higher than:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "allows electrons to flow in only one direction from cathode to anode",
        "id": "B-003-017-006",
        "options": [
            "allows electrons to flow in only one direction from cathode to anode",
            "has a high resistance to AC but not to DC",
            "has a high resistance to DC but not to AC",
            "allows electrons to flow in only one direction from anode to cathode"
        ],
        "question": "The diode is an important part of a simple power supply. It converts AC to DC, since it:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "diode",
        "id": "B-003-017-007",
        "options": [
            "diode",
            "transformer",
            "capacitor",
            "resistor"
        ],
        "question": "To convert AC to pulsating DC, you could use a:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "120 and 240 volts",
        "id": "B-003-017-008",
        "options": [
            "120 and 240 volts",
            "110 and 220 volts",
            "100 and 200 volts",
            "130 and 260 volts"
        ],
        "question": "Power-line voltages have been made standard over the years and the voltages generally supplied to homes are approximately:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Number 10, 0.07 V per metre (0.02 V per foot)",
        "id": "B-003-017-009",
        "options": [
            "Number 10, 0.07 V per metre (0.02 V per foot)",
            "Number 14, 0.19 V per metre (0.06 V per foot)",
            "Number 12, 0.11 V per metre (0.03 V per foot)",
            "Number 8, 0.05 V per metre (0.01 V per foot)"
        ],
        "question": "Your mobile HF transceiver draws 22 amperes on transmit. The manufacturer suggests limiting voltage drop to 0.5 volt and the vehicle battery is 3 metres (10 feet) away. Given the losses below at that current, which minimum wire gauge must you use?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "To prevent an overcurrent situation from starting a fire",
        "id": "B-003-017-010",
        "options": [
            "To prevent an overcurrent situation from starting a fire",
            "To prevent interference to the vehicle's electronic systems",
            "To reduce the voltage drop in the radio's DC supply",
            "To protect the radio from transient voltages"
        ],
        "question": "Why are fuses needed as close as possible to the vehicle battery when wiring a transceiver directly to the battery?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The power supply",
        "id": "B-003-017-011",
        "options": [
            "The power supply",
            "The variable-frequency oscillator",
            "The driver circuit",
            "The power amplifier circuit"
        ],
        "question": "You have a very loud low-frequency hum appearing on your transmission. In what part of the transmitter would you first look for the trouble?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Use a key-operated on/off switch in the main power line",
        "id": "B-003-018-001",
        "options": [
            "Use a key-operated on/off switch in the main power line",
            "Use a carrier-operated relay in the main power line",
            "Put a \"Danger - High Voltage\" sign in the station",
            "Put fuses in the main power line"
        ],
        "question": "How could you best keep unauthorized persons from using your amateur station at home?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Disconnect the microphone when you are not using it",
        "id": "B-003-018-002",
        "options": [
            "Disconnect the microphone when you are not using it",
            "Tune the radio to an unused frequency when you are done using it",
            "Turn the radio off when you are not using it",
            "Put a \"Do not touch\" sign on the radio"
        ],
        "question": "How could you best keep unauthorized persons from using a mobile amateur station in your car?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "To keep unauthorized persons from using your station",
        "id": "B-003-018-003",
        "options": [
            "To keep unauthorized persons from using your station",
            "For safety, in case the main fuses fail",
            "To keep the power company from turning off your electricity during an emergency",
            "For safety, to turn off the station in the event of an emergency"
        ],
        "question": "Why would you use a key-operated on/off switch in the main power line of your station?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "To keep anyone opening the cabinet from getting shocked by dangerous high voltages",
        "id": "B-003-018-004",
        "options": [
            "To keep anyone opening the cabinet from getting shocked by dangerous high voltages",
            "To keep dangerous RF radiation from leaking out through an open cabinet",
            "To keep dangerous RF radiation from coming in through an open cabinet",
            "To turn the power supply off when it is not being used"
        ],
        "question": "Why would there be a switch in a high-voltage power supply to turn off the power if its cabinet is opened?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "As little as 20 milliamperes",
        "id": "B-003-018-005",
        "options": [
            "As little as 20 milliamperes",
            "Approximately 10 amperes",
            "More than 20 amperes",
            "Current flow through the human body is never fatal"
        ],
        "question": "How little electrical current flowing through the human body can be fatal?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The heart",
        "id": "B-003-018-006",
        "options": [
            "The heart",
            "The brain",
            "The liver",
            "The lungs"
        ],
        "question": "Which body organ can be fatally affected by a very small amount of electrical current?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "30 volts",
        "id": "B-003-018-007",
        "options": [
            "30 volts",
            "100 volts",
            "1000 volts",
            "2000 volts"
        ],
        "question": "What is the minimum voltage which is usually dangerous to humans?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Turn off the power, call for emergency help and provide first-aid if needed",
        "id": "B-003-018-008",
        "options": [
            "Turn off the power, call for emergency help and provide first-aid if needed",
            "Wait for a few minutes to see if the person can get away from the high voltage on their own, then try to help",
            "Immediately drag the person away from the high voltage",
            "Run from the area so you won't be burned too"
        ],
        "question": "What should you do if you discover someone who is being burned by high voltage?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Turn off the high voltage switch before removing the person from contact with the source",
        "id": "B-003-018-009",
        "options": [
            "Turn off the high voltage switch before removing the person from contact with the source",
            "Wrap the person in a blanket and pull him to a safe area",
            "Call an electrician",
            "Remove the person by pulling an arm or a leg"
        ],
        "question": "What is the safest method to remove an unconscious person from contact with a high voltage source?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "turn off the power and remove power plug",
        "id": "B-003-018-010",
        "options": [
            "turn off the power and remove power plug",
            "short out leads of filter capacitor",
            "check action of capacitor bleeder resistance",
            "remove and check fuse from power supply"
        ],
        "question": "Before checking a fault in a mains operated power supply unit, it would be safest to first:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "electric shock",
        "id": "B-003-018-011",
        "options": [
            "electric shock",
            "damaging the transmitter",
            "overmodulation",
            "blowing the fuse"
        ],
        "question": "Fault finding in a power supply of an amateur transmitter while the supply is operating is not a recommended technique because of the risk of:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "All station equipment",
        "id": "B-003-019-001",
        "options": [
            "All station equipment",
            "The antenna transmission line",
            "The AC power line",
            "The power supply primary"
        ],
        "question": "For best protection from electrical shock, what should be grounded in an amateur station?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "a metallic cold water pipe",
        "id": "B-003-019-002",
        "options": [
            "a metallic cold water pipe",
            "a plastic cold water pipe",
            "a window screen",
            "a metallic natural gas pipe"
        ],
        "question": "If a separate ground system is not possible for your amateur station, an alternative indoor grounding point could be:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "a good ground connection",
        "id": "B-003-019-003",
        "options": [
            "a good ground connection",
            "a dummy load",
            "insulated shock mounts",
            "the antenna"
        ],
        "question": "To protect you against electrical shock, the chassis of each piece of your station equipment should be connected to:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Copper-clad steel",
        "id": "B-003-019-004",
        "options": [
            "Copper-clad steel",
            "Hard plastic",
            "Iron or steel",
            "Fiberglass"
        ],
        "question": "Which of these materials is best for a ground rod driven into the earth?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The station ground system must conform to applicable electrical code requirements",
        "id": "B-003-019-005",
        "options": [
            "The station ground system must conform to applicable electrical code requirements",
            "1.2 metre (4 ft)",
            "2.5 metres (8 ft)",
            "3 metres (10 ft)"
        ],
        "question": "If you ground your station equipment to a ground rod driven into the earth, what is the shortest length the rod should be?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "To the chassis",
        "id": "B-003-019-006",
        "options": [
            "To the chassis",
            "To the white wire",
            "To the \"hot\" side of the power switch",
            "To the fuse"
        ],
        "question": "Where should the green wire in a three-wire AC line cord be connected in a power supply?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Because the ground wire has significant reactance and acts more like an antenna than an RF ground connection",
        "id": "B-003-019-007",
        "options": [
            "Because the ground wire has significant reactance and acts more like an antenna than an RF ground connection",
            "Because of a bad antenna connection, allowing the RF energy to take an easier path out of the transceiver through you",
            "Because the transceiver's heat-sensing circuit is not working to start the cooling fan",
            "Because the ground rod is not making good contact with moist earth"
        ],
        "question": "If your third-floor amateur station has a ground wire running 10 metres (33 feet) down to a ground rod, why might you get an RF burn if you touch the front panel of your HF transceiver?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Keep the station's ground wire as short as possible",
        "id": "B-003-019-008",
        "options": [
            "Keep the station's ground wire as short as possible",
            "Make a couple of loops in the ground wire where it connects to your station",
            "Drive the ground rod at least 4m (14 feet) into the ground",
            "Use a beryllium ground wire for best conductivity"
        ],
        "question": "What is one good way to avoid stray RF energy in your amateur station?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "RF hot spots can occur in a station located above the ground floor if the equipment is grounded by a long ground wire",
        "id": "B-003-019-009",
        "options": [
            "RF hot spots can occur in a station located above the ground floor if the equipment is grounded by a long ground wire",
            "A ground loop is an effective way to ground station equipment",
            "If the chassis of all station equipment is connected with a good conductor, there is no need to tie them to an earth ground",
            "The chassis of each piece of station equipment should be tied together with high-impedance conductors"
        ],
        "question": "Which statement about station grounding is true?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "does not develop a high voltage with respect to the ground",
        "id": "B-003-019-010",
        "options": [
            "does not develop a high voltage with respect to the ground",
            "does not become conductive to prevent electric shock",
            "becomes conductive to prevent electric shock",
            "develops a high voltage compared to the ground"
        ],
        "question": "On mains operated power supplies, the ground wire should be connected to the metal chassis of the power supply. This ensures, in case there is a fault in the power supply, that the chassis:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "prevent the chassis from becoming live",
        "id": "B-003-019-011",
        "options": [
            "prevent the chassis from becoming live",
            "prevent the plug from being reversed in the wall outlet",
            "prevent internal short circuits",
            "make it inconvenient to use"
        ],
        "question": "The purpose of using a three-wire power cord and plug on amateur radio equipment is to:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "To help protect the station equipment and building from lightning damage",
        "id": "B-003-020-001",
        "options": [
            "To help protect the station equipment and building from lightning damage",
            "To lock the antenna system in one position",
            "To avoid radio frequency interference",
            "To make sure everything will stay in place"
        ],
        "question": "Why should you ground all antenna and rotator cables when your amateur station is not in use?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Outside, as close to earth grounding as possible",
        "id": "B-003-020-002",
        "options": [
            "Outside, as close to earth grounding as possible",
            "Close to the antenna",
            "Behind the transceiver",
            "Anywhere on the line"
        ],
        "question": "You want to install a lightning arrestor on your antenna transmission line, where should it be inserted?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Disconnect all equipment from the power lines and antenna cables",
        "id": "B-003-020-003",
        "options": [
            "Disconnect all equipment from the power lines and antenna cables",
            "Use heavy insulation on the wiring",
            "Never turn off the equipment",
            "Disconnect the ground system from all radios"
        ],
        "question": "How can amateur station equipment best be protected from lightning damage?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Approved equipment in accordance with applicable standards concerning fall protection",
        "id": "B-003-020-004",
        "options": [
            "Approved equipment in accordance with applicable standards concerning fall protection",
            "A reflective vest of approved colour",
            "A flashing red, yellow or white light",
            "A grounding chain"
        ],
        "question": "What equipment should be worn for working on an antenna tower?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "To prevent you from accidentally falling",
        "id": "B-003-020-005",
        "options": [
            "To prevent you from accidentally falling",
            "To safely bring any tools you might use up and down the tower",
            "To keep the tower from becoming unbalanced while you are working",
            "To safely hold your tools so they don't fall and injure someone on the ground"
        ],
        "question": "Why should you wear approved fall arrest equipment if you are working on an antenna tower?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "High enough so that no one can touch any part of it from the ground",
        "id": "B-003-020-006",
        "options": [
            "High enough so that no one can touch any part of it from the ground",
            "Above high-voltage electrical lines",
            "Just high enough so you can easily reach it for adjustments or repairs",
            "As close to the ground as possible"
        ],
        "question": "For safety, how high should you place a horizontal wire antenna?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "To protect your head from something dropped from the tower",
        "id": "B-003-020-007",
        "options": [
            "To protect your head from something dropped from the tower",
            "So you won't be hurt if the tower should accidentally fall",
            "To keep RF energy away from your head during antenna testing",
            "So someone passing by will know that work is being done on the tower and will stay away"
        ],
        "question": "Why should you wear a hard hat if you are on the ground helping someone work on an antenna tower?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Touching the antenna might cause RF burns",
        "id": "B-003-020-008",
        "options": [
            "Touching the antenna might cause RF burns",
            "Touching the antenna might reflect the signal back to the transmitter and cause damage",
            "Touching the antenna might radiate harmonics",
            "Touching the antenna might cause television interference"
        ],
        "question": "Why should your outside antennas be high enough so that no one can touch them while you are transmitting?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Because high-voltage radio energy might burn the person",
        "id": "B-003-020-009",
        "options": [
            "Because high-voltage radio energy might burn the person",
            "Because contact might break the transmission line",
            "Because contact might cause spurious emissions",
            "Because contact might cause a short circuit and damage the transmitter"
        ],
        "question": "Why should you make sure that no one can touch an open wire transmission line while you are transmitting with it?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Be sure to turn off the transmitter and disconnect the transmission line",
        "id": "B-003-020-010",
        "options": [
            "Be sure to turn off the transmitter and disconnect the transmission line",
            "Be sure you and the antenna structure are grounded",
            "Inform your neighbours so they are aware of your intentions",
            "Turn off the main power switch in your house"
        ],
        "question": "What safety precautions should you take before beginning repairs on an antenna?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It should be installed so no one can come in contact with it",
        "id": "B-003-020-011",
        "options": [
            "It should be installed so no one can come in contact with it",
            "It should be painted so people or animals do not accidentally run into it",
            "It should not be installed in a wet area",
            "It should not be installed higher than you can reach"
        ],
        "question": "What precaution should you take when installing a ground-mounted antenna?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Keep antenna away from your eyes when RF is applied",
        "id": "B-003-021-001",
        "options": [
            "Keep antenna away from your eyes when RF is applied",
            "Make sure that an RF leakage filter is installed at the antenna feed point",
            "Make sure the standing wave ratio is low before you conduct a test",
            "Never use a horizontally polarized antenna"
        ],
        "question": "What should you do for safety when operating at UHF and microwave frequencies?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Make sure the antenna will be in a place where no one can get near it when you are transmitting",
        "id": "B-003-021-002",
        "options": [
            "Make sure the antenna will be in a place where no one can get near it when you are transmitting",
            "Make sure the antenna is near the ground to keep its RF energy pointing in the correct direction",
            "Make sure you connect an RF leakage filter at the antenna feed point",
            "Make sure that RF field screens are in place"
        ],
        "question": "What should you do for safety if you put up a UHF transmitting antenna?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Make sure the amplifier cannot accidentally be turned on",
        "id": "B-003-021-003",
        "options": [
            "Make sure the amplifier cannot accidentally be turned on",
            "Make sure that RF leakage filters are connected",
            "Make sure the antenna transmission line is properly grounded",
            "Make sure all RF screens are in place at the antenna transmission line"
        ],
        "question": "What should you do for safety, before removing the shielding on a UHF power amplifier?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "To reduce your exposure to the radio-frequency energy",
        "id": "B-003-021-004",
        "options": [
            "To reduce your exposure to the radio-frequency energy",
            "To use your body to reflect the signal in one direction",
            "To keep static charges from building up",
            "To help the antenna radiate energy equally in all directions"
        ],
        "question": "Why should you make sure the antenna of a hand-held transceiver is not close to your head when transmitting?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Away from your head and away from others",
        "id": "B-003-021-005",
        "options": [
            "Away from your head and away from others",
            "Pointed towards the station you are contacting",
            "Pointed away from the station you are contacting",
            "Pointed down to bounce the signal off the ground"
        ],
        "question": "How should you position the antenna of a hand-held transceiver while you are transmitting?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It heats the tissue",
        "id": "B-003-021-006",
        "options": [
            "It heats the tissue",
            "It lowers blood pressure",
            "It paralyzes the tissue",
            "It causes hair to fall out"
        ],
        "question": "How can exposure to a large amount of RF energy affect body tissue?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Eyes",
        "id": "B-003-021-007",
        "options": [
            "Eyes",
            "Heart",
            "Liver",
            "Hands"
        ],
        "question": "Which body organ is the most likely to be damaged from the heating effects of RF radiation?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It heats the tissue",
        "id": "B-003-021-008",
        "options": [
            "It heats the tissue",
            "It causes ionizing radiation poisoning",
            "It causes blood flow to stop",
            "It has no effect on the body"
        ],
        "question": "Depending on the wavelength of the signal, the energy density of the RF field, and other factors, in what way can RF energy affect body tissue?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Locate the antennas as far away as possible from living spaces that will be occupied while you are operating",
        "id": "B-003-021-009",
        "options": [
            "Locate the antennas as far away as possible from living spaces that will be occupied while you are operating",
            "Position the antennas parallel to electrical power wires to take advantage of parasitic effects",
            "Position the antennas along the edge of a wall where it meets the floor or ceiling to reduce parasitic radiation",
            "Locate the antennas close to your operating position to minimize transmission line length"
        ],
        "question": "If you operate your amateur station with indoor antennas, what precautions should you take when you install them?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "So they will not direct RF energy toward people in nearby structures",
        "id": "B-003-021-010",
        "options": [
            "So they will not direct RF energy toward people in nearby structures",
            "So they will be dried by the wind after a heavy rain storm",
            "So they will not damage nearby structures with RF energy",
            "So they will receive more sky waves and fewer ground waves"
        ],
        "question": "Why should directional high-gain antennas be mounted higher than nearby structures?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "As high as possible to prevent people from coming in contact with the antenna",
        "id": "B-003-021-011",
        "options": [
            "As high as possible to prevent people from coming in contact with the antenna",
            "Near or over moist ground so RF energy will be radiated away from the ground",
            "As close to the transmitter as possible so RF energy will be concentrated near the transmitter",
            "Close to the ground so simple adjustments can be easily made without climbing a ladder"
        ],
        "question": "For best RF safety, where should the ends and center of a dipole antenna be located?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "an amplifier",
        "id": "B-004-001-001",
        "options": [
            "an amplifier",
            "a modulator",
            "an oscillator",
            "a receiver"
        ],
        "question": "A circuit designed to increase the level of its input signal is called:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "become distorted",
        "id": "B-004-001-002",
        "options": [
            "become distorted",
            "be saturated",
            "cause oscillations",
            "overload the power supply"
        ],
        "question": "If an amplifier becomes non-linear, the output signal would:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "an RF amplifier",
        "id": "B-004-001-003",
        "options": [
            "an RF amplifier",
            "an RF oscillator",
            "an audio oscillator",
            "an audio amplifier"
        ],
        "question": "To increase the level of very weak radio signals from an antenna, you would use:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "an audio amplifier",
        "id": "B-004-001-004",
        "options": [
            "an audio amplifier",
            "an RF oscillator",
            "an RF amplifier",
            "an audio oscillator"
        ],
        "question": "To increase the level of very weak signals from a microphone you would use:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "300 to 3000 Hz",
        "id": "B-004-001-005",
        "options": [
            "300 to 3000 Hz",
            "3 to 300 Hz",
            "300 to 1000 Hz",
            "40 to 40 000 Hz"
        ],
        "question": "The range of frequencies to be amplified by a speech amplifier is typically:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Resistance",
        "id": "B-004-001-006",
        "options": [
            "Resistance",
            "Current",
            "Power",
            "Voltage"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following is not amplified by an amplifier?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "gain",
        "id": "B-004-001-007",
        "options": [
            "gain",
            "attenuation",
            "amplitude",
            "modulation"
        ],
        "question": "The increase in signal level by an amplifier is called:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "amplification",
        "id": "B-004-001-008",
        "options": [
            "amplification",
            "attenuation",
            "oscillation",
            "modulation"
        ],
        "question": "A device with gain has the property of:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "amplifier",
        "id": "B-004-001-009",
        "options": [
            "amplifier",
            "attenuator",
            "oscillator",
            "audio fader"
        ],
        "question": "A device labelled \"Gain = 10 dB\" is likely to be an:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "voltage, current, or power",
        "id": "B-004-001-010",
        "options": [
            "voltage, current, or power",
            "current, power, or inductance",
            "voltage, power, or inductance",
            "voltage, current, or inductance"
        ],
        "question": "Amplifiers can amplify:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Loss",
        "id": "B-004-001-011",
        "options": [
            "Loss",
            "Gain",
            "Linearity",
            "Distortion"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following is not a property of an amplifier?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "voltage regulators",
        "id": "B-004-002-001",
        "options": [
            "voltage regulators",
            "current regulators",
            "RF detectors",
            "AF detectors"
        ],
        "question": "Zener diodes are used as:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "demodulation",
        "id": "B-004-002-002",
        "options": [
            "demodulation",
            "regeneration",
            "ionization",
            "biasing"
        ],
        "question": "One important application for diodes is recovering information from transmitted signals. This is referred to as:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "regulate or maintain a constant voltage",
        "id": "B-004-002-003",
        "options": [
            "regulate or maintain a constant voltage",
            "provide a voltage phase shift",
            "to boost the power supply voltage",
            "provide a path through which current can flow"
        ],
        "question": "The primary purpose of a Zener diode is to:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "rectification",
        "id": "B-004-002-004",
        "options": [
            "rectification",
            "amplification",
            "transformation",
            "modulation"
        ],
        "question": "The action of changing alternating current to direct current is called:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "anode and cathode",
        "id": "B-004-002-005",
        "options": [
            "anode and cathode",
            "gate and source",
            "collector and base",
            "cathode and drain"
        ],
        "question": "The electrodes of a semiconductor diode are known as:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Pulsating direct current",
        "id": "B-004-002-006",
        "options": [
            "Pulsating direct current",
            "No signal",
            "Steady direct current",
            "Pulsating alternating current"
        ],
        "question": "If alternating current is applied to the anode of a diode, what would you expect to see at the cathode?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "cathode to anode",
        "id": "B-004-002-007",
        "options": [
            "cathode to anode",
            "anode to cathode",
            "cathode to grid",
            "grid to anode"
        ],
        "question": "In a semiconductor diode, electrons flow from:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A light-emitting diode",
        "id": "B-004-002-008",
        "options": [
            "A light-emitting diode",
            "A fluorescent bulb",
            "A neon bulb",
            "A vacuum diode"
        ],
        "question": "What semiconductor device glows different colours, depending upon its chemical composition?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Zener diode",
        "id": "B-004-002-009",
        "options": [
            "Zener diode",
            "junction diode",
            "light-emitting diode",
            "vacuum diode"
        ],
        "question": "Voltage regulation is the principal application of the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "forward-biased",
        "id": "B-004-002-010",
        "options": [
            "forward-biased",
            "close coupled",
            "enhanced",
            "reverse-biased"
        ],
        "question": "In order for a diode to conduct, it must be:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A PNP transistor",
        "id": "B-004-003-001",
        "options": [
            "A PNP transistor",
            "A variable resistor",
            "An electrolytic capacitor",
            "A multiple-cell battery"
        ],
        "question": "Which component can amplify a small signal using low voltages?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "transistor",
        "id": "B-004-003-002",
        "options": [
            "transistor",
            "tube",
            "P-N junction",
            "diode"
        ],
        "question": "The basic semiconductor amplifying device is the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "collector, emitter and base",
        "id": "B-004-003-003",
        "options": [
            "collector, emitter and base",
            "drain, base and source",
            "collector, source and drain",
            "gate, source and drain"
        ],
        "question": "The three leads from a PNP transistor are named:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "amplification",
        "id": "B-004-003-004",
        "options": [
            "amplification",
            "detection",
            "modulation",
            "rectification"
        ],
        "question": "If a low level signal is placed at the input to a transistor, a higher level of signal is produced at the output lead. This effect is known as:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "3 leads",
        "id": "B-004-003-005",
        "options": [
            "3 leads",
            "1 lead",
            "2 leads",
            "4 leads"
        ],
        "question": "Bipolar transistors usually have:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "a bipolar transistor",
        "id": "B-004-003-006",
        "options": [
            "a bipolar transistor",
            "a silicon diode",
            "a triode",
            "an audio detector"
        ],
        "question": "A semiconductor is described as a \"general purpose audio NPN device\". This would be:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "NPN and PNP types",
        "id": "B-004-003-007",
        "options": [
            "NPN and PNP types",
            "diode and triode types",
            "varicap and Zener types",
            "P and N channel types"
        ],
        "question": "The two basic types of bipolar transistors are:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "excessive heat",
        "id": "B-004-003-008",
        "options": [
            "excessive heat",
            "excessive light",
            "saturation",
            "cut-off"
        ],
        "question": "A transistor can be destroyed in a circuit by:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "base",
        "id": "B-004-003-009",
        "options": [
            "base",
            "emitter",
            "source",
            "collector"
        ],
        "question": "In a bipolar transistor, the _____________compares closest to the control grid of a triode vacuum tube."
    },
    {
        "answer": "collector",
        "id": "B-004-003-010",
        "options": [
            "collector",
            "gate",
            "emitter",
            "base"
        ],
        "question": "In a bipolar transistor, the _____________compares closest to the plate of a triode vacuum tube."
    },
    {
        "answer": "emitter",
        "id": "B-004-003-011",
        "options": [
            "emitter",
            "collector",
            "base",
            "drain"
        ],
        "question": "In a bipolar transistor, the _____________ compares closest to the cathode of a triode vacuum tube."
    },
    {
        "answer": "N and P channel",
        "id": "B-004-004-001",
        "options": [
            "N and P channel",
            "NPN and PNP",
            "germanium and silicon",
            "inductive and capacitive"
        ],
        "question": "The two basic types of field effect transistors (FET) are:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "field-effect transistor",
        "id": "B-004-004-002",
        "options": [
            "field-effect transistor",
            "gated transistor",
            "bipolar transistor",
            "silicon diode"
        ],
        "question": "A semiconductor having its leads labelled gate, drain, and source is best described as a:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "gate",
        "id": "B-004-004-003",
        "options": [
            "gate",
            "drain",
            "source",
            "collector"
        ],
        "question": "In a field effect transistor, the ___________ is the terminal that controls the conductance of the channel."
    },
    {
        "answer": "source",
        "id": "B-004-004-004",
        "options": [
            "source",
            "gate",
            "drain",
            "emitter"
        ],
        "question": "In a field effect transistor, the ___________is the terminal where the charge carriers enter the channel."
    },
    {
        "answer": "drain",
        "id": "B-004-004-005",
        "options": [
            "drain",
            "collector",
            "source",
            "gate"
        ],
        "question": "In a field effect transistor, the __________ is the terminal where the charge carriers leave the channel."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Field effect transistor",
        "id": "B-004-004-006",
        "options": [
            "Field effect transistor",
            "Junction diode",
            "Zener diode",
            "Bipolar transistor"
        ],
        "question": "Which semiconductor device has characteristics most similar to a triode vacuum tube?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "gate",
        "id": "B-004-004-007",
        "options": [
            "gate",
            "source",
            "drain",
            "base"
        ],
        "question": "The control element in the field effect transistor is the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "increase the reverse bias voltage",
        "id": "B-004-004-008",
        "options": [
            "increase the reverse bias voltage",
            "decrease the reverse bias voltage",
            "increase the forward bias voltage",
            "increase the forward bias gain"
        ],
        "question": "If you wish to reduce the current flowing in a field effect transistor, you could:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "emitter",
        "id": "B-004-004-009",
        "options": [
            "emitter",
            "base",
            "drain",
            "collector"
        ],
        "question": "The source of a field effect transistor corresponds to the _______ of a bipolar transistor."
    },
    {
        "answer": "collector",
        "id": "B-004-004-010",
        "options": [
            "collector",
            "base",
            "source",
            "emitter"
        ],
        "question": "The drain of a field effect transistor corresponds to the _______ of a bipolar transistor."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Source and drain",
        "id": "B-004-004-011",
        "options": [
            "Source and drain",
            "Source and gate",
            "Gate and drain",
            "Source and base"
        ],
        "question": "Which two elements in a field effect transistor exhibit fairly similar characteristics?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It may be able to handle higher power",
        "id": "B-004-005-001",
        "options": [
            "It may be able to handle higher power",
            "It uses less current",
            "It is much smaller",
            "It uses lower voltages"
        ],
        "question": "What is one reason a triode vacuum tube might be used instead of a transistor in a circuit?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A vacuum tube",
        "id": "B-004-005-002",
        "options": [
            "A vacuum tube",
            "A transistor",
            "An electrolytic capacitor",
            "A multiple-cell battery"
        ],
        "question": "Which component can amplify a small signal but must use high voltages?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "can amplify signals",
        "id": "B-004-005-003",
        "options": [
            "can amplify signals",
            "have electrons drifting through a vacuum",
            "convert electrical energy to radio waves",
            "use heat to cause electron movement"
        ],
        "question": "A feature common to triode tubes and transistors is that both:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "plate",
        "id": "B-004-005-004",
        "options": [
            "plate",
            "filament (heater)",
            "cathode",
            "grid"
        ],
        "question": "In a vacuum tube, the electrode that is operated with the highest positive potential is the _________."
    },
    {
        "answer": "grid",
        "id": "B-004-005-005",
        "options": [
            "grid",
            "filament (heater)",
            "cathode",
            "plate"
        ],
        "question": "In a vacuum tube, the electrode that is usually a cylinder of wire mesh is the _______."
    },
    {
        "answer": "filament (heater)",
        "id": "B-004-005-006",
        "options": [
            "filament (heater)",
            "grid",
            "emitter",
            "cathode"
        ],
        "question": "In a vacuum tube, the element that is furthest away from the plate is the __________."
    },
    {
        "answer": "cathode",
        "id": "B-004-005-007",
        "options": [
            "cathode",
            "grid",
            "collector",
            "plate"
        ],
        "question": "In a vacuum tube, the electrode that emits electrons is the __________."
    },
    {
        "answer": "A vacuum",
        "id": "B-004-005-008",
        "options": [
            "A vacuum",
            "Argon",
            "Air",
            "Neon"
        ],
        "question": "What is inside the envelope of a triode tube?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "One",
        "id": "B-004-005-009",
        "options": [
            "One",
            "Two",
            "Three",
            "Three plus a filament"
        ],
        "question": "How many grids are there in a triode vacuum tube?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "By reading the resistor's colour code",
        "id": "B-004-006-001",
        "options": [
            "By reading the resistor's colour code",
            "By using Thevenin's theorem for resistors",
            "By reading its Baudot code",
            "By using a voltmeter"
        ],
        "question": "How do you find a resistor's tolerance rating?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The value of the resistor in ohms",
        "id": "B-004-006-002",
        "options": [
            "The value of the resistor in ohms",
            "The resistance material",
            "The power rating in watts",
            "The resistance tolerance in percent"
        ],
        "question": "What do the first three-colour bands on a resistor indicate?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The resistance tolerance in percent",
        "id": "B-004-006-003",
        "options": [
            "The resistance tolerance in percent",
            "The value of the resistor in ohms",
            "The power rating in watts",
            "The resistance material"
        ],
        "question": "What would the fourth colour band on a 47 ohm resistor indicate?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "90 to 110 ohms",
        "id": "B-004-006-004",
        "options": [
            "90 to 110 ohms",
            "90 to 100 ohms",
            "10 to 100 ohms",
            "80 to 120 ohms"
        ],
        "question": "What are the possible values of a 100 ohm resistor with a 10% tolerance?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "By using the resistor's colour code",
        "id": "B-004-006-005",
        "options": [
            "By using the resistor's colour code",
            "By using a voltmeter",
            "By using Thevenin's theorem for resistors",
            "By using the Baudot code"
        ],
        "question": "How do you find a resistor's value?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "0.1%",
        "id": "B-004-006-006",
        "options": [
            "0.1%",
            "5%",
            "10%",
            "20%"
        ],
        "question": "A club project requires that a resistive voltage divider provide a very accurate and predictable ratio. Out of the list below, which resistor tolerance would you select?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "20%",
        "id": "B-004-006-007",
        "options": [
            "20%",
            "0.1%",
            "5%",
            "10%"
        ],
        "question": "You need a current limiting resistor for a light-emitting diode (LED). The actual resistance is not critical at all. Out of the list below, which resistor tolerance would you select?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It will change depending on the resistor's temperature coefficient rating",
        "id": "B-004-006-008",
        "options": [
            "It will change depending on the resistor's temperature coefficient rating",
            "It will stay the same",
            "It will become time dependent",
            "It will increase by 20% for every 10 degrees centigrade"
        ],
        "question": "If a carbon resistor's temperature is increased, what will happen to the resistance?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "5%",
        "id": "B-004-006-009",
        "options": [
            "5%",
            "20%",
            "10%",
            "1%"
        ],
        "question": "A gold tolerance band on a resistor indicates the tolerance is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Third band",
        "id": "B-004-006-010",
        "options": [
            "Third band",
            "First band",
            "Second band",
            "Fourth band"
        ],
        "question": "Which colour band would differentiate a 120-ohm from a 1200-ohm resistor?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "270 kilohms",
        "id": "B-004-006-011",
        "options": [
            "270 kilohms",
            "274 ohms",
            "72 kilohms",
            "27 megohms"
        ],
        "question": "Given that red=2, violet=7 and yellow=4, what is the nominal value of a resistor whose colour code reads \"red\", \"violet\" and \"yellow\"?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "3525 kHz",
        "id": "B-005-001-001",
        "options": [
            "3525 kHz",
            "35.25 kHz",
            "3 525 000 kHz",
            "0.003525 kHz"
        ],
        "question": "If a dial marked in megahertz shows a reading of 3.525 MHz, what would it show if it were marked in kilohertz?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "3 amperes",
        "id": "B-005-001-002",
        "options": [
            "3 amperes",
            "0.003 ampere",
            "0.3 ampere",
            "3 000 000 amperes"
        ],
        "question": "If an ammeter marked in amperes is used to measure a 3000 milliampere current, what reading would it show?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "3.5 volts",
        "id": "B-005-001-003",
        "options": [
            "3.5 volts",
            "0.35 volt",
            "35 volts",
            "350 volts"
        ],
        "question": "If a voltmeter marked in volts is used to measure a 3500 millivolt potential, what reading would it show?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "1 microfarad",
        "id": "B-005-001-004",
        "options": [
            "1 microfarad",
            "1 000 000 000 microfarads",
            "1000 microfarads",
            "0.001 microfarad"
        ],
        "question": "How many microfarads is 1 000 000 picofarads?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "0.5",
        "id": "B-005-001-005",
        "options": [
            "0.5",
            "5",
            "50",
            "0.02"
        ],
        "question": "If you have a hand-held transceiver which puts out 500 milliwatts, how many watts would this be?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "1000 ohms",
        "id": "B-005-001-006",
        "options": [
            "1000 ohms",
            "0.1 ohm",
            "0.001 ohm",
            "10 ohms"
        ],
        "question": "A kilohm is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "6600 volts",
        "id": "B-005-001-007",
        "options": [
            "6600 volts",
            "660 volts",
            "66 volts",
            "66 000 volts"
        ],
        "question": "6.6 kilovolts is equal to:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "250 milliamperes",
        "id": "B-005-001-008",
        "options": [
            "250 milliamperes",
            "0.5 amperes",
            "0.25 milliampere",
            "250 microamperes"
        ],
        "question": "A current of one quarter ampere may be written as:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "2 000",
        "id": "B-005-001-009",
        "options": [
            "2 000",
            "0.000002",
            "2 000 000",
            "0.002"
        ],
        "question": "How many millivolts are equivalent to two volts?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "1 000 kHz",
        "id": "B-005-001-010",
        "options": [
            "1 000 kHz",
            "100 kHz",
            "0.001 Hz",
            "10 Hz"
        ],
        "question": "One megahertz is equal to:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "10 millihenrys",
        "id": "B-005-001-011",
        "options": [
            "10 millihenrys",
            "100 millihenrys",
            "10 henrys",
            "1 000 henrys"
        ],
        "question": "An inductance of 10 000 microhenrys may be stated correctly as:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Gold, silver, aluminum",
        "id": "B-005-002-001",
        "options": [
            "Gold, silver, aluminum",
            "Gold, silver, wood",
            "Copper, aluminum, paper",
            "Copper, gold, mica"
        ],
        "question": "Name three good electrical conductors."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Glass, air, plastic, porcelain",
        "id": "B-005-002-002",
        "options": [
            "Glass, air, plastic, porcelain",
            "Plastic, rubber, wood, carbon",
            "Paper, glass, air, aluminum",
            "Glass, wood, copper, porcelain"
        ],
        "question": "Name four good electrical insulators."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Some electrical energy passing through them is lost as heat",
        "id": "B-005-002-003",
        "options": [
            "Some electrical energy passing through them is lost as heat",
            "Their reactance makes them heat up",
            "Hotter circuit components nearby heat them up",
            "They absorb magnetic energy which makes them hot"
        ],
        "question": "Why do resistors sometimes get hot when in use?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "copper",
        "id": "B-005-002-004",
        "options": [
            "copper",
            "carbon",
            "silicon",
            "aluminium"
        ],
        "question": "What is the best conductor among the following materials?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "a conductor",
        "id": "B-005-002-005",
        "options": [
            "a conductor",
            "an insulator",
            "a semiconductor",
            "a dielectric"
        ],
        "question": "Which type of material listed will most readily allow an electric current to flow?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "low resistance",
        "id": "B-005-002-006",
        "options": [
            "low resistance",
            "high resistance",
            "high wattage",
            "low wattage"
        ],
        "question": "A length of metal is connected in a circuit and is found to conduct electricity very well. It would be best described as having a:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "resistance",
        "id": "B-005-002-007",
        "options": [
            "resistance",
            "impedance",
            "reluctance",
            "reactance"
        ],
        "question": "The letter \"R\" is the symbol for:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "conductance",
        "id": "B-005-002-008",
        "options": [
            "conductance",
            "reactance",
            "reluctance",
            "permeability"
        ],
        "question": "The reciprocal of resistance is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "the voltage developed across the terminals of a component",
        "id": "B-005-002-009",
        "options": [
            "the voltage developed across the terminals of a component",
            "any point in a radio circuit which has zero voltage",
            "the difference in voltage at output terminals of a transformer",
            "the voltage which is dissipated before useful work is accomplished"
        ],
        "question": "Voltage drop means:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "temperature",
        "id": "B-005-002-010",
        "options": [
            "temperature",
            "voltage",
            "current",
            "humidity"
        ],
        "question": "The resistance of a conductor changes with:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "carbon",
        "id": "B-005-002-011",
        "options": [
            "carbon",
            "gold",
            "mica",
            "lead"
        ],
        "question": "The most common material used to make a resistor is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Power",
        "id": "B-005-003-001",
        "options": [
            "Power",
            "Current",
            "Voltage",
            "Resistance"
        ],
        "question": "What is the word used to describe the rate at which electrical energy is used?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The 100 watt bulb",
        "id": "B-005-003-002",
        "options": [
            "The 100 watt bulb",
            "They will all be the same",
            "The 40 watt bulb",
            "The 60 watt bulb"
        ],
        "question": "If you have light bulbs marked 40 watts, 60 watts and 100 watts, which one will use electrical energy the fastest?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The watt",
        "id": "B-005-003-003",
        "options": [
            "The watt",
            "The ampere",
            "The volt",
            "The ohm"
        ],
        "question": "What is the basic unit of electrical power?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "An open circuit",
        "id": "B-005-003-004",
        "options": [
            "An open circuit",
            "A short circuit",
            "A complete circuit",
            "A closed circuit"
        ],
        "question": "Which electrical circuit will have no current?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A short circuit",
        "id": "B-005-003-005",
        "options": [
            "A short circuit",
            "A dead circuit",
            "A closed circuit",
            "An open circuit"
        ],
        "question": "Which electrical circuit draws too much current?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "watts",
        "id": "B-005-003-006",
        "options": [
            "watts",
            "volts",
            "amperes",
            "ohms"
        ],
        "question": "Power is expressed in:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Voltage and current",
        "id": "B-005-003-007",
        "options": [
            "Voltage and current",
            "Inductance and capacitance",
            "Voltage and inductance",
            "Resistance and capacitance"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following two quantities should be multiplied together to find power?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Volts and amperes",
        "id": "B-005-003-008",
        "options": [
            "Volts and amperes",
            "Volts and farads",
            "Farads and henrys",
            "Amperes and henrys"
        ],
        "question": "Which two electrical units multiplied together give the unit \"watts\"?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "power",
        "id": "B-005-003-009",
        "options": [
            "power",
            "voltage",
            "resistance",
            "current"
        ],
        "question": "A resistor in a circuit becomes very hot and starts to burn. This is because the resistor is dissipating too much:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "allowing heat to dissipate more readily",
        "id": "B-005-003-010",
        "options": [
            "allowing heat to dissipate more readily",
            "allowing higher voltage to be handled",
            "increasing the effective resistance of the resistor",
            "making it shock proof"
        ],
        "question": "High power resistors are usually large with heavy leads. The size aids the operation of the resistor by:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "20 watts",
        "id": "B-005-003-011",
        "options": [
            "20 watts",
            "100 ohms",
            "2 ohms",
            "0.5 watt"
        ],
        "question": "The resistor that could dissipate the most heat would be marked:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "100 volts",
        "id": "B-005-004-001",
        "options": [
            "100 volts",
            "48 volts",
            "52 volts",
            "25 volts"
        ],
        "question": "If a current of 2 amperes flows through a 50-ohm resistor, what is the voltage across the resistor?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Current equals voltage divided by resistance",
        "id": "B-005-004-002",
        "options": [
            "Current equals voltage divided by resistance",
            "Current equals resistance multiplied by voltage",
            "Current equals resistance divided by voltage",
            "Current equals power divided by voltage"
        ],
        "question": "How is the current in a DC circuit calculated when the voltage and resistance are known?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Resistance equals voltage divided by current",
        "id": "B-005-004-003",
        "options": [
            "Resistance equals voltage divided by current",
            "Resistance equals current multiplied by voltage",
            "Resistance equals power divided by voltage",
            "Resistance equals current divided by voltage"
        ],
        "question": "How is the resistance in a DC circuit calculated when the voltage and current are known?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Voltage equals current multiplied by resistance",
        "id": "B-005-004-004",
        "options": [
            "Voltage equals current multiplied by resistance",
            "Voltage equals current divided by resistance",
            "Voltage equals resistance divided by current",
            "Voltage equals power divided by current"
        ],
        "question": "How is the voltage in a DC circuit calculated when the current and resistance are known?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "48 ohms",
        "id": "B-005-004-005",
        "options": [
            "48 ohms",
            "3 ohms",
            "12 ohms",
            "0.25 ohm"
        ],
        "question": "If a 12-volt battery supplies 0.25 ampere to a circuit, what is the circuit's resistance?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "125 kilohms",
        "id": "B-005-004-006",
        "options": [
            "125 kilohms",
            "125 ohms",
            "1250 ohms",
            "1.25 kilohms"
        ],
        "question": "Calculate the value of resistance necessary to drop 100 volts with current flow of 0.8 milliamperes:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "220 volts",
        "id": "B-005-004-007",
        "options": [
            "220 volts",
            "2220 volts",
            "22.0 volts",
            "0.220 volt"
        ],
        "question": "The voltage required to force a current of 4.4 amperes through a resistance of 50 ohms is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "0.2 ampere",
        "id": "B-005-004-008",
        "options": [
            "0.2 ampere",
            "2 amperes",
            "0.5 ampere",
            "0.005 ampere"
        ],
        "question": "A lamp has a resistance of 30 ohms and a 6 volt battery is connected. The current flow will be:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "5 volts",
        "id": "B-005-004-009",
        "options": [
            "5 volts",
            "8 volts",
            "175 volts",
            "225 volts"
        ],
        "question": "What voltage would be needed to supply a current of 200 milliamperes, to operate an electric lamp which has a resistance of 25 ohms?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "R = E/I",
        "id": "B-005-004-010",
        "options": [
            "R = E/I",
            "R = I/E",
            "R = E/R",
            "R = E x I"
        ],
        "question": "The resistance of a circuit can be found by using one of the following:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "10 ohms",
        "id": "B-005-004-011",
        "options": [
            "10 ohms",
            "9 ohms",
            "5 ohms",
            "3 ohms"
        ],
        "question": "If a 3 volt battery supplies 300 milliamperes to a circuit, the circuit resistance is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It equals the sum of the branch current through each resistor",
        "id": "B-005-005-001",
        "options": [
            "It equals the sum of the branch current through each resistor",
            "It equals the average of the branch current through each resistor",
            "It decreases as more parallel resistors are added to the circuit",
            "It is the sum of each resistor's voltage drop multiplied by the total number of resistors"
        ],
        "question": "In a parallel circuit with a voltage source and several branch resistors, how is the total current related to the current in the branch resistors?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The current through the 10 ohms, 15 ohms and 20 ohms separate resistances, when added together, equals the total current drawn from the battery",
        "id": "B-005-005-002",
        "options": [
            "The current through the 10 ohms, 15 ohms and 20 ohms separate resistances, when added together, equals the total current drawn from the battery",
            "The current flowing through the 10 ohm resistance is less than that flowing through the 20 ohm resistance",
            "The voltage drop across each resistance added together equals 6 volts",
            "The voltage drop across the 20 ohm resistance is greater than the voltage across the 10 ohm resistance"
        ],
        "question": "Three resistors, respectively rated at 10, 15 and 20 ohms are connected in parallel across a 6-volt battery. Which statement is true?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "is always less than the smallest resistance",
        "id": "B-005-005-003",
        "options": [
            "is always less than the smallest resistance",
            "depends upon the voltage drop across each branch",
            "could be equal to the resistance of one branch",
            "depends upon the applied voltage"
        ],
        "question": "Total resistance in a parallel circuit:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "80 milliamperes",
        "id": "B-005-005-004",
        "options": [
            "80 milliamperes",
            "40 milliamperes",
            "80 amperes",
            "40 amperes"
        ],
        "question": "Two resistors are connected in parallel and are connected across a 40 volt battery. If each resistor is 1000 ohms, the total current is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "greater than the resistance of any one resistor",
        "id": "B-005-005-005",
        "options": [
            "greater than the resistance of any one resistor",
            "less than the resistance of any one resistor",
            "equal to the highest resistance present",
            "equal to the lowest resistance present"
        ],
        "question": "The total resistance of resistors connected in series is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "50 ohms",
        "id": "B-005-005-006",
        "options": [
            "50 ohms",
            "5 ohms",
            "10 ohms",
            "1 ohm"
        ],
        "question": "Five 10 ohm resistors connected in series equals:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Five 24 ohm",
        "id": "B-005-005-007",
        "options": [
            "Five 24 ohm",
            "Six 22 ohm",
            "Two 62 ohm",
            "Five 100 ohm"
        ],
        "question": "Which series combination of resistors would replace a single 120 ohm resistor?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "R / 10",
        "id": "B-005-005-008",
        "options": [
            "R / 10",
            "10 / R",
            "10 x R",
            "10 + R"
        ],
        "question": "If ten resistors of equal value were wired in parallel, the total resistance would be:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "17 ohms",
        "id": "B-005-005-009",
        "options": [
            "17 ohms",
            "12 ohms",
            "34 ohms",
            "272 ohms"
        ],
        "question": "The total resistance of four 68 ohm resistors wired in parallel is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A has half the resistance of B",
        "id": "B-005-005-010",
        "options": [
            "A has half the resistance of B",
            "the voltage across B is twice that across A",
            "the voltage across A is twice that across B",
            "B has half the resistance of A"
        ],
        "question": "Two resistors are in parallel. Resistor A carries twice the current of resistor B, which means that:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "sum of the currents through all the parallel branches",
        "id": "B-005-005-011",
        "options": [
            "sum of the currents through all the parallel branches",
            "source voltage divided by the value of one of the resistive elements",
            "source voltage divided by the sum of the resistive elements",
            "current in any one of the parallel branches"
        ],
        "question": "The total current in a parallel circuit is equal to the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "For greater power dissipation",
        "id": "B-005-006-001",
        "options": [
            "For greater power dissipation",
            "For better response time",
            "For a higher current gain",
            "For less impedance in the circuit"
        ],
        "question": "Why would a large size resistor be used instead of a smaller one of the same resistance?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "2.4 watts",
        "id": "B-005-006-002",
        "options": [
            "2.4 watts",
            "60 watts",
            "24 watts",
            "6 watts"
        ],
        "question": "How many watts of electrical power are used by a 12 volt DC light bulb that draws 0.2 ampere?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "6 watts",
        "id": "B-005-006-003",
        "options": [
            "6 watts",
            "20 watts",
            "500 watts",
            "12 watts"
        ],
        "question": "The DC input power of a transmitter operating at 12 volts and drawing 500 milliamperes would be:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "2 watts",
        "id": "B-005-006-004",
        "options": [
            "2 watts",
            "1 watt",
            "1/2 watt",
            "4 watts"
        ],
        "question": "When two 500 ohm 1 watt resistors are connected in series, the maximum total power that can be dissipated by the resistors is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "2 watts",
        "id": "B-005-006-005",
        "options": [
            "2 watts",
            "1/2 watt",
            "1 watt",
            "4 watts"
        ],
        "question": "When two 500 ohm 1 watt resistors are connected in parallel, they can dissipate a maximum total power of:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Increase four times",
        "id": "B-005-006-006",
        "options": [
            "Increase four times",
            "Decrease to half",
            "Double",
            "No change"
        ],
        "question": "If the voltage applied to two resistors in series is doubled, how much will the total power change?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Four 2-watt 200 ohms resistors in parallel",
        "id": "B-005-006-007",
        "options": [
            "Four 2-watt 200 ohms resistors in parallel",
            "Two 5-watt 100 ohms resistors in series",
            "Two 2-watt 25 ohms resistors in series",
            "Ten quarter-watt 500 ohms resistors in parallel"
        ],
        "question": "Which combination of resistors could make up a 50 ohms dummy load capable of safely dissipating 5 watts?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "30/12 amperes",
        "id": "B-005-006-008",
        "options": [
            "30/12 amperes",
            "18 amperes",
            "360 amperes",
            "12/30 amperes"
        ],
        "question": "A 12 volt light bulb is rated at a power of 30 watts. The current drawn would be:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "5 watts",
        "id": "B-005-006-009",
        "options": [
            "5 watts",
            "10 watts",
            "20 watts",
            "100 watts"
        ],
        "question": "If two 10 ohm resistors are connected in series with a 10 volt battery, the power consumption would be:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "the same resistance but greater power rating",
        "id": "B-005-006-010",
        "options": [
            "the same resistance but greater power rating",
            "the same resistance but lesser power rating",
            "greater resistance and similar power rating",
            "lesser resistance and similar power rating"
        ],
        "question": "One advantage of replacing a 50 ohm resistor with a parallel combination of two similarly rated 100 ohm resistors is that the parallel combination will have:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "determined by heat dissipation qualities",
        "id": "B-005-006-011",
        "options": [
            "determined by heat dissipation qualities",
            "calculated according to physical size and tolerance rating",
            "expressed in joules",
            "variable in steps of one hundred"
        ],
        "question": "Resistor wattage ratings are:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Frequency",
        "id": "B-005-007-001",
        "options": [
            "Frequency",
            "Speed",
            "Pulse rate",
            "Inductance"
        ],
        "question": "What term means the number of times per second that an alternating current flows back and forth?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "20 - 20 000 Hz",
        "id": "B-005-007-002",
        "options": [
            "20 - 20 000 Hz",
            "20 000 - 30 000 Hz",
            "200 - 200 000 Hz",
            "0 - 20 Hz"
        ],
        "question": "Approximately what frequency range can most humans hear?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Because the human ear can sense sounds in this range",
        "id": "B-005-007-003",
        "options": [
            "Because the human ear can sense sounds in this range",
            "Because the human ear cannot sense anything in this range",
            "Because this range is too low for radio energy",
            "Because the human ear can sense radio waves in this range"
        ],
        "question": "Why do we call signals in the range 20 Hz to 20 000 Hz audio frequencies?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Radio",
        "id": "B-005-007-004",
        "options": [
            "Radio",
            "Audio",
            "Hyper",
            "Super-high"
        ],
        "question": "Electrical energy at a frequency of 7125 kHz is in what frequency range?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Wavelength",
        "id": "B-005-007-005",
        "options": [
            "Wavelength",
            "Wave speed",
            "Waveform",
            "Wave spread"
        ],
        "question": "What is the name for the distance an AC signal travels during one complete cycle?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It gets shorter",
        "id": "B-005-007-006",
        "options": [
            "It gets shorter",
            "It gets longer",
            "It stays the same",
            "It disappears"
        ],
        "question": "What happens to a signal's wavelength as its frequency increases?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It goes down",
        "id": "B-005-007-007",
        "options": [
            "It goes down",
            "It disappears",
            "It stays the same",
            "It goes up"
        ],
        "question": "What happens to a signal's frequency as its wavelength gets longer?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "60 cycles per second",
        "id": "B-005-007-008",
        "options": [
            "60 cycles per second",
            "6000 metres per second",
            "60 metres per second",
            "6000 cycles per second"
        ],
        "question": "What does 60 hertz (Hz) mean?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "0.01 second",
        "id": "B-005-007-009",
        "options": [
            "0.01 second",
            "10 seconds",
            "0.0001 second",
            "1 second"
        ],
        "question": "If the frequency of the waveform is 100 Hz, the time for one cycle is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "10 Hz",
        "id": "B-005-007-010",
        "options": [
            "10 Hz",
            "1 Hz",
            "100 Hz",
            "1000 Hz"
        ],
        "question": "Current in an AC circuit goes through a complete cycle in 0.1 second. This means the AC has a frequency of:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "a harmonic of the 2 kHz signal",
        "id": "B-005-007-011",
        "options": [
            "a harmonic of the 2 kHz signal",
            "a fundamental of the 2 kHz signal",
            "the DC component of the main signal",
            "a dielectric signal of the main signal"
        ],
        "question": "A signal is composed of a fundamental frequency of 2 kHz and another of 4 kHz. This 4 kHz signal is referred to as:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "3 dB higher",
        "id": "B-005-008-001",
        "options": [
            "3 dB higher",
            "6 dB higher",
            "12 dB higher",
            "1 dB higher"
        ],
        "question": "A two-times increase in power results in a change of how many dB?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Divide the original power by 2",
        "id": "B-005-008-002",
        "options": [
            "Divide the original power by 2",
            "Divide the original power by 1.5",
            "Divide the original power by 3",
            "Divide the original power by 4"
        ],
        "question": "How can you decrease your transmitter's power by 3 dB?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Multiply the original power by 4",
        "id": "B-005-008-003",
        "options": [
            "Multiply the original power by 4",
            "Multiply the original power by 3",
            "Multiply the original power by 2",
            "Multiply the original power by 1.5"
        ],
        "question": "How can you increase your transmitter's power by 6 dB?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "S9",
        "id": "B-005-008-004",
        "options": [
            "S9",
            "S9 plus 3 dB",
            "S9 minus 10 dB",
            "S9 plus 5 dB"
        ],
        "question": "If a signal-strength report is \"10 dB over S9\", what should the report be if the transmitter power is reduced from 1500 watts to 150 watts?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "S9 plus 10 dB",
        "id": "B-005-008-005",
        "options": [
            "S9 plus 10 dB",
            "S9 plus 5 dB",
            "S9 plus 3 dB",
            "S9"
        ],
        "question": "If a signal-strength report is \"20 dB over S9\", what should the report be if the transmitter power is reduced from 1500 watts to 150 watts?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "a mathematical ratio",
        "id": "B-005-008-006",
        "options": [
            "a mathematical ratio",
            "an oscilloscope wave form",
            "certain radio waves",
            "a single side band signal"
        ],
        "question": "The unit \"decibel\" is used to indicate:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "3",
        "id": "B-005-008-007",
        "options": [
            "3",
            "30",
            "6",
            "1"
        ],
        "question": "The power output from a transmitter increases from 1 watt to 2 watts. This is a dB increase of:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "10 dB",
        "id": "B-005-008-008",
        "options": [
            "10 dB",
            "30 dB",
            "40 dB",
            "20 dB"
        ],
        "question": "The power of a transmitter is increased from 5 watts to 50 watts by a linear amplifier. The power gain, expressed in dB, is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "16 watts",
        "id": "B-005-008-009",
        "options": [
            "16 watts",
            "11 watts",
            "20 watts",
            "18 watts"
        ],
        "question": "You add a 9 dB gain amplifier to your 2 watt handheld. What is the power output of the combination?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "6 dB",
        "id": "B-005-008-010",
        "options": [
            "6 dB",
            "3 dB",
            "8 dB",
            "9 dB"
        ],
        "question": "The power of a transmitter is increased from 2 watts to 8 watts. This is a power gain of __________ dB."
    },
    {
        "answer": "100 mW",
        "id": "B-005-008-011",
        "options": [
            "100 mW",
            "1 W",
            "10 W",
            "33.3 W"
        ],
        "question": "A local amateur reports your 100W 2M simplex VHF transmission as 30 dB over S9. To reduce your signal to S9, you would reduce your power to ______ watts."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Twice the value of one inductor",
        "id": "B-005-009-001",
        "options": [
            "Twice the value of one inductor",
            "Half the value of one inductor",
            "The same as the value of either inductor",
            "The value of one inductor times the value of the other"
        ],
        "question": "If two equal-value inductors are connected in series, what is their total inductance?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Half the value of one inductor",
        "id": "B-005-009-002",
        "options": [
            "Half the value of one inductor",
            "Twice the value of one inductor",
            "The same as the value of either inductor",
            "The value of one inductor times the value of the other"
        ],
        "question": "If two equal-value inductors are connected in parallel, what is their total inductance?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Half the value of either capacitor",
        "id": "B-005-009-003",
        "options": [
            "Half the value of either capacitor",
            "Twice the value of one capacitor",
            "The same as the value of either capacitor",
            "The value of one capacitor times the value of the other"
        ],
        "question": "If two equal-value capacitors are connected in series, what is their total capacitance?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Twice the value of one capacitor",
        "id": "B-005-009-004",
        "options": [
            "Twice the value of one capacitor",
            "The same as the value of either capacitor",
            "The value of one capacitor times the value of the other",
            "Half the value of one capacitor"
        ],
        "question": "If two equal-value capacitors are connected in parallel, what is their total capacitance?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The core material, the coil diameter, the length of the coil and the number of turns of wire used to wind the coil",
        "id": "B-005-009-005",
        "options": [
            "The core material, the coil diameter, the length of the coil and the number of turns of wire used to wind the coil",
            "The core material, the number of turns used to wind the coil and the frequency of the current through the coil",
            "The coil diameter, the number of turns of wire used to wind the coil and the type of metal used for the wire",
            "The core material, the coil diameter, the length of the coil and whether the coil is mounted horizontally or vertically"
        ],
        "question": "What determines the inductance of a coil?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The material between the plates, the surface area of the plates, the number of plates and the spacing between the plates",
        "id": "B-005-009-006",
        "options": [
            "The material between the plates, the surface area of the plates, the number of plates and the spacing between the plates",
            "The material between the plates, the number of plates and the size of the wires connected to the plates",
            "The number of plates, the spacing between the plates and whether the dielectric material is N type or P type",
            "The material between the plates, the area of one plate, the number of plates and the material used for the protective coating"
        ],
        "question": "What determines the capacitance of a capacitor?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "5 millihenry chokes in series",
        "id": "B-005-009-008",
        "options": [
            "5 millihenry chokes in series",
            "20 millihenry chokes in series",
            "30 millihenry chokes in parallel",
            "5 millihenry chokes in parallel"
        ],
        "question": "To replace a faulty 10 millihenry choke, you could use two:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "5 microfarads",
        "id": "B-005-009-009",
        "options": [
            "5 microfarads",
            "45 microfarads",
            "12 microfarads",
            "18 microfarads"
        ],
        "question": "Three 15 microfarad capacitors are wired in series. The total capacitance of this arrangement is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Two 20 microfarad capacitors",
        "id": "B-005-009-010",
        "options": [
            "Two 20 microfarad capacitors",
            "Two 10 microfarad capacitors",
            "Twenty 2 microfarad capacitors",
            "Ten 2 microfarad capacitors"
        ],
        "question": "Which series combinations of capacitors would best replace a faulty 10 microfarad capacitor?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "always less than the smallest capacitor",
        "id": "B-005-009-011",
        "options": [
            "always less than the smallest capacitor",
            "found by adding each of the capacitors together and dividing by the total number of capacitors",
            "found by adding each of the capacitors together",
            "always greater than the largest capacitor"
        ],
        "question": "The total capacitance of two or more capacitors in series is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "As the frequency of the applied AC increases, the reactance increases",
        "id": "B-005-010-001",
        "options": [
            "As the frequency of the applied AC increases, the reactance increases",
            "As the amplitude of the applied AC increases, the reactance decreases",
            "As the amplitude of the applied AC increases, the reactance increases",
            "As the frequency of the applied AC increases, the reactance decreases"
        ],
        "question": "How does a coil react to AC?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "As the frequency of the applied AC increases, the reactance decreases",
        "id": "B-005-010-002",
        "options": [
            "As the frequency of the applied AC increases, the reactance decreases",
            "As the frequency of the applied AC increases, the reactance increases",
            "As the amplitude of the applied AC increases, the reactance increases",
            "As the amplitude of the applied AC increases, the reactance decreases"
        ],
        "question": "How does a capacitor react to AC?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "frequency decreases",
        "id": "B-005-010-003",
        "options": [
            "frequency decreases",
            "applied voltage increases",
            "applied voltage decreases",
            "frequency increases"
        ],
        "question": "The reactance of capacitors increases as:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "impedance",
        "id": "B-005-010-004",
        "options": [
            "impedance",
            "resonance",
            "inductance",
            "capacitance"
        ],
        "question": "In inductances, AC may be opposed by both resistance of winding wire and reactance due to inductive effect. The term which includes resistance and reactance is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "decreases as frequency increases",
        "id": "B-005-010-005",
        "options": [
            "decreases as frequency increases",
            "applies only to series RLC circuits",
            "increases as frequency increases",
            "increases with the time constant"
        ],
        "question": "Capacitive reactance:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "an increase in the applied frequency",
        "id": "B-005-010-006",
        "options": [
            "an increase in the applied frequency",
            "a decrease in the applied frequency",
            "a decrease in the supplied current",
            "an increase in the applied voltage"
        ],
        "question": "Inductive reactance may be increased by:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "High reactance at radio frequencies",
        "id": "B-005-010-007",
        "options": [
            "High reactance at radio frequencies",
            "Low reactance at radio frequencies",
            "Low reactance at audio frequencies",
            "High reactance at audio frequencies"
        ],
        "question": "What property allows a coil wound on a ferrite core to mitigate the effects of an offending radio signal?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Low reactance at radio frequencies",
        "id": "B-005-010-008",
        "options": [
            "Low reactance at radio frequencies",
            "High reactance at radio frequencies",
            "Low reactance at audio frequencies",
            "High reactance at audio frequencies"
        ],
        "question": "What property allows an RF bypass capacitor on an audio circuit to divert an offending radio signal?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "High reactance at low frequencies",
        "id": "B-005-010-009",
        "options": [
            "High reactance at low frequencies",
            "Low reactance at high frequencies",
            "High reactance at high frequencies",
            "Low reactance at low frequencies"
        ],
        "question": "What property allows an RF bypass capacitor to have little effect on an audio circuit?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Low reactance at low frequencies",
        "id": "B-005-010-010",
        "options": [
            "Low reactance at low frequencies",
            "High reactance at low frequencies",
            "Low reactance at high frequencies",
            "High reactance at high frequencies"
        ],
        "question": "What property allows an RF choke coil to have little effect on signals meant to flow through the coil?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "increasing AC frequency",
        "id": "B-005-010-011",
        "options": [
            "increasing AC frequency",
            "decreasing AC frequency",
            "decreasing applied voltage",
            "increasing applied voltage"
        ],
        "question": "In general, the reactance of inductors increases with:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Magnetizing current",
        "id": "B-005-011-001",
        "options": [
            "Magnetizing current",
            "Direct current",
            "Latent current",
            "Stabilizing current"
        ],
        "question": "If no load is attached to the secondary winding of a transformer, what is current in the primary winding called?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "13 watts",
        "id": "B-005-011-002",
        "options": [
            "13 watts",
            "6 watts",
            "8 watts",
            "3 watts"
        ],
        "question": "A transformer operates a 6.3 volt 2 ampere light bulb from its secondary winding. The input power to the primary winding is approximately:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "5 amperes",
        "id": "B-005-011-003",
        "options": [
            "5 amperes",
            "215 amperes",
            "25 amperes",
            "50 amperes"
        ],
        "question": "A transformer has a 240 volt primary that draws a current of 250 milliamperes from the mains supply. Assuming no losses and only one secondary, what current would be available from the 12 volt secondary?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "240 V",
        "id": "B-005-011-004",
        "options": [
            "240 V",
            "480 V",
            "610 V",
            "26 V"
        ],
        "question": "In a mains power transformer, the primary winding has 250 turns, and the secondary has 500. If the input voltage is 120 volts, the likely secondary voltage is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "directly proportional to the current in the conductor",
        "id": "B-005-011-005",
        "options": [
            "directly proportional to the current in the conductor",
            "inversely proportional to the diameter of the conductor",
            "directly proportional to the diameter of the conductor",
            "inversely proportional to the voltage on the conductor"
        ],
        "question": "The strength of the magnetic field around a conductor in air is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "current is going through its greatest rate of change",
        "id": "B-005-011-006",
        "options": [
            "current is going through its greatest rate of change",
            "the current through the coil is of a DC nature",
            "current is going through its least rate of change",
            "the magnetic field around the coil is not changing"
        ],
        "question": "Maximum induced voltage in a coil occurs when:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "perpendicular to the lines of force",
        "id": "B-005-011-007",
        "options": [
            "perpendicular to the lines of force",
            "made in a counter clockwise direction",
            "parallel to the lines of force",
            "made in a clockwise direction"
        ],
        "question": "The voltage induced in a conductor moving in a magnetic field is at a maximum when the movement is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "0.25 A",
        "id": "B-005-011-008",
        "options": [
            "0.25 A",
            "2 500 mA",
            "0.01 A",
            "0.25 mA"
        ],
        "question": "A 100% efficient transformer has a turns ratio of 1/5. If the secondary current is 50 milliamperes, the primary current is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "like",
        "id": "B-005-011-009",
        "options": [
            "like",
            "unlike",
            "positive",
            "negative"
        ],
        "question": "A force of repulsion exists between two _________ magnetic poles."
    },
    {
        "answer": "steel",
        "id": "B-005-011-010",
        "options": [
            "steel",
            "copper",
            "aluminum",
            "brass"
        ],
        "question": "A permanent magnet would most likely be made from:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "warm iron laminations",
        "id": "B-005-011-011",
        "options": [
            "warm iron laminations",
            "electrostatic shielding",
            "large secondary currents",
            "high primary voltages"
        ],
        "question": "The fact that energy transfer from primary to secondary windings in a power transformer is not perfect is indicated by:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "inductive reactance and capacitive reactance are equal",
        "id": "B-005-012-001",
        "options": [
            "inductive reactance and capacitive reactance are equal",
            "inductive reactance is the only opposition in the circuit",
            "the circuit contains no resistance",
            "resistance is equal to the reactance"
        ],
        "question": "Resonance is the condition that exists when:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "high impedance at resonance",
        "id": "B-005-012-002",
        "options": [
            "high impedance at resonance",
            "low impedance at resonance",
            "zero impedance at resonance",
            "an impedance equal to resistance of the circuit"
        ],
        "question": "Parallel tuned circuits offer:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "the frequency characteristic of a coil and capacitor circuit",
        "id": "B-005-012-003",
        "options": [
            "the frequency characteristic of a coil and capacitor circuit",
            "an inductor",
            "a set of parallel inductors",
            "the results of tuning a varicap (varactor)"
        ],
        "question": "Resonance is an electrical property used to describe:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "inductors and capacitors",
        "id": "B-005-012-004",
        "options": [
            "inductors and capacitors",
            "resistors and transistors",
            "directors and reflectors",
            "diodes and transistors"
        ],
        "question": "A tuned circuit is formed from two basic components. These are:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "resonant frequency",
        "id": "B-005-012-005",
        "options": [
            "resonant frequency",
            "impedance frequency",
            "inductive frequency",
            "reactive frequency"
        ],
        "question": "When a parallel coil-capacitor combination is supplied with AC of different frequencies, there will be one frequency where the impedance will be highest. This is the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "high impedance",
        "id": "B-005-012-006",
        "options": [
            "high impedance",
            "low impedance",
            "low mutual inductance",
            "high mutual inductance"
        ],
        "question": "In a parallel-resonant circuit at resonance, the circuit has a:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "low impedance",
        "id": "B-005-012-007",
        "options": [
            "low impedance",
            "high impedance",
            "low mutual inductance",
            "high mutual inductance"
        ],
        "question": "In a series resonant circuit at resonance, the circuit has:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "add a resistor to the circuit",
        "id": "B-005-012-008",
        "options": [
            "add a resistor to the circuit",
            "increase the area of plates in the capacitor",
            "insert Mylar sheets between the plates of the capacitor",
            "wind more turns on the coil"
        ],
        "question": "A coil and an air-spaced capacitor are arranged to form a resonant circuit. The resonant frequency will remain the same if we:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "select signal frequencies",
        "id": "B-005-012-009",
        "options": [
            "select signal frequencies",
            "filter direct current",
            "increase power",
            "adjust voltage levels"
        ],
        "question": "Resonant circuits in a receiver are used to:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "inductive reactance and capacitive reactance are equal and opposite in sign",
        "id": "B-005-012-010",
        "options": [
            "inductive reactance and capacitive reactance are equal and opposite in sign",
            "inductive reactance is the only opposition in the circuit",
            "the circuit contains no resistance",
            "resistance is equal to the reactance"
        ],
        "question": "Resonance is the condition that exists when:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "line current reaches maximum",
        "id": "B-005-012-011",
        "options": [
            "line current reaches maximum",
            "line current lags the applied voltage",
            "line current leads the applied voltage",
            "impedance is maximum"
        ],
        "question": "When a series LCR circuit is tuned to the frequency of the source, the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "In parallel with the circuit",
        "id": "B-005-013-001",
        "options": [
            "In parallel with the circuit",
            "In series with the circuit",
            "In quadrature with the circuit",
            "In phase with the circuit"
        ],
        "question": "How is a voltmeter usually connected to a circuit under test?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "In series with the circuit",
        "id": "B-005-013-002",
        "options": [
            "In series with the circuit",
            "In quadrature with the circuit",
            "In phase with the circuit",
            "In parallel with the circuit"
        ],
        "question": "How is an ammeter usually connected to a circuit under test?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Voltage, current and resistance",
        "id": "B-005-013-003",
        "options": [
            "Voltage, current and resistance",
            "Resistance, capacitance and inductance",
            "Resistance and reactance",
            "SWR and power"
        ],
        "question": "What does a multimeter measure?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "an ammeter",
        "id": "B-005-013-004",
        "options": [
            "an ammeter",
            "an ohmmeter",
            "a wattmeter",
            "a voltmeter"
        ],
        "question": "The correct instrument to measure plate current or collector current of a transmitter is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A DC ammeter",
        "id": "B-005-013-005",
        "options": [
            "A DC ammeter",
            "An RF ammeter",
            "An RF power meter",
            "An electrostatic voltmeter"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following meters would you use to measure the power supply current drawn by a small hand-held transistorized receiver?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "a low value resistance",
        "id": "B-005-013-006",
        "options": [
            "a low value resistance",
            "a perfect conductor",
            "an extra current drain",
            "an insulator"
        ],
        "question": "When measuring current drawn from a DC power supply, it is true to say that the meter will act in circuit as:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "in series with one of the receiver power leads",
        "id": "B-005-013-007",
        "options": [
            "in series with one of the receiver power leads",
            "in series with both receiver power leads",
            "in parallel with both receiver power supply leads",
            "in parallel with one of the receiver power leads"
        ],
        "question": "When measuring the current drawn by a receiver from a power supply, the current meter should be placed:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "a voltmeter",
        "id": "B-005-013-008",
        "options": [
            "a voltmeter",
            "a wattmeter",
            "an ohmmeter",
            "an ammeter"
        ],
        "question": "Potential difference is measured by means of:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "ammeter",
        "id": "B-005-013-009",
        "options": [
            "ammeter",
            "faradmeter",
            "wattmeter",
            "voltmeter"
        ],
        "question": "The instrument used for measuring the flow of electrical current is the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "the voltmeter in parallel and ammeter in series",
        "id": "B-005-013-010",
        "options": [
            "the voltmeter in parallel and ammeter in series",
            "the voltmeter in series and ammeter in parallel",
            "both voltmeter and ammeter in series",
            "both voltmeter and ammeter in parallel"
        ],
        "question": "In measuring volts and amperes, the connections should be made with:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A transmission line",
        "id": "B-006-001-001",
        "options": [
            "A transmission line",
            "The power cord",
            "A ground wire",
            "A dummy load"
        ],
        "question": "What connects your transceiver to your antenna?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "physical dimensions and relative positions of the conductors",
        "id": "B-006-001-002",
        "options": [
            "physical dimensions and relative positions of the conductors",
            "length of the line",
            "frequency at which the line is operated",
            "load placed on the line"
        ],
        "question": "The characteristic impedance of a transmission line is determined by the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "52 ohms",
        "id": "B-006-001-003",
        "options": [
            "52 ohms",
            "26 ohms",
            "39 ohms",
            "13 ohms"
        ],
        "question": "The characteristic impedance of a 20 metre piece of transmission line is 52 ohms. If 10 metres were cut off, the impedance would be:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "can be the same for different diameter line",
        "id": "B-006-001-004",
        "options": [
            "can be the same for different diameter line",
            "changes significantly with the frequency of the energy it carries",
            "is correct for only one size of line",
            "is greater for larger diameter line"
        ],
        "question": "The characteristic impedance of a coaxial line:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Coaxial cable",
        "id": "B-006-001-005",
        "options": [
            "Coaxial cable",
            "300 ohm twin-lead",
            "600 ohm open-wire line",
            "75 ohm twin-lead"
        ],
        "question": "What commonly available antenna transmission line can be buried directly in the ground for some distance without adverse effects?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "equal to the pure resistance which, if connected to the end of the line, will absorb all the power arriving along it",
        "id": "B-006-001-006",
        "options": [
            "equal to the pure resistance which, if connected to the end of the line, will absorb all the power arriving along it",
            "the impedance of a section of the line one wavelength long",
            "the dynamic impedance of the line at the operating frequency",
            "the ratio of the power supplied to the line to the power delivered to the load"
        ],
        "question": "The characteristic impedance of a transmission line is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "propagation delay",
        "id": "B-006-001-007",
        "options": [
            "propagation delay",
            "capacitive reactance",
            "inductive reactance",
            "resistance"
        ],
        "question": "A transmission line differs from an ordinary circuit or network in communications or signalling devices in one very important way. That important aspect is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "velocity of energy on the line",
        "id": "B-006-001-008",
        "options": [
            "velocity of energy on the line",
            "radius of the conductors",
            "centre to centre distance between conductors",
            "dielectric"
        ],
        "question": "The characteristic impedance of a parallel wire transmission line does not depend on the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Some value of impedance influenced by line length",
        "id": "B-006-001-009",
        "options": [
            "Some value of impedance influenced by line length",
            "An infinite impedance",
            "A negative impedance",
            "An impedance nearly equal to the characteristic impedance"
        ],
        "question": "If the impedance terminating a transmission line differs significantly from the characteristic impedance of the line, what will be observed at the input of the line?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The distance between the centres of the conductors and the radius of the conductors",
        "id": "B-006-001-010",
        "options": [
            "The distance between the centres of the conductors and the radius of the conductors",
            "The distance between the centres of the conductors and the length of the line",
            "The radius of the conductors and the frequency of the signal",
            "The frequency of the signal and the length of the line"
        ],
        "question": "What factors determine the characteristic impedance of a parallel-conductor antenna transmission line?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The ratio of the diameter of the inner conductor to the diameter of the outer shield",
        "id": "B-006-001-011",
        "options": [
            "The ratio of the diameter of the inner conductor to the diameter of the outer shield",
            "The diameter of the shield and the length of the line",
            "The diameter of the shield and the frequency of the signal",
            "The frequency of the signal and the length of the line"
        ],
        "question": "What factors determine the characteristic impedance of a coaxial antenna transmission line?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A center wire inside an insulating material which is covered by a metal sleeve or shield",
        "id": "B-006-002-001",
        "options": [
            "A center wire inside an insulating material which is covered by a metal sleeve or shield",
            "Two wires side-by-side in a plastic ribbon",
            "Two wires side-by-side held apart by insulating rods",
            "Two wires twisted around each other in a spiral"
        ],
        "question": "What is a coaxial cable?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Two wires side-by-side held apart by insulating material",
        "id": "B-006-002-002",
        "options": [
            "Two wires side-by-side held apart by insulating material",
            "Two wires twisted around each other in a spiral",
            "A center wire inside an insulating material which is covered by a metal sleeve or shield",
            "A metal pipe which is as wide or slightly wider than a wavelength of the signal it carries"
        ],
        "question": "What is parallel-conductor transmission line?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Open wire line",
        "id": "B-006-002-003",
        "options": [
            "Open wire line",
            "Coaxial cable",
            "Twin lead in a plastic ribbon",
            "Twisted pair"
        ],
        "question": "What kind of antenna transmission line is made of two conductors held apart by insulated rods?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Balanced to unbalanced",
        "id": "B-006-002-004",
        "options": [
            "Balanced to unbalanced",
            "Balanced unloader",
            "Balanced unmodulator",
            "Balanced antenna network"
        ],
        "question": "What does the term \"balun\" mean?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Between the coaxial cable and the antenna",
        "id": "B-006-002-005",
        "options": [
            "Between the coaxial cable and the antenna",
            "Between the transmitter and the coaxial cable",
            "Between the antenna and the ground",
            "Between the coaxial cable and the ground"
        ],
        "question": "Where would you install a balun to feed a dipole antenna with 50-ohm coaxial cable?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Transmission line with one conductor connected to ground",
        "id": "B-006-002-006",
        "options": [
            "Transmission line with one conductor connected to ground",
            "Transmission line with neither conductor connected to ground",
            "Transmission line with both conductors connected to ground",
            "Transmission line with both conductors connected to each other"
        ],
        "question": "What is an unbalanced line?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A balun",
        "id": "B-006-002-007",
        "options": [
            "A balun",
            "A triaxial transformer",
            "A wave trap",
            "A loading coil"
        ],
        "question": "What device can be installed to feed a balanced antenna with an unbalanced transmission line?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "braided shield conductor and insulation around a central conductor",
        "id": "B-006-002-008",
        "options": [
            "braided shield conductor and insulation around a central conductor",
            "four or more conductors running parallel",
            "only one conductor",
            "two parallel conductors separated by spacers"
        ],
        "question": "A flexible coaxial line contains:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "is made of two parallel wires",
        "id": "B-006-002-009",
        "options": [
            "is made of two parallel wires",
            "has one conductor inside the other",
            "carries RF current on one wire only",
            "is made of one conductor only"
        ],
        "question": "A balanced transmission line:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "by using a 4 to 1 impedance transformer",
        "id": "B-006-002-010",
        "options": [
            "by using a 4 to 1 impedance transformer",
            "with an extra 250 ohm resistor",
            "by using a 4 to 1 trigatron",
            "by inserting a diode in one leg of the antenna"
        ],
        "question": "A 75 ohm transmission line could be matched to the 300 ohm feed point of an antenna:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "600 ohm open wire line",
        "id": "B-006-002-011",
        "options": [
            "600 ohm open wire line",
            "Coaxial cable",
            "75 ohm twin-lead",
            "300 ohm twin-lead"
        ],
        "question": "What kind of antenna transmission line can be constructed using two conductors which are maintained a uniform distance apart using insulated spreaders?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It is weatherproof, and its impedance matches most amateur antennas",
        "id": "B-006-003-001",
        "options": [
            "It is weatherproof, and its impedance matches most amateur antennas",
            "It is weatherproof, and its impedance is higher than that of most amateur antennas",
            "It can be used near metal objects, and its impedance is higher than that of most amateur antennas",
            "You can make it at home, and its impedance matches most amateur antennas"
        ],
        "question": "Why does coaxial cable make a good antenna transmission line?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Coaxial cable",
        "id": "B-006-003-002",
        "options": [
            "Coaxial cable",
            "Ladder-line",
            "Twisted pair",
            "Twin lead"
        ],
        "question": "What is the best antenna transmission line to use, if it must be put near grounded metal objects?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It does not work well when tied down to metal objects, and you should use a balun and may have to use an impedance-matching device with your transceiver",
        "id": "B-006-003-003",
        "options": [
            "It does not work well when tied down to metal objects, and you should use a balun and may have to use an impedance-matching device with your transceiver",
            "You must use an impedance-matching device with your transceiver, and it does not work very well with a high SWR",
            "It does not work well when tied down to metal objects, and it cannot operate under high power",
            "It is difficult to make at home, and it does not work very well with a high SWR"
        ],
        "question": "What are some reasons not to use parallel-conductor transmission line?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A PL-259 connector",
        "id": "B-006-003-004",
        "options": [
            "A PL-259 connector",
            "An F-type cable connector",
            "A banana plug connector",
            "A binding post connector"
        ],
        "question": "What common connector type usually joins RG-213 coaxial cable to an HF transceiver?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "An SMA connector",
        "id": "B-006-003-005",
        "options": [
            "An SMA connector",
            "A PL-259 connector",
            "An F-type cable connector",
            "A binding post connector"
        ],
        "question": "What common connector usually joins a hand-held transceiver to its antenna?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A type-N connector",
        "id": "B-006-003-006",
        "options": [
            "A type-N connector",
            "An F-type cable connector",
            "A BNC connector",
            "A PL-259 connector"
        ],
        "question": "Which of these common connectors has the lowest loss at UHF?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "RG-213",
        "id": "B-006-003-007",
        "options": [
            "RG-213",
            "RG-174",
            "RG-59",
            "RG-58"
        ],
        "question": "If you install a 6 metre Yagi on a tower 60 metres (200 ft) from your transmitter, which of the following transmission lines provides the least loss?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "To help keep their contact resistance at a minimum",
        "id": "B-006-003-008",
        "options": [
            "To help keep their contact resistance at a minimum",
            "To keep them looking nice",
            "To keep them from getting stuck in place",
            "To increase their capacitance"
        ],
        "question": "Why should you regularly clean and tighten all antenna connectors?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Coaxial cable",
        "id": "B-006-003-009",
        "options": [
            "Coaxial cable",
            "75 ohm twin-lead",
            "600 ohm open wire line",
            "300 ohm twin-lead"
        ],
        "question": "What commonly available antenna transmission line can be buried directly in the ground for some distance without adverse effects?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Coaxial cable",
        "id": "B-006-003-010",
        "options": [
            "Coaxial cable",
            "300 ohm twin-lead",
            "600 ohm open wire line",
            "75 ohm twin-lead"
        ],
        "question": "When antenna transmission lines must be placed near grounded metal objects, which of the following transmission lines should be used?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "300 ohms",
        "id": "B-006-003-011",
        "options": [
            "300 ohms",
            "600 ohms",
            "50 ohms",
            "70 ohms"
        ],
        "question": "TV twin-lead transmission line can be used for a transmission line in an amateur station. The impedance of this line is approximately:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "To keep RF loss low",
        "id": "B-006-004-001",
        "options": [
            "To keep RF loss low",
            "To keep television interference high",
            "To keep the power going to your antenna system from getting too high",
            "To keep the standing wave ratio of your antenna system high"
        ],
        "question": "Why should you use only good quality coaxial cable and connectors for a UHF antenna system?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It will operate with a high SWR, and has less loss than coaxial cable",
        "id": "B-006-004-002",
        "options": [
            "It will operate with a high SWR, and has less loss than coaxial cable",
            "It has low impedance, and will operate with a high SWR",
            "It will operate with a high SWR, and it works well when tied down to metal objects",
            "It has a low impedance, and has less loss than coaxial cable"
        ],
        "question": "What are some reasons to use parallel-conductor transmission line?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Shorten the excess cable",
        "id": "B-006-004-003",
        "options": [
            "Shorten the excess cable",
            "Shorten the excess cable so the transmission line is an odd number of wavelengths long",
            "Roll the excess cable into a coil which is as small as possible",
            "Shorten the excess cable so the transmission line is an even number of wavelengths long"
        ],
        "question": "If your transmitter and antenna are 15 metres (50 ft) apart, but are connected by 60 metres (200 ft) of RG-58 coaxial cable, what should be done to reduce transmission line loss?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Signal loss increases as length increases",
        "id": "B-006-004-004",
        "options": [
            "Signal loss increases as length increases",
            "Signal loss decreases as length increases",
            "Signal loss is the least when the length is the same as the signal's wavelength",
            "Signal loss is the same for any length of transmission line"
        ],
        "question": "As the length of a transmission line is changed, what happens to signal loss?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Signal loss increases with increasing frequency",
        "id": "B-006-004-005",
        "options": [
            "Signal loss increases with increasing frequency",
            "Signal loss increases with decreasing frequency",
            "Signal loss is the least when the signal's wavelength is the same as the transmission line's length",
            "Signal loss is the same for any frequency"
        ],
        "question": "As the frequency of a signal is changed, what happens to signal loss in a transmission line?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "less RF power being radiated",
        "id": "B-006-004-006",
        "options": [
            "less RF power being radiated",
            "an SWR reading of 1:1",
            "reflections occurring in the line",
            "the wire radiating RF energy"
        ],
        "question": "Losses occurring on a transmission line between transmitter and antenna results in:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "open wire line",
        "id": "B-006-004-007",
        "options": [
            "open wire line",
            "75 ohm twin-lead",
            "coaxial cable",
            "300 ohm twin-lead"
        ],
        "question": "The lowest loss transmission line on HF is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "dB per unit length",
        "id": "B-006-004-008",
        "options": [
            "dB per unit length",
            "Ohms per MHz",
            "dB per MHz",
            "Ohms per metre"
        ],
        "question": "In what values are RF transmission line losses expressed?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It would be increased by 100%",
        "id": "B-006-004-009",
        "options": [
            "It would be increased by 100%",
            "It would be reduced by 10%",
            "It would be increased by 10%",
            "It would be reduced to 50%"
        ],
        "question": "If the length of coaxial transmission line is increased from 20 metres (66 ft) to 40 metres (132 ft), how would this affect the line loss?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It would increase",
        "id": "B-006-004-010",
        "options": [
            "It would increase",
            "It is independent of frequency",
            "It depends on the line length",
            "It would decrease"
        ],
        "question": "If the frequency is increased, how would this affect the loss on a transmission line?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The best impedance match has been attained",
        "id": "B-006-005-001",
        "options": [
            "The best impedance match has been attained",
            "An antenna for another frequency band is probably connected",
            "No power is going to the antenna",
            "The SWR meter is broken"
        ],
        "question": "What does an SWR reading of 1:1 mean?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A fairly good impedance match",
        "id": "B-006-005-002",
        "options": [
            "A fairly good impedance match",
            "An impedance match which is too low",
            "A serious impedance mismatch, something may be wrong with the antenna system",
            "An antenna gain of 1.5"
        ],
        "question": "What does an SWR reading of less than 1.5:1 mean?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A jumpy reading",
        "id": "B-006-005-003",
        "options": [
            "A jumpy reading",
            "A negative reading",
            "No reading at all",
            "A very low reading"
        ],
        "question": "What kind of SWR reading may mean poor electrical contact between parts of an antenna system?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The antenna is the wrong length for the operating frequency, or the transmission line may be open or short circuited",
        "id": "B-006-005-004",
        "options": [
            "The antenna is the wrong length for the operating frequency, or the transmission line may be open or short circuited",
            "The transmitter is putting out more power than normal, showing that it is about to go bad",
            "There is a large amount of solar radiation, which means very poor radio conditions",
            "The signals coming from the antenna are unusually strong, which means very good radio condition"
        ],
        "question": "What does a very high SWR reading mean?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The ratio of maximum to minimum voltages on a transmission line",
        "id": "B-006-005-005",
        "options": [
            "The ratio of maximum to minimum voltages on a transmission line",
            "The ratio of maximum to minimum inductances on a transmission line",
            "The ratio of maximum to minimum resistances on a transmission line",
            "The ratio of maximum to minimum impedances on a transmission line"
        ],
        "question": "What does standing-wave ratio mean?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The SWR may be too high, or the transmission line loss may be high",
        "id": "B-006-005-006",
        "options": [
            "The SWR may be too high, or the transmission line loss may be high",
            "You should transmit using less power",
            "The conductors in the transmission line are not insulated very well",
            "The transmission line is too long"
        ],
        "question": "If your antenna transmission line gets hot when you are transmitting, what might this mean?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "standing waves are produced in the transmission line",
        "id": "B-006-005-007",
        "options": [
            "standing waves are produced in the transmission line",
            "heat is produced at the junction",
            "the SWR reading falls to 1:1",
            "the antenna will not radiate any signal"
        ],
        "question": "If the characteristic impedance of the transmission line does not match the antenna input impedance then:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "reduced transfer of RF energy to the antenna",
        "id": "B-006-005-008",
        "options": [
            "reduced transfer of RF energy to the antenna",
            "perfect impedance match between transmitter and transmission line",
            "maximum transfer of energy to the antenna from the transmitter",
            "lack of radiation from the transmission line"
        ],
        "question": "The result of the presence of standing waves on a transmission line is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "comparing forward and reflected voltage",
        "id": "B-006-005-009",
        "options": [
            "comparing forward and reflected voltage",
            "measuring radiated RF energy",
            "measuring the conductor temperature",
            "inserting a diode in the transmission line"
        ],
        "question": "An SWR meter measures the degree of match between transmission line and antenna by:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "4:1",
        "id": "B-006-005-010",
        "options": [
            "4:1",
            "6:1",
            "3:1",
            "5:1"
        ],
        "question": "A resonant antenna having a feed point impedance of 200 ohms is connected to a transmission line which has an impedance of 50 ohms. What will the standing wave ratio of this system be?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "600 ohm open wire line",
        "id": "B-006-005-011",
        "options": [
            "600 ohm open wire line",
            "75 ohm twin-lead",
            "coaxial line",
            "300 ohm twin-lead"
        ],
        "question": "The type of transmission line best suited to operating at a high standing wave ratio is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "An antenna tuner",
        "id": "B-006-006-001",
        "options": [
            "An antenna tuner",
            "An SWR meter",
            "A low pass filter",
            "A high pass filter"
        ],
        "question": "What device might allow use of an antenna on a band it was not designed for?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It matches a transceiver to a mismatched antenna system",
        "id": "B-006-006-002",
        "options": [
            "It matches a transceiver to a mismatched antenna system",
            "It helps a receiver automatically tune in stations that are far away",
            "It switches an antenna system to a transmitter when sending, and to a receiver when listening",
            "It switches a transceiver between different kinds of antennas connected to one transmission line"
        ],
        "question": "What does an antenna tuner do?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "An impedance-matching device",
        "id": "B-006-006-003",
        "options": [
            "An impedance-matching device",
            "An SWR meter",
            "A low pass filter",
            "A terminating resistor"
        ],
        "question": "What would you use to connect a coaxial cable of 50 ohms impedance to an antenna of 17 ohms impedance?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "When the impedance of the load is equal to the impedance of the source",
        "id": "B-006-006-004",
        "options": [
            "When the impedance of the load is equal to the impedance of the source",
            "When air wound transformers are used instead of iron-core transformers",
            "When the power-supply fuse rating equals the primary winding current",
            "When the load resistance is infinite"
        ],
        "question": "When will a power source deliver maximum output to the load?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The source delivers maximum power to the load",
        "id": "B-006-006-005",
        "options": [
            "The source delivers maximum power to the load",
            "The electrical load is shorted",
            "No current can flow through the circuit",
            "The source delivers minimum power to the load"
        ],
        "question": "What happens when the impedance of an electrical load is equal to the internal impedance of the power source?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "So the source can deliver maximum power to the load",
        "id": "B-006-006-006",
        "options": [
            "So the source can deliver maximum power to the load",
            "So the load will draw minimum power from the source",
            "To ensure that there is less resistance than reactance in the circuit",
            "To ensure that the resistance and reactance in the circuit are equal"
        ],
        "question": "Why is impedance matching important?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "matching of impedances",
        "id": "B-006-006-007",
        "options": [
            "matching of impedances",
            "high load impedance",
            "low load resistance",
            "inductive impedance"
        ],
        "question": "To obtain efficient power transmission from a transmitter to an antenna requires:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "matching of impedance",
        "id": "B-006-006-008",
        "options": [
            "matching of impedance",
            "high load impedance",
            "proper method of balance",
            "low load resistance"
        ],
        "question": "To obtain efficient transfer of power from a transmitter to an antenna, it is important that there is a:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "will have no effect on the matching",
        "id": "B-006-006-009",
        "options": [
            "will have no effect on the matching",
            "must be a full wavelength long",
            "must be an odd number of quarter-wave",
            "must be an even number of half-waves"
        ],
        "question": "If an antenna is correctly matched to a transmitter, the length of transmission line:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "transfer the maximum amount of power to the antenna",
        "id": "B-006-006-010",
        "options": [
            "transfer the maximum amount of power to the antenna",
            "ensure that the radiated signal has the intended polarization",
            "prevent frequency drift",
            "overcome fading of the transmitted signal"
        ],
        "question": "The reason that an RF transmission line should be matched at the transmitter end is to:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "6:1",
        "id": "B-006-006-011",
        "options": [
            "6:1",
            "2:1",
            "4:1",
            "10:1"
        ],
        "question": "If the centre impedance of a folded dipole is approximately 300 ohms, and you are using RG8U (50 ohms) coaxial lines, what is the ratio required to have the line and the antenna matched?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The electric lines of force of a radio wave are parallel to the Earth's surface",
        "id": "B-006-007-001",
        "options": [
            "The electric lines of force of a radio wave are parallel to the Earth's surface",
            "The electric and magnetic lines of force of a radio wave are perpendicular to the Earth's surface",
            "The electric lines of force of a radio wave are perpendicular to the Earth's surface",
            "The magnetic lines of force of a radio wave are parallel to the Earth's surface"
        ],
        "question": "What does horizontal wave polarization mean?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The electric lines of force of a radio wave are perpendicular to the Earth's surface",
        "id": "B-006-007-002",
        "options": [
            "The electric lines of force of a radio wave are perpendicular to the Earth's surface",
            "The magnetic lines of force of a radio wave are perpendicular to the Earth's surface",
            "The electric and magnetic lines of force of a radio wave are parallel to the Earth's surface",
            "The electric lines of force of a radio wave are parallel to the Earth's surface"
        ],
        "question": "What does vertical wave polarization mean?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Horizontal",
        "id": "B-006-007-003",
        "options": [
            "Horizontal",
            "Helical",
            "Vertical",
            "Circular"
        ],
        "question": "What electromagnetic wave polarization does a Yagi antenna have when its elements are parallel to the Earth's surface?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Vertical",
        "id": "B-006-007-004",
        "options": [
            "Vertical",
            "Circular",
            "Horizontal",
            "Parabolical"
        ],
        "question": "What electromagnetic wave polarization does a half-wavelength antenna have when it is perpendicular to the Earth's surface?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "the orientation of the electric field relative to the Earth's surface",
        "id": "B-006-007-005",
        "options": [
            "the orientation of the electric field relative to the Earth's surface",
            "the height of the antenna",
            "the type of antenna",
            "the magnetic field"
        ],
        "question": "Polarization of an antenna is determined by:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "a hypothetical point source",
        "id": "B-006-007-006",
        "options": [
            "a hypothetical point source",
            "an infinitely long piece of wire",
            "a dummy load",
            "a half-wave reference dipole"
        ],
        "question": "An isotropic antenna is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A sphere",
        "id": "B-006-007-007",
        "options": [
            "A sphere",
            "A parabola",
            "A cardioid",
            "A unidirectional cardioid"
        ],
        "question": "What is the antenna radiation pattern for an isotropic radiator?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "vertical ground-plane antenna",
        "id": "B-006-007-008",
        "options": [
            "vertical ground-plane antenna",
            "random length of wire",
            "horizontal ground-plane antenna",
            "horizontal dipole antenna"
        ],
        "question": "VHF signals from a mobile station using a vertical whip antenna will normally be best received using a:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "mounted vertically",
        "id": "B-006-007-009",
        "options": [
            "mounted vertically",
            "fed with the correct type of RF",
            "too near to the ground",
            "parallel with the ground"
        ],
        "question": "A dipole antenna will emit a vertically polarized wave if it is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "vertically polarized",
        "id": "B-006-007-010",
        "options": [
            "vertically polarized",
            "polarized at right angles to original",
            "horizontally polarized",
            "polarized in any plane"
        ],
        "question": "If an electromagnetic wave leaves an antenna vertically polarized, it will arrive at the receiving antenna, by ground wave:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "at greater strength",
        "id": "B-006-007-011",
        "options": [
            "at greater strength",
            "at weaker strength",
            "without any comparative difference",
            "if the antenna changes the polarization"
        ],
        "question": "Compared with a horizontal antenna, a vertical antenna will receive a vertically polarized radio wave:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It decreases",
        "id": "B-006-008-001",
        "options": [
            "It decreases",
            "It increases",
            "It stays the same",
            "It disappears"
        ],
        "question": "If an antenna is made longer, what happens to its resonant frequency?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It increases",
        "id": "B-006-008-002",
        "options": [
            "It increases",
            "It stays the same",
            "It disappears",
            "It decreases"
        ],
        "question": "If an antenna is made shorter, what happens to its resonant frequency?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "12 metres (39.4 ft)",
        "id": "B-006-008-003",
        "options": [
            "12 metres (39.4 ft)",
            "15 metres (49.2 ft)",
            "4 metres (13.1 ft)",
            "32 metres (105 ft)"
        ],
        "question": "The wavelength for a frequency of 25 MHz is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "300 000 kilometres per second",
        "id": "B-006-008-004",
        "options": [
            "300 000 kilometres per second",
            "3000 kilometres per second",
            "150 kilometres per second",
            "186 000 kilometres per second"
        ],
        "question": "The velocity of propagation of radio frequency energy in free space is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "decrease the resonant frequency",
        "id": "B-006-008-005",
        "options": [
            "decrease the resonant frequency",
            "increase the resonant frequency",
            "have little effect",
            "have no change on the resonant frequency"
        ],
        "question": "Adding a series inductance to an antenna would:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "shortening the radiating element",
        "id": "B-006-008-006",
        "options": [
            "shortening the radiating element",
            "lowering the radiating element",
            "increasing the height of the radiating element",
            "lengthening the radiating element"
        ],
        "question": "The resonant frequency of an antenna may be increased by:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "is the same as the speed of light",
        "id": "B-006-008-007",
        "options": [
            "is the same as the speed of light",
            "is infinite in space",
            "is always less than half speed of light",
            "varies directly with frequency"
        ],
        "question": "The speed of a radio wave:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "limit the electrical length of the antenna",
        "id": "B-006-008-008",
        "options": [
            "limit the electrical length of the antenna",
            "increase the effective antenna length",
            "allow the antenna to be more easily held vertically",
            "prevent any loss of radio waves by the antenna"
        ],
        "question": "At the end of suspended antenna wire, insulators are used. These act to:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "lengthen it",
        "id": "B-006-008-009",
        "options": [
            "lengthen it",
            "shorten it",
            "ground one end",
            "centre feed it with TV ribbon transmission line"
        ],
        "question": "To lower the resonant frequency of an antenna, the operator should:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "a coil and capacitor in parallel",
        "id": "B-006-008-010",
        "options": [
            "a coil and capacitor in parallel",
            "large wire-wound resistors",
            "coils wrapped around a ferrite rod",
            "hollow metal cans"
        ],
        "question": "One solution to multiband operation with a shortened radiator is the \"trap dipole\" or trap vertical. These \"traps\" are actually:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "150 m (492 ft)",
        "id": "B-006-008-011",
        "options": [
            "150 m (492 ft)",
            "360 m (1181 ft)",
            "1500 m (4921 ft)",
            "30 m (98 ft)"
        ],
        "question": "The wavelength corresponding to a frequency of 2 MHz is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "An antenna where some elements obtain their radio energy by induction or radiation from a driven element",
        "id": "B-006-009-001",
        "options": [
            "An antenna where some elements obtain their radio energy by induction or radiation from a driven element",
            "An antenna where the driven element obtains its radio energy by induction or radiation from director elements",
            "An antenna where all elements are driven by direct connection to the transmission line",
            "An antenna where wave traps are used to magnetically couple the elements"
        ],
        "question": "What is a parasitic beam antenna?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Use larger diameter elements",
        "id": "B-006-009-002",
        "options": [
            "Use larger diameter elements",
            "Use traps on the elements",
            "Use tapered-diameter elements",
            "Use closer element spacing"
        ],
        "question": "How can the bandwidth of a parasitic beam antenna be increased?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A major lobe will develop in the horizontal plane, from the dipole toward the parasitic element",
        "id": "B-006-009-003",
        "options": [
            "A major lobe will develop in the horizontal plane, from the dipole toward the parasitic element",
            "A major lobe will develop in the horizontal plane, parallel to the two elements",
            "A major lobe will develop in the vertical plane, away from the ground",
            "The radiation pattern will not be affected"
        ],
        "question": "If a parasitic element slightly shorter than a horizontal dipole antenna is placed parallel to the dipole 0.1 wavelength from it and at the same height, what effect will this have on the antenna's radiation pattern?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A major lobe will develop in the horizontal plane, from the parasitic element toward the dipole",
        "id": "B-006-009-004",
        "options": [
            "A major lobe will develop in the horizontal plane, from the parasitic element toward the dipole",
            "A major lobe will develop in the horizontal plane, parallel to the two elements",
            "A major lobe will develop in the vertical plane, away from the ground",
            "The radiation pattern will not be affected"
        ],
        "question": "If a parasitic element slightly longer than a horizontal dipole antenna is placed parallel to the dipole 0.1 wavelength from it and at the same height, what effect will this have on the antenna's radiation pattern?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "bandwidth",
        "id": "B-006-009-005",
        "options": [
            "bandwidth",
            "front-to-back ratio",
            "impedance",
            "polarization"
        ],
        "question": "The property of an antenna, which defines the range of frequencies to which it will respond, is called its:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "2.1 dB",
        "id": "B-006-009-006",
        "options": [
            "2.1 dB",
            "1.5 dB",
            "3.0 dB",
            "6.0 dB"
        ],
        "question": "Approximately how much gain does a half-wave dipole have over an isotropic radiator?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The numerical ratio relating the radiated signal strength of an antenna to that of another antenna",
        "id": "B-006-009-007",
        "options": [
            "The numerical ratio relating the radiated signal strength of an antenna to that of another antenna",
            "The numerical ratio of the signal in the forward direction to the signal in the back direction",
            "The numerical ratio of the amount of power radiated by an antenna compared to the transmitter output power",
            "The power amplifier gain minus the transmission line losses"
        ],
        "question": "What is meant by antenna gain?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The frequency range over which the antenna may be expected to perform well",
        "id": "B-006-009-008",
        "options": [
            "The frequency range over which the antenna may be expected to perform well",
            "Antenna length divided by the number of elements",
            "The angle between the half-power radiation points",
            "The angle formed between two imaginary lines drawn through the ends of the elements"
        ],
        "question": "What is meant by antenna bandwidth?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Minimum radiation from the ends, maximum broadside",
        "id": "B-006-009-009",
        "options": [
            "Minimum radiation from the ends, maximum broadside",
            "Maximum radiation from the ends, minimum broadside",
            "Omnidirectional",
            "Maximum radiation at 45 degrees to the plane of the antenna"
        ],
        "question": "In free space, what is the radiation characteristic of a half-wave dipole?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "isotropic",
        "id": "B-006-009-010",
        "options": [
            "isotropic",
            "ideal",
            "ionosphere",
            "interpolated"
        ],
        "question": "The gain of an antenna, especially on VHF and above, is quoted in dBi. The \"i\" in this expression stands for:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "the ratio of the maximum forward power in the major lobe to the maximum backward power radiation",
        "id": "B-006-009-011",
        "options": [
            "the ratio of the maximum forward power in the major lobe to the maximum backward power radiation",
            "the forward power of the major lobe to the power in the backward direction both being measured at the 3 dB points",
            "undefined",
            "the ratio of the forward power at the 3 dB points to the power radiated in the backward direction"
        ],
        "question": "The front-to-back ratio of a beam antenna is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Divide 71.5 (234) by the antenna's operating frequency in MHz",
        "id": "B-006-010-001",
        "options": [
            "Divide 71.5 (234) by the antenna's operating frequency in MHz",
            "Divide 468 (1532) by the antenna's operating frequency in MHz",
            "Divide 300 (982) by the antenna's operating frequency in MHz",
            "Divide 150 (491) by the antenna's operating frequency in MHz"
        ],
        "question": "How do you calculate the length in metres (feet) of a quarter-wavelength antenna using frequencies below 30MHz?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "3.36 metres (11.0 ft)",
        "id": "B-006-010-002",
        "options": [
            "3.36 metres (11.0 ft)",
            "3.6 metres (11.8 ft)",
            "7.2 metres (23.6 ft)",
            "6.76 metres (22.2 ft)"
        ],
        "question": "If you made a quarter-wavelength vertical antenna for 21.125 MHz, approximately how long would it be?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "67 cm (26.4 in)",
        "id": "B-006-010-003",
        "options": [
            "67 cm (26.4 in)",
            "128 cm (50.4 in)",
            "105 cm (41.3 in)",
            "134.6 cm (53 in)"
        ],
        "question": "If you made a half-wavelength vertical antenna for 223 MHz, approximately how long would it be?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A 5/8-wavelength antenna has more gain",
        "id": "B-006-010-004",
        "options": [
            "A 5/8-wavelength antenna has more gain",
            "A 5/8-wavelength antenna has less corona loss",
            "A 5/8-wavelength antenna is easier to install on a car",
            "A 5/8-wavelength antenna can handle more power"
        ],
        "question": "Why is a 5/8-wavelength vertical antenna better than a 1/4-wavelength vertical antenna for VHF or UHF mobile operations?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It goes out equally well in all horizontal directions",
        "id": "B-006-010-005",
        "options": [
            "It goes out equally well in all horizontal directions",
            "Most of it is aimed high into the sky",
            "Most of it goes equally in two opposite directions",
            "Most of it goes in one direction"
        ],
        "question": "If a magnetic-base whip antenna is placed on the roof of a car, in what direction does it send out radio energy?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It brings the feed point impedance closer to 50 ohms",
        "id": "B-006-010-006",
        "options": [
            "It brings the feed point impedance closer to 50 ohms",
            "It increases the radiation angle",
            "It brings the feed point impedance closer to 300 ohms",
            "It lowers the radiation angle"
        ],
        "question": "What is an advantage of downward sloping radials on a ground plane antenna?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It increases",
        "id": "B-006-010-007",
        "options": [
            "It increases",
            "It decreases",
            "It stays the same",
            "It approaches zero"
        ],
        "question": "What happens to the feed point impedance of a ground-plane antenna when its radials are changed from horizontal to downward-sloping?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "50 ohms coaxial cable",
        "id": "B-006-010-008",
        "options": [
            "50 ohms coaxial cable",
            "300 ohms balanced transmission line",
            "75 ohms balanced transmission line",
            "300 ohms coaxial cable"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following transmission lines will give the best match to the base of a quarter-wave ground-plane antenna?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "receive signals equally well from all compass points around it",
        "id": "B-006-010-009",
        "options": [
            "receive signals equally well from all compass points around it",
            "be very sensitive to signals coming from horizontal antennas",
            "require few insulators",
            "be easy to feed with TV ribbon transmission line"
        ],
        "question": "The main characteristic of a vertical antenna is that it will:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "To tune out capacitive reactance",
        "id": "B-006-010-010",
        "options": [
            "To tune out capacitive reactance",
            "To lower the losses",
            "To lower the Q",
            "To filter out electrical noise"
        ],
        "question": "Why is a loading coil often used with an HF mobile vertical antenna?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The angle of radiation is low",
        "id": "B-006-010-011",
        "options": [
            "The angle of radiation is low",
            "The angle of radiation is high giving excellent local coverage",
            "It is easy to match the antenna to the transmitter",
            "It's a convenient length on VHF"
        ],
        "question": "What is the main reason why so many VHF base and mobile antennas are 5/8 of a wavelength?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "One",
        "id": "B-006-011-001",
        "options": [
            "One",
            "Two",
            "Three",
            "None"
        ],
        "question": "How many directly driven elements do most Yagi antennas have?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "10.21 metres (33.5 feet)",
        "id": "B-006-011-002",
        "options": [
            "10.21 metres (33.5 feet)",
            "5.21 metres (17 feet)",
            "10.67 metres (35 feet)",
            "20.12 metres (66 feet)"
        ],
        "question": "Approximately how long is the driven element of a Yagi antenna for 14.0 MHz?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "6.4 metres (21 feet)",
        "id": "B-006-011-003",
        "options": [
            "6.4 metres (21 feet)",
            "5.18 metres (17 feet)",
            "3.2 metres (10.5 feet)",
            "12.8 metres (42 feet)"
        ],
        "question": "Approximately how long is the director element of a Yagi antenna for 21.1 MHz?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "5.33 metres (17.5 feet)",
        "id": "B-006-011-004",
        "options": [
            "5.33 metres (17.5 feet)",
            "4.88 metres (16 feet)",
            "10.67 metres (35 feet)",
            "2.66 metres (8.75 feet)"
        ],
        "question": "Approximately how long is the reflector element of a Yagi antenna for 28.1 MHz?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Gain increases",
        "id": "B-006-011-005",
        "options": [
            "Gain increases",
            "SWR increases",
            "Weight decreases",
            "Wind load decreases"
        ],
        "question": "What is one effect of increasing the boom length and adding directors to a Yagi antenna?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "High gain, less critical tuning and wider bandwidth",
        "id": "B-006-011-006",
        "options": [
            "High gain, less critical tuning and wider bandwidth",
            "High gain, lower loss and a low SWR",
            "High front-to-back ratio and lower input resistance",
            "Shorter boom length, lower weight and wind resistance"
        ],
        "question": "What are some advantages of a Yagi with wide element spacing?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It helps reduce interference from other stations off to the side or behind",
        "id": "B-006-011-007",
        "options": [
            "It helps reduce interference from other stations off to the side or behind",
            "It provides excellent omnidirectional coverage in the horizontal plane",
            "It is smaller, less expensive and easier to erect than a dipole or vertical antenna",
            "It provides the highest possible angle of radiation for the HF bands"
        ],
        "question": "Why is a Yagi antenna often used for radiocommunications on the 20-metre band?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The power radiated in the major radiation lobe compared to the power radiated in exactly the opposite direction",
        "id": "B-006-011-008",
        "options": [
            "The power radiated in the major radiation lobe compared to the power radiated in exactly the opposite direction",
            "The relative position of the driven element with respect to the reflectors and directors",
            "The power radiated in the major radiation lobe compared to the power radiated 90 degrees away from that direction",
            "The number of directors versus the number of reflectors"
        ],
        "question": "What does \"antenna front-to-back ratio\" mean in reference to a Yagi antenna?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Optimize the lengths and spacing of the elements",
        "id": "B-006-011-009",
        "options": [
            "Optimize the lengths and spacing of the elements",
            "Use RG-58 transmission line",
            "Use a reactance bridge to measure the antenna performance from each direction around the antenna",
            "Avoid using towers higher than 9 metres (30 feet) above the ground"
        ],
        "question": "What is a good way to get maximum performance from a Yagi antenna?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "0.20",
        "id": "B-006-011-010",
        "options": [
            "0.20",
            "0.10",
            "0.50",
            "0.75"
        ],
        "question": "The spacing between the elements on a three-element Yagi antenna, representing the best overall choice, is _____ of a wavelength."
    },
    {
        "answer": "13 dBi",
        "id": "B-006-011-011",
        "options": [
            "13 dBi",
            "7 dBi",
            "20 dBi",
            "10 dBi"
        ],
        "question": "If the forward gain of a six-element Yagi is about 10 dBi, what would the gain of two of these antennas be if they were \"stacked\"?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "5.08 metres (16.62 ft)",
        "id": "B-006-012-001",
        "options": [
            "5.08 metres (16.62 ft)",
            "10.5 metres (34.37 ft)",
            "28.55 metres (93.45 ft)",
            "10.16 metres (33.26 ft)"
        ],
        "question": "If you made a half-wavelength dipole antenna for 28.150 MHz, approximately how long would it be?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "You may experience RF feedback in your station",
        "id": "B-006-012-002",
        "options": [
            "You may experience RF feedback in your station",
            "It usually produces vertically polarized radiation",
            "It must be longer than 1 wavelength",
            "You must use an inverted T matching network for multi-band operation"
        ],
        "question": "What is one disadvantage of a random wire antenna?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It is a figure-eight, perpendicular to the antenna",
        "id": "B-006-012-003",
        "options": [
            "It is a figure-eight, perpendicular to the antenna",
            "It is a circle (equal radiation in all directions)",
            "It is two smaller lobes on one side of the antenna, and one larger lobe on the other side",
            "It is a figure-eight, off both ends of the antenna"
        ],
        "question": "What is the low angle radiation pattern of an ideal half-wavelength dipole HF antenna in free space installed parallel to the Earth?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "73 and 300",
        "id": "B-006-012-004",
        "options": [
            "73 and 300",
            "73 and 150",
            "52 and 100",
            "52 and 200"
        ],
        "question": "The impedances in ohms at the feed point of the dipole and folded dipole in free space are, respectively:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "mostly to the East and West",
        "id": "B-006-012-005",
        "options": [
            "mostly to the East and West",
            "mostly to the South and North",
            "mostly to the South",
            "equally in all directions"
        ],
        "question": "A horizontal dipole transmitting antenna, installed at an ideal height so that the ends are pointing North/South, radiates:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It is greater",
        "id": "B-006-012-006",
        "options": [
            "It is greater",
            "It is essentially the same",
            "It is less than 50%",
            "It is 0.707 times the bandwidth"
        ],
        "question": "How does the bandwidth of a folded dipole antenna compare with that of a simple dipole antenna?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It may radiate harmonics more readily",
        "id": "B-006-012-007",
        "options": [
            "It may radiate harmonics more readily",
            "It is too sharply directional at lower frequencies",
            "It must be neutralized",
            "It can only be used for one band"
        ],
        "question": "What is a disadvantage of using an antenna equipped with traps?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It may be used for multi-band operation",
        "id": "B-006-012-008",
        "options": [
            "It may be used for multi-band operation",
            "It has high directivity at the higher frequencies",
            "It has high gain",
            "It minimizes harmonic radiation"
        ],
        "question": "What is an advantage of using a trap antenna?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "38 meters (125 ft)",
        "id": "B-006-012-009",
        "options": [
            "38 meters (125 ft)",
            "32 meters (105 ft)",
            "45 meters (145 ft)",
            "75 meters (245 ft)"
        ],
        "question": "If you were to cut a half wave dipole for 3.75 MHz, what would be its approximate length?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Two or more parallel four-sided wire loops, each approximately one-electrical wavelength long",
        "id": "B-006-013-001",
        "options": [
            "Two or more parallel four-sided wire loops, each approximately one-electrical wavelength long",
            "A center-fed wire 1/2-electrical wavelength long",
            "A vertical conductor 1/4-electrical wavelength high, fed at the bottom",
            "Four straight, parallel elements in line with each other, each approximately 1/2-electrical wavelength long"
        ],
        "question": "What is a cubical quad antenna?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "An antenna whose elements are each a three sided loop whose total length is approximately one electrical wavelength",
        "id": "B-006-013-002",
        "options": [
            "An antenna whose elements are each a three sided loop whose total length is approximately one electrical wavelength",
            "A large copper ring or wire loop, used in direction finding",
            "An antenna system made of three vertical antennas, arranged in a triangular shape",
            "An antenna made from several triangular coils of wire on an insulating form"
        ],
        "question": "What is a delta loop antenna?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "3.54 metres (11.7 feet)",
        "id": "B-006-013-003",
        "options": [
            "3.54 metres (11.7 feet)",
            "0.36 metres (1.17 feet)",
            "14.33 metres (47 feet)",
            "143 metres (469 feet)"
        ],
        "question": "Approximately how long is each side of a cubical quad antenna driven element for 21.4 MHz?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "5.36 metres (17.6 feet)",
        "id": "B-006-013-004",
        "options": [
            "5.36 metres (17.6 feet)",
            "21.43 metres (70.3 feet)",
            "53.34 metres (175 feet)",
            "7.13 metres (23.4 feet)"
        ],
        "question": "Approximately how long is each side of a cubical quad antenna driven element for 14.3 MHz?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "3.32 metres (10.89 feet)",
        "id": "B-006-013-005",
        "options": [
            "3.32 metres (10.89 feet)",
            "2.67 metres (8.75 feet)",
            "7.13 metres (23.4 feet)",
            "10.67 metres (35 feet)"
        ],
        "question": "Approximately how long is each leg of a symmetrical delta loop antenna driven element for 28.7 MHz?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "They compare favourably with a three-element Yagi",
        "id": "B-006-013-006",
        "options": [
            "They compare favourably with a three-element Yagi",
            "They perform very well only at HF",
            "They are effective only when constructed using insulated wire",
            "They perform poorly above HF"
        ],
        "question": "Which statement about two-element delta loops and quad antennas is true?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The quad has more directivity in both horizontal and vertical planes",
        "id": "B-006-013-007",
        "options": [
            "The quad has more directivity in both horizontal and vertical planes",
            "The quad has more directivity in the horizontal plane but less directivity in the vertical plane",
            "The quad has less directivity in the horizontal plane but more directivity in the vertical plane",
            "The quad has less directivity in both horizontal and vertical planes"
        ],
        "question": "Compared to a dipole antenna, what are the directional radiation characteristics of a cubical quad antenna?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It will change the antenna polarization from horizontal to vertical",
        "id": "B-006-013-008",
        "options": [
            "It will change the antenna polarization from horizontal to vertical",
            "It will change the antenna polarization from vertical to horizontal",
            "It will significantly decrease the antenna feed point impedance",
            "It will significantly increase the antenna feed point impedance"
        ],
        "question": "Moving the feed point of a multi-element quad antenna from a side parallel to the ground to a side perpendicular to the ground will have what effect?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The power radiated in the major radiation lobe compared to the power radiated in exactly the opposite direction",
        "id": "B-006-013-009",
        "options": [
            "The power radiated in the major radiation lobe compared to the power radiated in exactly the opposite direction",
            "The relative position of the driven element with respect to the reflectors and directors",
            "The power radiated in the major radiation lobe compared to the power radiated 90 degrees away from that direction",
            "The number of directors versus the number of reflectors"
        ],
        "question": "What does the term \"antenna front-to-back ratio\" mean in reference to a delta loop antenna?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "one wavelength",
        "id": "B-006-013-010",
        "options": [
            "one wavelength",
            "three-quarters of a wavelength",
            "two wavelengths",
            "one-half wavelength"
        ],
        "question": "The cubical \"quad\" or \"quad\" antenna consists of two or more square loops of wire. The driven element has an approximate overall length of:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "one wavelength",
        "id": "B-006-013-011",
        "options": [
            "one wavelength",
            "one-quarter of a wavelength",
            "two wavelengths",
            "one-half of a wavelength"
        ],
        "question": "The delta loop antenna consists of two or more triangular structures mounted on a boom. The overall length of the driven element is approximately:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Line-of-sight propagation",
        "id": "B-007-001-001",
        "options": [
            "Line-of-sight propagation",
            "Tunnel propagation",
            "Skywave propagation",
            "Auroral propagation"
        ],
        "question": "What type of propagation usually occurs from one hand-held VHF transceiver to another nearby?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It is much longer",
        "id": "B-007-001-002",
        "options": [
            "It is much longer",
            "It is much shorter",
            "It is about the same",
            "It depends on the weather"
        ],
        "question": "How does the range of sky-wave propagation compare to ground-wave propagation?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Sky-wave propagation",
        "id": "B-007-001-003",
        "options": [
            "Sky-wave propagation",
            "Tropospheric propagation",
            "Ground-wave propagation",
            "Earth-Moon-Earth propagation"
        ],
        "question": "When a signal is returned to Earth by the ionosphere, what is this called?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "By direct wave",
        "id": "B-007-001-004",
        "options": [
            "By direct wave",
            "By sky wave",
            "By plane wave",
            "By geometric wave"
        ],
        "question": "How are VHF signals propagated within the range of the visible horizon?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "ionospheric wave",
        "id": "B-007-001-005",
        "options": [
            "ionospheric wave",
            "tropospheric wave",
            "ground wave",
            "inverted wave"
        ],
        "question": "Skywave is another name for:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "ground wave",
        "id": "B-007-001-006",
        "options": [
            "ground wave",
            "tropospheric wave",
            "ionospheric wave",
            "inverted wave"
        ],
        "question": "That portion of the radiation which is directly affected by the surface of the Earth is called:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "ground wave",
        "id": "B-007-001-007",
        "options": [
            "ground wave",
            "troposphere",
            "skip wave",
            "ionosphere"
        ],
        "question": "At lower HF frequencies, radiocommunication out to 200 km is made possible by:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "is less at higher frequencies",
        "id": "B-007-001-008",
        "options": [
            "is less at higher frequencies",
            "depends on the maximum usable frequency",
            "is more at higher frequencies",
            "is the same for all frequencies"
        ],
        "question": "The distance travelled by ground waves:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "ionospheric wave",
        "id": "B-007-001-009",
        "options": [
            "ionospheric wave",
            "F layer",
            "surface wave",
            "skip wave"
        ],
        "question": "The radio wave which follows a path from the transmitter to the ionosphere and back to Earth is known correctly as the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "ionospheric wave",
        "id": "B-007-001-010",
        "options": [
            "ionospheric wave",
            "ground wave",
            "skip wave",
            "surface wave"
        ],
        "question": "Reception of high frequency (HF) radio waves beyond 4000 km is generally made possible by:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Solar radiation ionizing the outer atmosphere",
        "id": "B-007-002-001",
        "options": [
            "Solar radiation ionizing the outer atmosphere",
            "Lightning ionizing the outer atmosphere",
            "Release of fluorocarbons into the atmosphere",
            "Temperature changes ionizing the outer atmosphere"
        ],
        "question": "What causes the ionosphere to form?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Ultraviolet",
        "id": "B-007-002-002",
        "options": [
            "Ultraviolet",
            "Microwave",
            "Ionized particles",
            "Thermal"
        ],
        "question": "What type of solar radiation is most responsible for ionization in the outer atmosphere?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The D region",
        "id": "B-007-002-003",
        "options": [
            "The D region",
            "The E region",
            "The F region",
            "The A region"
        ],
        "question": "Which ionospheric region is closest to the Earth?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The D region",
        "id": "B-007-002-004",
        "options": [
            "The D region",
            "The F2 region",
            "The F1 region",
            "The E region"
        ],
        "question": "Which region of the ionosphere is the least useful for long distance radio-wave propagation?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "F1 and F2",
        "id": "B-007-002-005",
        "options": [
            "F1 and F2",
            "Troposphere and stratosphere",
            "Electrostatic and electromagnetic",
            "D and E"
        ],
        "question": "What two sub-regions of ionosphere exist only in the daytime?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Midday",
        "id": "B-007-002-006",
        "options": [
            "Midday",
            "Dawn",
            "Midnight",
            "Dusk"
        ],
        "question": "When is the ionosphere most ionized?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Shortly before dawn",
        "id": "B-007-002-007",
        "options": [
            "Shortly before dawn",
            "Just after noon",
            "Just after dusk",
            "Shortly before midnight"
        ],
        "question": "When is the ionosphere least ionized?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Because it is the highest ionospheric region",
        "id": "B-007-002-008",
        "options": [
            "Because it is the highest ionospheric region",
            "Because it exists only at night",
            "Because it is the lowest ionospheric region",
            "Because it does not absorb radio waves as much as other ionospheric regions"
        ],
        "question": "Why is the F2 region mainly responsible for the longest distance radio-wave propagation?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Because of D-region absorption",
        "id": "B-007-002-009",
        "options": [
            "Because of D-region absorption",
            "Because of auroral propagation",
            "Because of magnetic flux",
            "Because of a lack of activity"
        ],
        "question": "What is the main reason the 160, 80 and 40 metre amateur bands tend to be useful only for short-distance communications during daylight hours?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "F1 and F2",
        "id": "B-007-002-010",
        "options": [
            "F1 and F2",
            "D1 and D2",
            "E1 and E2",
            "A and B"
        ],
        "question": "During the day, one of the ionospheric layers splits into two parts called:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "below the F layer",
        "id": "B-007-002-011",
        "options": [
            "below the F layer",
            "below the D layer",
            "sporadic",
            "above the F layer"
        ],
        "question": "The position of the E layer in the ionosphere is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "An area which is too far away for ground-wave propagation, but too close for sky-wave propagation",
        "id": "B-007-003-001",
        "options": [
            "An area which is too far away for ground-wave propagation, but too close for sky-wave propagation",
            "An area which is too far away for ground-wave or sky-wave propagation",
            "An area covered by sky-wave propagation",
            "An area covered by ground-wave propagation"
        ],
        "question": "What is a skip zone?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "4000 km (2500 miles)",
        "id": "B-007-003-002",
        "options": [
            "4000 km (2500 miles)",
            "None, the F2 region does not support radio-wave propagation",
            "2000 km (1250 miles)",
            "300 km (190 miles)"
        ],
        "question": "What is the maximum distance along the Earth's surface that is normally covered in one hop using the F2 region?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "2000 km (1250 miles)",
        "id": "B-007-003-003",
        "options": [
            "2000 km (1250 miles)",
            "300 km (190 miles)",
            "4000 km (2500 miles)",
            "None, the E region does not support radio-wave propagation"
        ],
        "question": "What is the maximum distance along the Earth's surface that is normally covered in one hop using the E region?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "a zone between the end of the ground wave and the point where the first refracted wave returns to Earth",
        "id": "B-007-003-004",
        "options": [
            "a zone between the end of the ground wave and the point where the first refracted wave returns to Earth",
            "a zone of silence caused by lost sky waves",
            "a zone between any two refracted waves",
            "a zone between the antenna and the return of the first refracted wave"
        ],
        "question": "Skip zone is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Multihop",
        "id": "B-007-003-005",
        "options": [
            "Multihop",
            "Sporadic \"E\"",
            "Back scatter",
            "Tropospheric scatter"
        ],
        "question": "The distance to Europe from your location is approximately 5000 km. What sort of propagation is the most likely to be involved?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "height of the ionosphere and the angle of radiation",
        "id": "B-007-003-006",
        "options": [
            "height of the ionosphere and the angle of radiation",
            "power fed to the power amplifier",
            "angle of radiation",
            "type of transmitting antenna used"
        ],
        "question": "For radio signals, the skip distance is determined by the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "skip distance",
        "id": "B-007-003-007",
        "options": [
            "skip distance",
            "skip zone",
            "angle of radiation",
            "maximum usable frequency"
        ],
        "question": "The distance from the transmitter to the nearest point where the sky wave returns to the Earth is called the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "the minimum distance reached by a signal after one reflection by the ionosphere",
        "id": "B-007-003-008",
        "options": [
            "the minimum distance reached by a signal after one reflection by the ionosphere",
            "the maximum distance reached by a signal after one reflection by the ionosphere",
            "the minimum distance reached by a ground-wave signal",
            "the maximum distance a signal will travel by both a ground wave and reflected wave"
        ],
        "question": "Skip distance is the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "reflection and refraction from the ionosphere",
        "id": "B-007-003-009",
        "options": [
            "reflection and refraction from the ionosphere",
            "selective fading of local signals",
            "high gain antennas being used",
            "local cloud cover"
        ],
        "question": "Skip distance is a term associated with signals from the ionosphere. Skip effects are due to:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "angle between the ground and the radiation is smallest",
        "id": "B-007-003-010",
        "options": [
            "angle between the ground and the radiation is smallest",
            "polarization is vertical",
            "ionosphere is most densely ionized",
            "signal given out is strongest"
        ],
        "question": "The skip distance of a sky wave will be greatest when the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "becomes greater",
        "id": "B-007-003-011",
        "options": [
            "becomes greater",
            "stays the same",
            "varies regularly",
            "decreases"
        ],
        "question": "If the height of the reflecting layer of the ionosphere increases, the skip distance of a high frequency (HF) transmission:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It absorbs the signals",
        "id": "B-007-004-001",
        "options": [
            "It absorbs the signals",
            "It bends the radio waves out into space",
            "It refracts the radio waves back to Earth",
            "It has little or no effect on 80-metre radio waves"
        ],
        "question": "What effect does the D region of the ionosphere have on lower frequency HF signals in the daytime?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The ionization of the D region",
        "id": "B-007-004-002",
        "options": [
            "The ionization of the D region",
            "The presence of ionized clouds in the E region",
            "The splitting of the F region",
            "The weather below the ionosphere"
        ],
        "question": "What causes distant AM broadcast and 160 metre ham band stations not to be heard during daytime hours?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "fading",
        "id": "B-007-004-003",
        "options": [
            "fading",
            "baffling",
            "absorption",
            "skip"
        ],
        "question": "Two or more parts of the radio wave follow different paths during propagation and this may result in phase differences at the receiver. This \"change\" at the receiver is called:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "fading",
        "id": "B-007-004-004",
        "options": [
            "fading",
            "absorption",
            "fluctuation",
            "path loss"
        ],
        "question": "A change or variation in signal strength at the antenna, caused by differences in path lengths, is called:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "variations in signal strength",
        "id": "B-007-004-005",
        "options": [
            "variations in signal strength",
            "consistent fading of received signal",
            "consistently stronger signals",
            "a change in the ground-wave signal"
        ],
        "question": "When a transmitted radio signal reaches a station by a one-hop and two-hop skip path, small changes in the ionosphere can cause:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "cause a fade-out of sky-wave signals",
        "id": "B-007-004-006",
        "options": [
            "cause a fade-out of sky-wave signals",
            "produce extreme weather changes",
            "prevent communications by ground wave",
            "increase the maximum usable frequency"
        ],
        "question": "The usual effect of ionospheric storms is to:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The ionosphere can change the polarization of the signal from moment to moment",
        "id": "B-007-004-007",
        "options": [
            "The ionosphere can change the polarization of the signal from moment to moment",
            "The ground wave and the sky wave continually shift the polarization",
            "Anomalies in the Earth's magnetic field produce a profound effect on HF polarization but not on VHF & UHF frequencies",
            "Greater selectivity is possible with HF receivers making changes in polarization redundant"
        ],
        "question": "On the VHF and UHF bands, polarization of the receiving antenna is very important in relation to the transmitting antenna, yet on HF bands it is relatively unimportant. Why is that so?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Phase differences between radio wave components of the same transmission, as experienced at the receiving station",
        "id": "B-007-004-008",
        "options": [
            "Phase differences between radio wave components of the same transmission, as experienced at the receiving station",
            "Small changes in beam heading at the receiving station",
            "Time differences between the receiving and transmitting stations",
            "Large changes in the height of the ionosphere at the receiving station ordinarily occurring shortly before sunrise and sunset"
        ],
        "question": "What causes selective fading?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It is more pronounced at wide bandwidths",
        "id": "B-007-004-009",
        "options": [
            "It is more pronounced at wide bandwidths",
            "It is the same for both wide and narrow bandwidths",
            "Only the receiver bandwidth determines the selective fading effect",
            "It is more pronounced at narrow bandwidths"
        ],
        "question": "How does the bandwidth of a transmitted signal affect selective fading?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Parabolic interaction",
        "id": "B-007-004-010",
        "options": [
            "Parabolic interaction",
            "Reflections",
            "Passage through magnetic fields (Faraday rotation)",
            "Refractions"
        ],
        "question": "Polarization change often takes place on radio waves that are propagated over long distances. Which of these does not cause polarization change?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "little or no phase-shift distortion",
        "id": "B-007-004-011",
        "options": [
            "little or no phase-shift distortion",
            "phase-shift distortion",
            "signal cancellation at the receiver",
            "a high-pitch squeal at the receiver"
        ],
        "question": "Reflection of a SSB transmission from the ionosphere causes:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The more sunspots there are, the greater the ionization",
        "id": "B-007-005-001",
        "options": [
            "The more sunspots there are, the greater the ionization",
            "The more sunspots there are, the less the ionization",
            "Unless there are sunspots, the ionization is zero",
            "They have no effect"
        ],
        "question": "How do sunspots change the ionization of the atmosphere?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "11 years",
        "id": "B-007-005-002",
        "options": [
            "11 years",
            "17 years",
            "5 years",
            "7 years"
        ],
        "question": "How long is an average sunspot cycle?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The radio energy emitted by the sun",
        "id": "B-007-005-003",
        "options": [
            "The radio energy emitted by the sun",
            "A measure of the tilt of the Earth's ionosphere on the side toward the sun",
            "The number of sunspots on the side of the sun facing the Earth",
            "The density of the sun's magnetic field"
        ],
        "question": "What is solar flux?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A measure of solar activity that is taken at a specific frequency",
        "id": "B-007-005-004",
        "options": [
            "A measure of solar activity that is taken at a specific frequency",
            "Another name for the American sunspot number",
            "A measure of solar activity that compares daily readings with results from the last six months",
            "A measure of solar activity that is taken annually"
        ],
        "question": "What is the solar-flux index?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Solar radiation",
        "id": "B-007-005-005",
        "options": [
            "Solar radiation",
            "The F2 region of the ionosphere",
            "The F1 region of the ionosphere",
            "Lunar tidal effects"
        ],
        "question": "What influences all radiocommunication beyond ground-wave or line-of-sight ranges?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Electromagnetic and particle emissions",
        "id": "B-007-005-006",
        "options": [
            "Electromagnetic and particle emissions",
            "Subaudible and audio-frequency emissions",
            "Polar region and equatorial emissions",
            "Infrared and gamma-ray emissions"
        ],
        "question": "Which two types of radiation from the sun influence propagation?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Frequencies up to 40 MHz or even higher become usable for long-distance communication",
        "id": "B-007-005-007",
        "options": [
            "Frequencies up to 40 MHz or even higher become usable for long-distance communication",
            "High frequency radio signals are absorbed",
            "Frequencies up to 100 MHz or higher are normally usable for long-distance communication",
            "High frequency radio signals become weak and distorted"
        ],
        "question": "When sunspot numbers are high, how is propagation affected?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "sun",
        "id": "B-007-005-008",
        "options": [
            "sun",
            "ionosphere",
            "aurora borealis",
            "atmospheric conditions"
        ],
        "question": "All communication frequencies throughout the spectrum are affected in varying degrees by the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "11 years",
        "id": "B-007-005-009",
        "options": [
            "11 years",
            "3 years",
            "6 years",
            "1 year"
        ],
        "question": "Average duration of a solar cycle is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "the amount of solar radiation",
        "id": "B-007-005-010",
        "options": [
            "the amount of solar radiation",
            "the power of the transmitted signal",
            "the receiver sensitivity",
            "upper atmosphere weather conditions"
        ],
        "question": "The ability of the ionosphere to reflect high frequency radio signals depends on:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "years",
        "id": "B-007-005-011",
        "options": [
            "years",
            "months",
            "days",
            "centuries"
        ],
        "question": "HF radio propagation cycles have a period of approximately 11:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "They pass through the ionosphere",
        "id": "B-007-006-001",
        "options": [
            "They pass through the ionosphere",
            "They are absorbed by the ionosphere",
            "Their frequency is changed by the ionosphere to be below the maximum usable frequency",
            "They are reflected back to their source"
        ],
        "question": "What happens to signals higher in frequency than the critical frequency?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The amount of radiation received from the sun, mainly ultraviolet",
        "id": "B-007-006-002",
        "options": [
            "The amount of radiation received from the sun, mainly ultraviolet",
            "The temperature of the ionosphere",
            "The speed of the winds in the upper atmosphere",
            "The type of weather just below the ionosphere"
        ],
        "question": "What causes the maximum usable frequency to vary?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The highest frequency signal that will reach its intended destination",
        "id": "B-007-006-003",
        "options": [
            "The highest frequency signal that will reach its intended destination",
            "The lowest frequency signal that will reach its intended destination",
            "The highest frequency signal that is most absorbed by the ionosphere",
            "The lowest frequency signal that is most absorbed by the ionosphere"
        ],
        "question": "What does maximum usable frequency mean?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Try a higher frequency band",
        "id": "B-007-006-004",
        "options": [
            "Try a higher frequency band",
            "Try the other sideband",
            "Try a different antenna polarization",
            "Try a different frequency shift"
        ],
        "question": "What can be done at an amateur station to continue HF communications during a sudden ionospheric disturbance?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Listen for signals from 10-metre beacon stations",
        "id": "B-007-006-005",
        "options": [
            "Listen for signals from 10-metre beacon stations",
            "Listen for signals from 20-metre beacon stations",
            "Listen for signals from 39-metre broadcast stations",
            "Listen for WWVH time signals on 20 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "What is one way to determine if the maximum usable frequency (MUF) is high enough to support 28 MHz propagation between your station and western Europe?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "They are bent back to the Earth",
        "id": "B-007-006-006",
        "options": [
            "They are bent back to the Earth",
            "They are changed to a frequency above the MUF",
            "They are completely absorbed by the ionosphere",
            "They pass through the ionosphere"
        ],
        "question": "What usually happens to radio waves with frequencies below the maximum usable frequency (MUF) when they are sent into the ionosphere?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "At any point in the solar cycle",
        "id": "B-007-006-007",
        "options": [
            "At any point in the solar cycle",
            "Only at the minimum point of the solar cycle",
            "Only at the maximum point of the solar cycle",
            "At the summer solstice"
        ],
        "question": "At what point in the solar cycle does the 20-metre band usually support worldwide propagation during daylight hours?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "maximum usable frequency",
        "id": "B-007-006-008",
        "options": [
            "maximum usable frequency",
            "skip distance",
            "speed of light",
            "sunspot frequency"
        ],
        "question": "If we transmit a signal, the frequency of which is so high we no longer receive a reflection from the ionosphere, the signal frequency is above the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "daytime in summer",
        "id": "B-007-006-009",
        "options": [
            "daytime in summer",
            "evening in winter",
            "evening in summer",
            "daytime in winter"
        ],
        "question": "Communication on the 80 metre band is generally most difficult during:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "slightly lower",
        "id": "B-007-006-010",
        "options": [
            "slightly lower",
            "double the MUF",
            "half the MUF",
            "slightly higher"
        ],
        "question": "The optimum working frequency provides the best long range HF communication. Compared with the maximum usable frequency (MUF), it is usually:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "160 and 80 metres",
        "id": "B-007-006-011",
        "options": [
            "160 and 80 metres",
            "40 metres",
            "30 metres",
            "20 metres"
        ],
        "question": "During summer daytime, which bands are the most difficult for communications beyond ground wave?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The E region",
        "id": "B-007-007-001",
        "options": [
            "The E region",
            "The F2 region",
            "The F1 region",
            "The D region"
        ],
        "question": "Which ionospheric region most affects sky-wave propagation on the 6 metre band?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It lets you contact stations farther away",
        "id": "B-007-007-002",
        "options": [
            "It lets you contact stations farther away",
            "It causes them to travel shorter distances",
            "It garbles the signal",
            "It reverses the sideband of the signal"
        ],
        "question": "What effect does tropospheric bending have on 2-metre radio waves?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A temperature inversion",
        "id": "B-007-007-003",
        "options": [
            "A temperature inversion",
            "Lightning between the transmitting and receiving stations",
            "An aurora to the north",
            "A very low pressure area"
        ],
        "question": "What causes tropospheric ducting of radio waves?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "tropospheric wave",
        "id": "B-007-007-004",
        "options": [
            "tropospheric wave",
            "inverted wave",
            "ground wave",
            "ionospheric wave"
        ],
        "question": "That portion of the radiation kept close to the Earth's surface due to bending in the atmosphere is called the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Patches of dense ionization at E-region height",
        "id": "B-007-007-005",
        "options": [
            "Patches of dense ionization at E-region height",
            "Partial tropospheric ducting at E-region height",
            "Variations in E-region height caused by sunspot variations",
            "A brief decrease in VHF signals caused by sunspot variations"
        ],
        "question": "What is a sporadic-E condition?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "6 metres",
        "id": "B-007-007-006",
        "options": [
            "6 metres",
            "160 metres",
            "20 metres",
            "2 metres"
        ],
        "question": "On which amateur frequency band is the extended-distance propagation effect of sporadic-E most often observed?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "North",
        "id": "B-007-007-007",
        "options": [
            "North",
            "East",
            "West",
            "South"
        ],
        "question": "In the northern hemisphere, in which direction should a directional antenna be pointed to take maximum advantage of auroral propagation?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "At E-region height",
        "id": "B-007-007-008",
        "options": [
            "At E-region height",
            "At F-region height",
            "In the equatorial band",
            "At D-region height"
        ],
        "question": "Where in the ionosphere does auroral activity occur?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "CW",
        "id": "B-007-007-009",
        "options": [
            "CW",
            "RTTY",
            "FM",
            "SSB"
        ],
        "question": "Which emission mode is best for auroral propagation?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "800 km (500 miles)",
        "id": "B-007-007-010",
        "options": [
            "800 km (500 miles)",
            "2400 km (1500 miles)",
            "3200 km (2000 miles)",
            "1600 km (1000 miles)"
        ],
        "question": "Excluding enhanced propagation modes, what is the approximate range of normal VHF tropospheric propagation?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Tropospheric ducting",
        "id": "B-007-007-011",
        "options": [
            "Tropospheric ducting",
            "Faraday rotation",
            "D-region absorption",
            "Moon bounce (EME) Earth - Moon - Earth"
        ],
        "question": "What effect is responsible for propagating a VHF signal over 800 km (500 miles)?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Scatter-mode",
        "id": "B-007-008-001",
        "options": [
            "Scatter-mode",
            "Sky-wave with low radiation angle",
            "Ducting",
            "Ground-wave"
        ],
        "question": "What kind of unusual HF propagation allows weak signals from the skip zone to be heard occasionally?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Scatter",
        "id": "B-007-008-002",
        "options": [
            "Scatter",
            "Ground-wave",
            "Line-of-sight",
            "Ducting"
        ],
        "question": "If you receive a weak, distorted signal from a distance, and close to the maximum usable frequency, what type of propagation is probably occurring?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Rapid flutter or hollow sounding distortion",
        "id": "B-007-008-003",
        "options": [
            "Rapid flutter or hollow sounding distortion",
            "Reversed modulation",
            "Reversed sidebands",
            "High intelligibility"
        ],
        "question": "What is a characteristic of HF scatter signals?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Energy scattered into the skip zone through several radio-wave paths",
        "id": "B-007-008-004",
        "options": [
            "Energy scattered into the skip zone through several radio-wave paths",
            "Auroral activity and changes in the Earth's magnetic field",
            "Propagation through ground waves that absorb much of the signal",
            "The state of the E-region at the point of refraction"
        ],
        "question": "What makes HF scatter signals often sound distorted?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Only a small part of the signal energy is scattered into the skip zone",
        "id": "B-007-008-005",
        "options": [
            "Only a small part of the signal energy is scattered into the skip zone",
            "Propagation through ground waves absorbs most of the signal energy",
            "The F region of the ionosphere absorbs most of the signal energy",
            "Auroral activity absorbs most of the signal energy"
        ],
        "question": "Why are HF scatter signals usually weak?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Scatter",
        "id": "B-007-008-006",
        "options": [
            "Scatter",
            "Short-path skip",
            "Sporadic-E skip",
            "Ground wave"
        ],
        "question": "What type of propagation may allow a weak signal to be heard at a distance too far for ground-wave propagation but too near for normal sky-wave propagation?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "When weak and distorted signals near or above the maximum usable frequency for normal propagation can be heard over unusual paths",
        "id": "B-007-008-007",
        "options": [
            "When weak and distorted signals near or above the maximum usable frequency for normal propagation can be heard over unusual paths",
            "When the sunspot cycle is at a minimum and D-region absorption is high",
            "At night",
            "When the F1 and F2 regions are combined"
        ],
        "question": "On the HF bands, when is scatter propagation most likely involved?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Absorption scatter",
        "id": "B-007-008-008",
        "options": [
            "Absorption scatter",
            "Meteor scatter",
            "Tropospheric scatter",
            "Ionospheric scatter"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following is not a scatter mode?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "6 metres",
        "id": "B-007-008-009",
        "options": [
            "6 metres",
            "40 metres",
            "15 metres",
            "160 metres"
        ],
        "question": "Meteor scatter is most effective on what band?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Inverted scatter",
        "id": "B-007-008-010",
        "options": [
            "Inverted scatter",
            "Side scatter",
            "Back scatter",
            "Forward scatter"
        ],
        "question": "Which of the following is not a scatter mode?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "30 - 100 MHz",
        "id": "B-007-008-011",
        "options": [
            "30 - 100 MHz",
            "10 - 30 MHz",
            "3 - 10 MHz",
            "100 - 300 MHz"
        ],
        "question": "In which frequency range is meteor scatter most effective for extended-range communication?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Interference caused by strong signals from a nearby transmitter",
        "id": "B-008-001-001",
        "options": [
            "Interference caused by strong signals from a nearby transmitter",
            "Interference caused by turning the volume up too high",
            "Too much current from the power supply",
            "Too much voltage from the power supply"
        ],
        "question": "What is meant by receiver overload?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "If the interference is about the same no matter what frequency is used for the transmitter",
        "id": "B-008-001-002",
        "options": [
            "If the interference is about the same no matter what frequency is used for the transmitter",
            "If grounding the receiver makes the problem worse",
            "If connecting a low pass filter to the receiver greatly cuts down the interference",
            "If connecting a low pass filter to the transmitter greatly cuts down the interference"
        ],
        "question": "What is one way to tell if radio frequency interference to a receiver is caused by front-end overload?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Receiver overload",
        "id": "B-008-001-003",
        "options": [
            "Receiver overload",
            "Incorrect antenna length",
            "Receiver VR tube discharge",
            "Too little transmitter harmonic suppression"
        ],
        "question": "If a neighbour reports television interference whenever you transmit, no matter what band you use, what is probably the cause of the interference?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "High-pass",
        "id": "B-008-001-004",
        "options": [
            "High-pass",
            "Low-pass",
            "Band-pass",
            "No filter"
        ],
        "question": "What type of filter should be connected to a TV receiver as the first step in trying to prevent RF overload from an amateur HF station transmission?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Receiver desensitization",
        "id": "B-008-001-005",
        "options": [
            "Receiver desensitization",
            "Both stations are fed from the same generator",
            "Improper station grounding",
            "Harmonic radiation"
        ],
        "question": "During a club ARRL Field Day outing, reception on the 20 m SSB station is compromised every time the 20 m CW station is on the air. What might cause such interference?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "the undesired signal in the background of the desired signal",
        "id": "B-008-001-006",
        "options": [
            "the undesired signal in the background of the desired signal",
            "interference only when a broadcast signal is tuned",
            "distortion on transmitted voice peaks",
            "interference continuously across the dial"
        ],
        "question": "Inter-modulation in a broadcast receiver by a nearby transmitter would be noticed in the receiver as:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Receiver intermodulation interference",
        "id": "B-008-001-007",
        "options": [
            "Receiver intermodulation interference",
            "Harmonic interference from other stations",
            "Audio stage overload interference",
            "Audio stage intermodulation interference"
        ],
        "question": "You have connected your hand-held VHF transceiver to an outside gain antenna. You now hear a mixture of signals together with different modulation on your desired frequency. What is the nature of this interference?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Intermodulation interference",
        "id": "B-008-001-008",
        "options": [
            "Intermodulation interference",
            "Receiver quieting",
            "Capture effect",
            "Front-end desensitization"
        ],
        "question": "Two or more strong out-of-band signals mix in your receiver to produce interference on a desired frequency. What is this called?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The strong signal of one mobile transmitter may desensitize the receiver of the other mobile receiver",
        "id": "B-008-001-009",
        "options": [
            "The strong signal of one mobile transmitter may desensitize the receiver of the other mobile receiver",
            "Simplex operation does not require the use of CTCSS tones",
            "There is less time delay using simplex operation compared to using a repeater",
            "There are many more simplex frequencies than repeater frequencies available"
        ],
        "question": "Two mobile stations are traveling along the same road in close proximity to each other and having trouble communicating through a local repeater. Why may it be necessary to use simplex operation to communicate between these cars?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Insert a high pass filter at the antenna connector of the television",
        "id": "B-008-001-010",
        "options": [
            "Insert a high pass filter at the antenna connector of the television",
            "Insert a low pass filter at the antenna connector of the HF transmitter",
            "Insert a high pass filter at the antenna connector of the HF transmitter",
            "Insert a low pass filter at the antenna connector of the television"
        ],
        "question": "A television receiver suffers interference on channel 5 (76 - 82 MHz) only when you transmit on 14 MHz. From your home you see the tower of a commercial FM station known to broadcast on 92.5 MHz. Which of these solutions would you try first?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "By installing a suitable filter at the receiver",
        "id": "B-008-001-011",
        "options": [
            "By installing a suitable filter at the receiver",
            "By using a better antenna",
            "By increasing the receiver RF gain while decreasing the AF gain",
            "By adjusting the passband tuning"
        ],
        "question": "How can intermodulation be reduced?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Coils on ferrite cores",
        "id": "B-008-002-001",
        "options": [
            "Coils on ferrite cores",
            "Bypass resistors",
            "Metal-oxide varistors",
            "Bypass inductors"
        ],
        "question": "What devices would you install to reduce or eliminate audio-frequency interference to home entertainment systems?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Install a modular plug-in telephone RFI filter close to the telephone device",
        "id": "B-008-002-002",
        "options": [
            "Install a modular plug-in telephone RFI filter close to the telephone device",
            "Ground and shield the local telephone distribution amplifier",
            "Stop transmitting whenever the telephone is in use",
            "Make internal adjustments to the telephone equipment"
        ],
        "question": "What should be done if a properly operating amateur station is the cause of interference to a nearby telephone?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Distorted speech from the transmitter's signals",
        "id": "B-008-002-003",
        "options": [
            "Distorted speech from the transmitter's signals",
            "Clearly audible speech from the transmitter's signals",
            "On-and-off humming or clicking",
            "A steady hum whenever the transmitter's carrier is on the air"
        ],
        "question": "What sound is heard from a public-address system if audio rectification of a nearby single-sideband phone transmission occurs?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "On-and-off humming or clicking",
        "id": "B-008-002-004",
        "options": [
            "On-and-off humming or clicking",
            "Audible, possibly distorted speech",
            "Muffled, severely distorted speech",
            "A steady whistling"
        ],
        "question": "What sound is heard from a public-address system if audio rectification of a nearby CW transmission occurs?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Ensure that all station equipment is properly grounded",
        "id": "B-008-002-005",
        "options": [
            "Ensure that all station equipment is properly grounded",
            "Install bypass capacitors on all power supply rectifiers",
            "Use CW only",
            "Use a solid-state transmitter"
        ],
        "question": "How can you minimize the possibility of audio rectification of your transmitter's signals?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "audio rectification in the receiver",
        "id": "B-008-002-006",
        "options": [
            "audio rectification in the receiver",
            "harmonics interference from the transmitter",
            "poor image rejection",
            "splatter from the transmitter"
        ],
        "question": "An amateur transmitter is being heard across the entire dial of a broadcast receiver. The receiver is most probably suffering from:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Audio rectification of strong signals",
        "id": "B-008-002-007",
        "options": [
            "Audio rectification of strong signals",
            "Harmonics generated at the transmitter",
            "Improper filtering in the transmitter",
            "Lack of receiver sensitivity and selectivity"
        ],
        "question": "Your SSB HF transmissions are heard muffled on a sound system in the living room regardless of its volume setting. What causes this?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Ferrite core",
        "id": "B-008-002-008",
        "options": [
            "Ferrite core",
            "Magnet",
            "Attenuator",
            "Diode"
        ],
        "question": "What device can be used to minimize the effect of RF pickup by audio wires connected to stereo speakers, intercom amplifiers, telephones, etc.?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Shorten the leads",
        "id": "B-008-002-009",
        "options": [
            "Shorten the leads",
            "Lengthen the leads",
            "Connect the speaker through an audio attenuator",
            "Connect a diode across the speaker"
        ],
        "question": "Stereo speaker leads often act as antennas to pick up RF signals. What is one method you can use to minimize this effect?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "through a ferrite core",
        "id": "B-008-002-010",
        "options": [
            "through a ferrite core",
            "around a copper bar",
            "around an iron bar",
            "around a wooden dowel"
        ],
        "question": "One method of preventing RF from entering a stereo set through the speaker leads is to wrap each of the speaker leads:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "receiving antennas",
        "id": "B-008-002-011",
        "options": [
            "receiving antennas",
            "transmitting antennas",
            "RF attenuators",
            "frequency discriminators"
        ],
        "question": "Stereo amplifiers often have long leads which pick up transmitted signals because they act as:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "By using a key-click filter",
        "id": "B-008-003-001",
        "options": [
            "By using a key-click filter",
            "By increasing power",
            "By using a better power supply",
            "By sending CW more slowly"
        ],
        "question": "How can you prevent key-clicks?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Your hand-held is transmitting spurious emissions",
        "id": "B-008-003-002",
        "options": [
            "Your hand-held is transmitting spurious emissions",
            "You need a power amplifier for your hand-held",
            "Your hand-held has a chirp from weak batteries",
            "You need to turn the volume up on your hand-held"
        ],
        "question": "If someone tells you that signals from your hand-held transceiver are interfering with other signals on a frequency near yours, what could be the cause?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Spurious emissions",
        "id": "B-008-003-003",
        "options": [
            "Spurious emissions",
            "Side tones",
            "Transmitter chirping",
            "Off-frequency emissions"
        ],
        "question": "If your transmitter sends signals outside the band where it is transmitting, what is this called?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It may radiate spurious emissions",
        "id": "B-008-003-004",
        "options": [
            "It may radiate spurious emissions",
            "It may transmit a weak signal",
            "It may interfere with other stations operating near its frequency",
            "It may transmit a chirpy signal"
        ],
        "question": "What problem may occur if your transmitter is operated without the cover and other shielding in place?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "the making and breaking of the circuit at the Morse key",
        "id": "B-008-003-005",
        "options": [
            "the making and breaking of the circuit at the Morse key",
            "frequency shifting caused by poor voltage regulation",
            "the power amplifier, and is caused by high frequency parasitic oscillations",
            "poor waveshaping caused by a poor voltage regulator"
        ],
        "question": "In Morse code transmission, local RF interference (key-clicks) is produced by:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "too sharp rise and decay times of the keyed carrier",
        "id": "B-008-003-006",
        "options": [
            "too sharp rise and decay times of the keyed carrier",
            "power supply hum modulating the carrier",
            "sparks emitting RF from the key contacts",
            "changes in oscillator frequency on keying"
        ],
        "question": "Key-clicks, heard from a Morse code transmitter at a distant receiver, are the result of:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "poor shaping of the waveform",
        "id": "B-008-003-007",
        "options": [
            "poor shaping of the waveform",
            "shift in frequency when keying the transmitter",
            "sparking at the key contacts",
            "sudden movement in the receiver loudspeaker"
        ],
        "question": "In a Morse code transmission, broad bandwidth RF interference (key-clicks) heard at a distance is produced by:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Check the keying filter and the functioning of later stages",
        "id": "B-008-003-008",
        "options": [
            "Check the keying filter and the functioning of later stages",
            "Turn the receiver down",
            "Regulate the oscillator supply voltage",
            "Use a choke in the RF power output"
        ],
        "question": "What should you do if you learn your transmitter is producing key clicks?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "is an unwanted signal developed in a transmitter",
        "id": "B-008-003-009",
        "options": [
            "is an unwanted signal developed in a transmitter",
            "is generated by parasitic elements of a Yagi beam",
            "does not cause any radio interference",
            "is produced in a transmitter oscillator stage"
        ],
        "question": "A parasitic oscillation:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "at high or low frequencies",
        "id": "B-008-003-010",
        "options": [
            "at high or low frequencies",
            "on harmonic frequencies",
            "at high frequencies only",
            "at low frequencies only"
        ],
        "question": "Parasitic oscillations in the RF power amplifier stage of a transmitter may be found:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "above or below the transmitter frequency",
        "id": "B-008-003-011",
        "options": [
            "above or below the transmitter frequency",
            "on VHF frequencies only",
            "on the transmitter fundamental frequency",
            "on harmonics of the transmitter frequency"
        ],
        "question": "Transmitter RF amplifiers can generate parasitic oscillations:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Harmonic radiation from your transmitter",
        "id": "B-008-004-001",
        "options": [
            "Harmonic radiation from your transmitter",
            "De ionization of the ionosphere near your neighbour's TV antenna",
            "TV receiver front-end overload",
            "Too much low pass filtering on the transmitter"
        ],
        "question": "If a neighbour reports television interference on one or two channels only when you transmit on 15 metres, what is probably the cause of the interference?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Unwanted signals at frequencies which are multiples of the fundamental (chosen) frequency",
        "id": "B-008-004-002",
        "options": [
            "Unwanted signals at frequencies which are multiples of the fundamental (chosen) frequency",
            "Unwanted signals that are combined with a 60-Hz hum",
            "Unwanted signals caused by sympathetic vibrations from a nearby transmitter",
            "Signals which cause skip propagation to occur"
        ],
        "question": "What is meant by harmonic radiation?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "It may cause interference to other stations and may result in out-of-band signals",
        "id": "B-008-004-003",
        "options": [
            "It may cause interference to other stations and may result in out-of-band signals",
            "It uses large amounts of electric power",
            "It may cause sympathetic vibrations in nearby transmitters",
            "It may cause auroras in the air"
        ],
        "question": "Why is harmonic radiation from an amateur station not wanted?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Harmonic radiation",
        "id": "B-008-004-004",
        "options": [
            "Harmonic radiation",
            "Parasitic excitation",
            "Intermodulation",
            "Auroral distortion"
        ],
        "question": "What type of interference may come from a multi-band antenna connected to a poorly tuned transmitter?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Your transmitter was radiating harmonic signals",
        "id": "B-008-004-005",
        "options": [
            "Your transmitter was radiating harmonic signals",
            "Your transmitter's power-supply filter choke was bad",
            "You were sending CW too fast",
            "Your transmitter's power-supply filter capacitor was bad"
        ],
        "question": "If you are told your station was heard on 21 375 kHz, but at the time you were operating on 7125 kHz, what is one reason this could happen?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Overmodulating a transmitter",
        "id": "B-008-004-006",
        "options": [
            "Overmodulating a transmitter",
            "Keying a transmitter too fast",
            "Signals from a transmitter's output circuit are being sent back to its input circuit",
            "The transmitting antenna is the wrong length"
        ],
        "question": "What causes splatter interference?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "harmonic radiation from the transmitter",
        "id": "B-008-004-007",
        "options": [
            "harmonic radiation from the transmitter",
            "no high-pass filter on the TV",
            "a bad ground at the transmitter",
            "front-end overload of the TV"
        ],
        "question": "Your amateur radio transmitter appears to be creating interference to the television on channel 3 (60-66 MHz) when you are transmitting on the 15 metre band. Other channels are not affected. The most likely cause is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "reduce microphone gain",
        "id": "B-008-004-008",
        "options": [
            "reduce microphone gain",
            "retune transmitter output",
            "use another antenna",
            "reduce oscillator output"
        ],
        "question": "One possible cause of TV interference by harmonics from an SSB transmitter is from \"flat topping\" - driving the power amplifier into non-linear operation. The most appropriate remedy for this is:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "overdriven stages",
        "id": "B-008-004-009",
        "options": [
            "overdriven stages",
            "low SWR",
            "resonant circuits",
            "a linear amplifier"
        ],
        "question": "In a transmitter, excessive harmonics are produced by:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "second harmonic of a 10 metre transmission",
        "id": "B-008-004-010",
        "options": [
            "second harmonic of a 10 metre transmission",
            "crystal oscillator operating on its fundamental",
            "seventh harmonic of an 80 metre transmission",
            "third harmonic of a 15 metre transmission"
        ],
        "question": "An interfering signal from a transmitter is found to have a frequency of 57 MHz (TV Channel 2 is 54 - 60 MHz). This signal could be the:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "excessive drive signal is applied to it",
        "id": "B-008-004-011",
        "options": [
            "excessive drive signal is applied to it",
            "the output tank circuit is tuned to the fundamental frequency",
            "the oscillator frequency is unstable",
            "modulation is applied to a high-level stage"
        ],
        "question": "Harmonics may be produced in the RF power amplifier of a transmitter if:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A low pass filter",
        "id": "B-008-005-001",
        "options": [
            "A low pass filter",
            "A key-click filter",
            "A high pass filter",
            "A CW filter"
        ],
        "question": "What type of filter might be connected to an amateur HF transmitter to cut down on harmonic radiation?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "To reduce harmonic radiation",
        "id": "B-008-005-002",
        "options": [
            "To reduce harmonic radiation",
            "To reduce fundamental radiation",
            "To reduce low frequency interference to other amateurs",
            "To reduce RF energy below a cut-off point"
        ],
        "question": "Why do modern HF transmitters have a built-in low pass filter in their RF output circuits?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "A band pass filter",
        "id": "B-008-005-003",
        "options": [
            "A band pass filter",
            "A high pass filter",
            "An input filter",
            "A low pass filter"
        ],
        "question": "What circuit blocks RF energy above and below a certain limit?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "About the same",
        "id": "B-008-005-004",
        "options": [
            "About the same",
            "Substantially lower",
            "Twice the transmission line impedance",
            "Substantially higher"
        ],
        "question": "What should be the impedance of a low pass filter as compared to the impedance of the transmission line into which it is inserted?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "Low pass",
        "id": "B-008-005-005",
        "options": [
            "Low pass",
            "Key click",
            "High pass",
            "Rejection"
        ],
        "question": "In order to reduce the harmonic output of a high frequency (HF) transmitter, which of the following filters should be installed at the transmitter?"
    },
    {
        "answer": "low pass filter",
        "id": "B-008-005-006",
        "options": [
            "low pass filter",
            "high pass filter",
            "band reject filter",
            "wave trap"
        ],
        "question": "To reduce harmonic output from a high frequency transmitter, you would put a ____________ in the transmission line as close to the transmitter as possible."
    },
    {
        "answer": "high pass filter",
        "id": "B-008-005-007",
        "options": [
            "high pass filter",
            "low pass filter",
            "wave trap",
            "band reject filter"
        ],
        "question": "To reduce energy from an HF transmitter getting into a television set, you would place a ____________ as close to the TV as possible."
    },
    {
        "answer": "allow only certain frequencies through",
        "id": "B-008-005-008",
        "options": [
            "allow only certain frequencies through",
            "attenuate high frequencies but not low",
            "pass frequencies each side of a band",
            "stop frequencies in a certain band"
        ],
        "question": "A band pass filter will:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "pass frequencies each side of a band",
        "id": "B-008-005-009",
        "options": [
            "pass frequencies each side of a band",
            "allow only two frequencies through",
            "pass frequencies below 100 MHz",
            "stop frequencies each side of a band"
        ],
        "question": "A band reject filter will:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "at the antenna terminals of the TV receiver",
        "id": "B-008-005-010",
        "options": [
            "at the antenna terminals of the TV receiver",
            "between microphone and speech amplifier",
            "at the Morse key or keying relay in a transmitter",
            "between transmitter output and transmission line"
        ],
        "question": "A high pass filter would normally be fitted:"
    },
    {
        "answer": "attenuate frequencies above 30 MHz",
        "id": "B-008-005-011",
        "options": [
            "attenuate frequencies above 30 MHz",
            "pass audio frequencies above 3 kHz",
            "attenuate frequencies below 30 MHz",
            "pass audio frequencies below 3 kHz"
        ],
        "question": "A low pass filter suitable for a high frequency transmitter would:"
    }
]